<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vr on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/vr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vr on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/vr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Web - Life beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</guid>
      <description>Get ready: Great International Developer Summit is re-scheduled from 17-21st Aug, in Bangalore.
Come and talk about the life beyond keyboard and screens, spatial web is taking over get ready&amp;hellip;
 The talk is about Spatial Web is an umbrella term for the next generation web technologies that will transform every aspect of our life. It will connect the human and machines seamlessly such that the difference between physical and virtual will disappear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XR Day - ThoughtWorks India</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/thougthworks_xrday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/thougthworks_xrday/</guid>
      <description>The XR Day Organized XR Days at ThoughtWorks, India in different cities and conducted awareness sessions and ideation workshop and more..
The talks are about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen xr day 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Event Summary It was well recevied the participats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AwayDay 2019 - SLAM Aware Applications</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Thoutworks&amp;rsquo;s Awayday 2019, where the entire ThoughtWorks India travelled to celebrate togetherness.
I and my colleague Raju Kandaswamy presented this talk in the breakout sessions in category Seismic Shifts Around 2000 Thoghtworkers get together, and enjoyed fusion of technology showcases, cultural event and more. Glimpse here
 The talk is about  What is SLAM (Simultaneous Localization And Mapping)? The use cases of SLAM? How does it work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/talk/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here  Explore the world beyond your normal ways of communicating with smart devices! #Explore AR/VR with @thinkuldeep@WTM_Delhi @gdg_nd @thoughtworksIN</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>