<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>security on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/security/</link>
        <description>Recent content in security on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>DNS Resolution In Thread Network</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-thread-dns-resolution/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-thread-dns-resolution/</guid>
            <description>In previous articles, we explored communication between a Thread device and external (non-Thread) networks, primarily over TCP/HTTP using IP addresses and ports. However, in real-world applications, we rarely use raw IP addresses. Instead, we rely on hostnames — which are resolved to IP addresses using DNS (Domain Name System).
Public DNS resolution (like Google’s 8.8.8.8) handles global domain names, typically configured at the OS or browser level. But for private, local networks — like those used in IoT and Thread-based deployments — we need a local DNS setup to resolve custom hostnames (e.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Implementing a Joiner in nRF Connect SDK</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-thread-joiner-implementation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-thread-joiner-implementation/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how a Commissioner node provisions a Joiner in a Thread network using OpenThread&amp;rsquo;s default firmware. However, in real-world applications, custom firmware logic is often required, along with programmatic control over the commissioning process. In this article, we will implement a Joiner using the nRF Connect SDK, following these four key steps.
Joiner in Action The Joiner process involves the following steps:
 Enable Thread – Ensure that the Thread network and IPv6 are enabled.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Simplifying Thread Network Provisioning with Joiner and Commissioner</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-thread-network-provisioning/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-thread-network-provisioning/</guid>
            <description>In previous articles, we explored the Thread protocol and connected Thread devices to the internet using a Border Router. We joined the Thread network by manually configuring each node with a full dataset containing network credentials such as the PAN ID, Network Key, Network Name, and more (refer to Step 6.1: Access Network Credentials). While this method works, it becomes impractical when provisioning hundreds of Thread devices in real-world scenarios.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Framework for choosing an IoT Platform</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/choosing_iot_platform/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/choosing_iot_platform/</guid>
            <description>As we understand “IoT Platform” is an essential building block of IoT Ecosystem . A platform essentially decouples the business application from low level details of the technology stack and required services. Thus, it makes more sense to go for an off-the-shelf platform that provide all the relevant features and required flexibility, instead of developing the whole IoT stack from scratch. Selection of an IoT Platform is a key to develop a scalable and robust IoT Solution.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>