<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>simulation on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/simulation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in simulation on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</guid>
            <description>The MasterClass This October, at Thoughtworks India, we’re celebrating our 20th anniversary! That’s 20 years of excellence in technology!
 All through the month we’re hosting 10 tech talks, delivered by some of our best-and-brightest technologists in India. Each of them will be taking you through different topics, ranging from Distributed Delivery and XR, to Security and Navigating Ambiguity.
I am sharing stage with Raju Kandaswamy who is a robotics enthusiast and taking us through &amp;ldquo;Using XR in building autonomous vehicles&amp;rdquo;.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Training autonomous vehicles with XR simulation</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/training-autonomous-vehicles-in-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/training-autonomous-vehicles-in-xr/</guid>
            <description>Self driving cars are a good example of what artificial intelligence can accomplish today. Such tech-centered advances are built on the back of highly trained Machine Learning (ML) algorithms.
These algorithms require exhaustive data that help the AI effectively model all possible scenarios. Accessing and pooling all that data needs complex and very expensive real-world hardware setups, aside from the extensive time it takes to gather the necessary training-data in the cloud (to train ML).</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>