<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>meta on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/meta/</link>
        <description>Recent content in meta on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 3</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Kanchan Ray, Chief Technology Officer at Nagarro. We collaborated on building and conceptualizing various cutting-edge proof-of-concepts using emerging technologies. His support and advice were always invaluable.
🙏 I extend my heartfelt thanks to Kanchan for reviewing early versions of the book, sharing his valuable insights, and writing the following foreword:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Dr. Rebecca J Parsons, former Chief Technology Officer at Thoughtworks. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Rebecca at numerous technology strategy events, where her insights on responsible technology usage and our collective responsibility towards sustainability and technological adaptation have been invaluable.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse — A Synopsis</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo; featured on Industry4.0. It is available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online.
 The metaverse, a loosely defined term, has gone from a virtual game world to the next internet and sparks conversations on technology’s potential. Despite eye-rolling at terms like metaverse and eXtended Reality (XR), immersive technologies are silently becoming part of our daily life through social media, virtual collaboration, and digitized experiences. We seamlessly embrace digital tools, scanning codes, engaging in virtual trials, and altering reality through digital filters.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Vishal Shah, General Manager of XR and Metaverse at Lenovo. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of hearing Vishal speak at events like CES and AWE, where he shared invaluable insights on the metaverse and XR technology. Meeting him in person at Lenovo Tech World 2023 was a highlight, where we discussed this book, and he graciously agreed to contribute to its exploration of the metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead The concept of the Metaverse keeps evolving, leaving many confused. 📖 In my book, Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age I leverage my years of experience to:
 Unravel the Metaverse: Demystify the term and explore its true potential. Separate Myth from Reality: Address misconceptions surrounding the metaverse. Prepare for the Future: Equip you with insights to navigate the evolving digital landscape.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Coming Soon! Exploring the Metaverse</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</guid>
            <description>In the world of tech buzzwords, “metaverse” has been topic of discussion, largely understood and misunderstood. It comes, goes, and comes again in new shapes and forms, definitions and understanding. The term has been around for three decades and is poised to continue its evolution.
In the past, it has been defined to suit the narratives of organizations and individuals alike. Some see it as a game, others as a virtual world, while some view it as a tool for global connection and collaboration.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the next Internet, that’s what we summarized it in the previous article. We discussed it’s characteristics and building blocks. In this article we will discuss some prominent use cases of the metaverse. We understand the metaverse as a trillion dollar opportunity in the next few years. It is growing at real fast speed, but without effective rules and regulations, without effective standards and practices, and we will also touch upon this concerning part of metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most enquired word after Facebook renamed itself to “Meta” to align to their metaversal vision. However, the term “metaverse” was coined 3 decade ago by Neal Stephenson, in his 1992 science-fiction novel “Snow Crash,” which envisions a virtual reality-based successor to the internet. In the novel, people use digital avatars of themselves to explore the online world, often as a way of escaping a dystopian reality.
Today, Metaverse is being considered as a $800 billion path with double digit growth in next 5 years, where industry is trying to get most out of it by co-creating with communities, and focusing on it’s cost-effective universal acceptance.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>