<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>whitepaper on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/whitepaper/</link>
        <description>Recent content in whitepaper on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/whitepaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 5</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
One of the most distinguished endorsements comes from Prof. M Manivannan, who leads the Experiential Technologies Innovation Center (XTIC) at IIT Madras.
Prof. Mani has spearheaded innovation at XTIC and have made India proud. His pioneering work in areas like iTad(interactive Touch Active Display) and integrating haptics into virtual reality solutions is noteworthy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR - the Enabler | XROS Fellowship Report</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, a transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtended Reality (XR) at its core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution is the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. My book, Exploring the Metaverse, available globally, outlines this kind of collaboration as a call to action for all of us.
FICCI XROS Fellowship Program Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce &amp;amp; Industry (FICCI), is the voice of india&amp;rsquo;s business and industry for policy change.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR in India — A Whitepaper by XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</guid>
            <description>XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre), is India’s 1st Research &amp;amp; Product Innovation centre for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality and Haptics at IIT Madras. It has published a white-paper and skill gap analysis for Experiential Technologies in India.
Whitepaper - XR in India
It was great to be a contributor in this research. It is authored by 19 industry leader from various enterprises, institutes and government body. Excursions from this research also got published in The Hindu Businessline.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>