<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>talks on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/talks/</link>
        <description>Recent content in talks on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:54992/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>TW Spotlight: Going with the Flow – My Journey</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/tw-spotlight-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/tw-spotlight-2024/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks has always amazed me—whether it&amp;rsquo;s the pioneering work we do in the industry or the contributions we make to software engineering practices. What truly inspires me is our people-centered approach. Recently, I was honored by our market leadership, who put me in the spotlight to share my journey with fellow Thoughtworkers. While I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a great deal from my colleagues, I took this opportunity to share my own experiences in the hope of inspiring others.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>20 reflections of 20 years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/20-of-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/20-of-20/</guid>
            <description>On July 5, 2004, I embarked on my professional journey. These past 20 years have been nothing short of adventurous and fulfilling.
 &amp;ldquo;Learning is a natural process, and it matures by sharing&amp;rdquo;
 I&amp;rsquo;ve had a wealth of learnings throughout these two decades, as I worked on over 50 projects spanning various domains and technologies. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of directly working with over a thousand individuals from diverse backgrounds across different organizations.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>thinkuldeep.com | 100 Articles and 50 Events</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/100-articles-50-events/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/100-articles-50-events/</guid>
            <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve reached a milestone: 100 articles and 50 events at thinkuldeep.com. This experience has improved my writing, boosted my confidence, and fueled my passion for self-expression. I&amp;rsquo;m thankful to readers, authors, speakers, and mentors who inspired me.
I want to share common obstacles I overcame, hoping to inspire others on their creative journeys.
1. I am not a great writer/speaker, I can&amp;rsquo;t express well Blocker#1 is doubting our abilities, it is natural when we haven&amp;rsquo;t explored our potential.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>