<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>life on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/life/</link>
        <description>Recent content in life on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Some moments</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/moments/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/moments/</guid>
            <description>Jim corbett trip - Jun, 2023  Lakshya&amp;rsquo;s visit to Thoughtworks Gurugram - May, 2023  16th Wedding anniversary - Feb, 2023  Father Retirement Speech - Jun, 2022  ☞ More Details 14th Wedding anniversary - Feb, 2021  Keep Moving - Jan, 2021  3rd Birthday Lovyansh - Jun, 2020  ☞ More Details </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Habit Matters - The change is a side effect</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/habitmatters/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/habitmatters/</guid>
            <description>“Change is the only constant, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether we like it or not, it takes place”- shared and reflected in my change stories.
 Over the years, I have been following my theory of change Accept-Observe-Absorb. It helped me to traverse through the change year 2020, and understand the role of “Will” and how to cultivate it. I shared how just one change “working from my native home” brought so many other changes in lifestyle and behavior.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Corporate lessons from a Home Makeover</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</guid>
            <description>Recently I shared an article on my life lessons from my father’s work life, and mentioned that I dedicated a new home to my father’s work life, also promised that I will share some corporate lessons learned from making-over this new home. I can well relate my takeaways to the corporate experiences such as vendor selection, negotiation, solutioning, estimation, prioritization, agility and being a trusted partner and many more..
 As I keep saying “we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad”</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lessons of Life - Father’s Retirement</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</guid>
            <description>I started thinkuldeep.com keeping in mind that we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad. Our learning matures by sharing, we explore more of us by giving it away to others.
 Recently my father turned 60, and has retired from government services. 60 years full of life is a quite big experience, where around 38 years he spent in serving the same Govt of Rajasthan.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Open-sources and Apps</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/open-sources/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/open-sources/</guid>
            <description>Arium — An Automation framework for Unity/XR Arium is a lightweight, extensible, platform-agnostic framework for writing automation tests in Unity not limited to but built specifically for XR (ARVR) Applications. I am part of core development team and a reviewer for this.
☞ GitHub ☞ Medium Article ☞ Thoughtworks Insights
DecoAR — Decorate the world with XR DecoAR is an App for exdended the decoration at home, office or any place.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My impactful change stories</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/my-impactful-change-stories/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/my-impactful-change-stories/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I have been invited to share my 3 years Thoughtworks Journey, at “Impact Series” by Social Change Group TW, India.
 &amp;ldquo;Striving for positive social change is at the heart of our purpose, culture and work&amp;rdquo; — /thoughtworks
 I believe an impactful change is the change that changes you, and any social change start from within, our own journey. I shared my change journey, and received number of comments, and feedbacks.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Learning Equation</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-learning-equation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-learning-equation/</guid>
            <description>Today, The world is celebrating teacher’s day. I wish Happy Teacher&amp;rsquo;s day to all of us! We all are teachers and learners as every one of us has something to learn from others and something to teach others. I am thinking of an equation of learning that defines my way of learning and hope it would be helpful for you too.  The learning equation — Learning is proportional to Sharing; Learning ∝ Sharing</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two Thoughtful Years!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/two-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/two-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>It’s now two years since I accepted a challenging change to leave the previous organization after 13 long years, and join ThoughtWorks. Any change requires sacrifices and dedication before it becomes a positive change, but the journey becomes easy when we believe in the change and accept it. A change introduces us to a new environment and enables new thoughts, and new energy. The two years journey at ThoughtWorks is no different.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>2020 — The year of Change</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2020-year-of-change/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2020-year-of-change/</guid>
            <description>Change is the only constant, early we accept, early we get ready for the future. 2020 is a year of change, accept it, and change our lifestyle and get ready for the future.
I have been writing about the change in the past, right from accepting the change to change for good to have a purposeful and balanced life and uncover human potential in this Covid19 time.
Today, June 20, is my younger son Lovyansh’s 3rd Birthday, and June month is really time to rejuvenate and celebrate for the kids when they are free from school.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Uncovering the human potential</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</guid>
            <description>Covid19 has challenged the way work, I have penned down my earlier article to cover my workday and our shift toward new ways of working. Covid19 has impacted not just the way we work, but also our lives. All-day, we keep hearing how it is hitting hard on humanity and it has brought so much negativity around us.
Enough of negativity, let’s uncover human potential to cop with it. In this article, I will cover how the ways of our regular life are shifting, and uncovering new human potentials to try out new things and performing our chores own our own.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>