<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>industry4.0 on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/industry4.0/</link>
        <description>Recent content in industry4.0 on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/industry4.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse — A Synopsis</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo; featured on Industry4.0. It is available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online.
 The metaverse, a loosely defined term, has gone from a virtual game world to the next internet and sparks conversations on technology’s potential. Despite eye-rolling at terms like metaverse and eXtended Reality (XR), immersive technologies are silently becoming part of our daily life through social media, virtual collaboration, and digitized experiences. We seamlessly embrace digital tools, scanning codes, engaging in virtual trials, and altering reality through digital filters.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Panelist &amp; Organizer - Nagarro LSD - Industry 4.0</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nagarro-lsd-industory-4-0/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nagarro-lsd-industory-4-0/</guid>
            <description>Organized Nagarro LSD event, on Industry 4.0, demonstrated usecases on connected services concept, and was a panelist for a discussion on
 Smarter Services - Predictive, Always Connected, Personalized Global experts will debate ways to create smarter services based around predictive maintenance, always connected devices and personalized solutions.
 Whether we call Industry 4.0 an evolution or a revolution, there is little doubt that it will have a disruptive impact on the manufacturing industry.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>