<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>awe on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/awe/</link>
        <description>Recent content in awe on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/awe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Livestreaming</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/streaming/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/streaming/</guid>
            <description>Machine Gaze - What Happens When Glasses Begin to Think Gatherverse Summit 2025 - ☞ More Details   The Metaverse United : How AI and XR Can Deepen Human Connections Gatherverse Summit 2025 - ☞ More Details   Defining the AI Powered Virtual World Gatherverse Virtual World Symposium 2024 - ☞ More Details   India&amp;rsquo;s Metaverse Journey: Opportunities and Challenges XROM Postcast - ☞ More Details   Global Insights from XR Leaders in India: AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR AWE Asia 2024 - ☞ More Details   Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR Express Computer Webinar - ☞ More Details   Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World Season of AI - Azure Developer Community - Rekill - ☞ More Details   Evolving into Tomorrow, Today: Enter the Metaverse Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024 - ☞ More Details   Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining the reality in the digital age Book promo - ☞ More Details   XR in practice: the engineering challenges of extending reality Thoughtworks Podcast - ☞ More Details   AI Assisted Content Pipeline for XR Thoughtworks XConf 2022 - ☞ More Details    Using XR in building autonomous vehicles Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021 - ☞ More Details   &amp;nbsp;  The Shift from Enterprise XR to Ethical XR Thoughtworks XConf 2021 - ☞ More Details   Navigating the new normal The VRARA - ☞ More Details    eXtended Reality for Enterprise XROM Podcast - ☞ More Details   XR - Nicety to Necessity Techgig Webinars - ☞ More Details    How to get started with AR VR?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Testing the Ground: Reflections on 2024 and the Road Ahead for 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we bid farewell to 2024 and welcome 2025, it’s a perfect moment to reflect on the lessons this year has offered—both rewarding and challenging—and to prepare for the opportunities ahead.
This year marked a significant milestone as I celebrated 20 years in the industry. Along this journey, I shared my experiences by publishing a book, contributing over 30 articles and whitepapers on topics like the AI-powered metaverse, IoT, D&amp;amp;Iand product management.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit and AWE Nite | XR with AI, Gaming, AVGC</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to announce that I’ll be part of the XR Summit 2024 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the AI-powered Metaverse is Our Next Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>📖 My Takeaways from Our Next Reality by Alvin Wang Graylin and Louis Rosenberg
☞ Buy - Exploring the Metaverse ☞ Buy - Our Next Reality 
Our Next Reality topped my reading list for months, and travel always helps me catch up on books! After meeting Alvin at AWE Asia 2024, I was eager to dive in and finally complete it. Following recent trips to Singapore and now the US, here’s what I found worth sharing from the book.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>