<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>spatial-computing on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/spatial-computing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in spatial-computing on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/spatial-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the AI-powered Metaverse is Our Next Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>📖 My Takeaways from Our Next Reality by Alvin Wang Graylin and Louis Rosenberg
☞ Buy - Exploring the Metaverse ☞ Buy - Our Next Reality 
Our Next Reality topped my reading list for months, and travel always helps me catch up on books! After meeting Alvin at AWE Asia 2024, I was eager to dive in and finally complete it. Following recent trips to Singapore and now the US, here’s what I found worth sharing from the book.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/aweasia-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/aweasia-2024/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ai-powered-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ai-powered-xr/</guid>
            <description>In a world where AI is ubiquitous, technologies like AR, VR, and XR often raise eyebrows, despite their vast potential. AI is not only propelling these technologies forward but also preparing them for the next stages of development. There are tremendous opportunities to leverage their potential for business transformation. I am honored to be invited by Express Computers - India Leading IT Magazine, to speak on this topic and dispel common myths.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>Season of AI, a virtual event series of the Microsoft Azure Developer Community by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a session, where I had the opportunity to guide the community and share insights from my experience in XR and AI development.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, and special thanks to Rohit Sardana and Azkar Khan for extending the invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>