<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>book launch on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/book-launch/</link>
        <description>Recent content in book launch on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/book-launch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>📕 Available Now! Jagjeevan : Living Larger than Life</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-avaiable-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-avaiable-now/</guid>
            <description>📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life is a heartfelt tribute to the extraordinary life and timeless wisdom of Shri Jagguram—an enlightened soul whose values shaped generations. Blending personal memories with profound life lessons, it captures the essence of a man who lived with humility, discipline, compassion, and unwavering purpose.
 Through ten insightful chapters, the book explores heritage, resilience, responsibility, inner strength, family unity, conflict resolution, gratitude, and the power of one’s actions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕Jagjeevan launch@Thoughtworks</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks, Thoughtworkers, and books share a deep and enduring connection. Over the years, hundreds of books have been authored by Thoughtworkers, reflecting a culture rooted in thought leadership, learning, and knowledge sharing.
As part of this vibrant thought-sharing community, I recently had the privilege of launching my book 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger than Life at the Thoughtworks office and signing copies for colleagues. The moment was special—not just because it was a book launch, but because it was about sharing timeless life lessons and inspirations drawn from the life of my great-grandfather, lessons that feel especially relevant in today’s fast-paced world.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Symposium Takeaways and Book Launch at IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of speaking at XR Symposium 2025, hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class symposium showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Navigating the Challenges of Digital Transformation | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/book-navigating-challenges-of-digital-transformation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/book-navigating-challenges-of-digital-transformation/</guid>
            <description>The third industrial revolution gave birth to the digital web—a new era of global connectivity and digital intelligence. My book Exploring the Metaverse, covers it and explore what comes next. As we now step into an AI-driven world, we must ask: where are we truly heading, and how ready are we?
Transformation requires us to evolve—from traditional methods to newer, more adaptive approaches. While the digital era has been around for decades, many industries still struggle with achieving meaningful digital transformation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Product Management Untangled | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/book-product-management-untangled/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/book-product-management-untangled/</guid>
            <description>Product management is a unique blend of art and science, distinct from roles such as project management, program management, business analysis, or business development. Some projects or products may have dedicated product managers, but I believe these skills are valuable for various roles, even if not explicitly labeled as a product manager. Even technologists can benefit from these skills to enhance the value of their work.
This is where Dinker Charak&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;lsquo;Product Management Untangled&amp;rsquo; becomes essential.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>