<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>takeaways on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/takeaways/</link>
    <description>Recent content in takeaways on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/takeaways/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</guid>
      <description>After a wonderful experience of participating as a judge and mentor at Smart India Hackathon 2019, I am delighted to share that I again got a chance to meet and judge India&amp;rsquo;s young winners and innovators at Grand Finale of Smart India Hackathon 2020, world’s biggest open innovation modal, organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. This time it is no more a hackathon but a hackathon of hackathons — 4 Lacks students, 1500 small hackathons, 40 Nodal centers, around 2000 mentors and 1000 evaluators, 11000 finalists and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success Mantra</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/success_mantra_amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/success_mantra_amazon/</guid>
      <description>Everyone in India is talking about Jeff Bezos, the richest of the world, who was on India&amp;rsquo;s visit recently. People are talking about the investments he is making in India, talking about his prediction about India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;21st Century is going to be the Indian century&amp;rdquo;, and discussing the impact on small businesses. We have seen disruptions lead by Amazon in multiple sectors, now people have a fear that whatever Amazon touch, it becomes Amazon&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception Workshop | Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</guid>
      <description>Inception exercise is very common in software development, where we gather the business requirements and define the delivery plan for the MVP(Minimum Viable Product) on a shared understanding. There are a set of tools and practices available to define the MVP requirements and its delivery plan. Famous tools are Lean Value Tree, Business Model Canvas, Plane Map, Elevator Pitch, Futurespective, Empathy Maps, Value Proposition Canvas, User Journey Map, Gamestorming, Process Diagram, MoSCoW, Communication Plan, Project Plan etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embibe purpose and balance in life</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</guid>
      <description>I just finished a book &amp;ldquo;Life&amp;rsquo;s Amazing Secrets&amp;rdquo; by Gaur Gopal Das. It covers the topic of balance and purpose in life nicely. Few of the concepts from the book I can very well relate to my current organization&amp;rsquo;s focus on cultivation and collaboration culture.
It&amp;rsquo;s now more than 6 months of my journey with Thoughtworks, an organization which started as a social experiment more than 25 years ago, and believes in balancing 3 pillars in life ; sustainability, excellence and purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2019</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</guid>
      <description>Recently got a chance to judge and mentor india&amp;rsquo;s young innovators at Smart India Hackathon 2019, world&amp;rsquo;s largest hackathon with 11000 shortlisted participants, hosted by 48 centers across India. It was organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. I was invited to Judge the event at Panipat Institute of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology, Panipat. I am delighted to contribute in the journey of India&amp;rsquo;s transformation, and see innovative ideas from the new generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development as a Design Process</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/software-development-as-design-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/software-development-as-design-process/</guid>
      <description>The book &amp;ldquo;Agile IT Organization Design - For digital transformation and continuous delivery&amp;rdquo; by Sriram Narayan explains software development as a design process. Following statement from the book means a lot.
 &amp;ldquo;Software development is a design process, and the production environment is the factory where product takes place. IT OPS work to keep the factory running..&amp;rdquo;
 It questions the way we traditionally think of operation support, maintenance, production bugs, rework, their costs and budgets and the focus in software development life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your organisation agility by test-first-pair development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/test-first-pair-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/test-first-pair-development/</guid>
      <description>Agile software development methodology is the key selling point for most of the IT organisations, however many of the organisations have gone by the literal meaning of the word &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo;. They follow agile practices without really being agile. If we go by Manifesto for Agile Software Development, it focus more on human factor (people, interaction, collaboration) which produces working software as per the need of time, than on processes, tools and strict planning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>