<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>testimonial on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/testimonial/</link>
        <description>Recent content in testimonial on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/testimonial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 5</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
One of the most distinguished endorsements comes from Prof. M Manivannan, who leads the Experiential Technologies Innovation Center (XTIC) at IIT Madras.
Prof. Mani has spearheaded innovation at XTIC and have made India proud. His pioneering work in areas like iTad(interactive Touch Active Display) and integrating haptics into virtual reality solutions is noteworthy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 4</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Venkatesh Ponniah, Global Head of Emerging Technologies at Thoughtworks.
We call him Venki. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Venki on technology strategy and governance. He has great insights into emerging technology businesses, particularly in AI, SDV, Digital Twins, and XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 3</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Kanchan Ray, Chief Technology Officer at Nagarro. We collaborated on building and conceptualizing various cutting-edge proof-of-concepts using emerging technologies. His support and advice were always invaluable.
🙏 I extend my heartfelt thanks to Kanchan for reviewing early versions of the book, sharing his valuable insights, and writing the following foreword:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Dr. Rebecca J Parsons, former Chief Technology Officer at Thoughtworks. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Rebecca at numerous technology strategy events, where her insights on responsible technology usage and our collective responsibility towards sustainability and technological adaptation have been invaluable.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Vishal Shah, General Manager of XR and Metaverse at Lenovo. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of hearing Vishal speak at events like CES and AWE, where he shared invaluable insights on the metaverse and XR technology. Meeting him in person at Lenovo Tech World 2023 was a highlight, where we discussed this book, and he graciously agreed to contribute to its exploration of the metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>