<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>genAI on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/genai/</link>
        <description>Recent content in genAI on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/genai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | Surviving in the Artificially Intelligent Immersive World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2026/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2026/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at Ideatron: AI for Public Good</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ideatron-ai-for-public-goods/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ideatron-ai-for-public-goods/</guid>
            <description>India is hosting the AI Impact Summit 2026, reaffirming its commitment to making Artificial Intelligence (AI) accessible and beneficial for the public good. The event will explore how AI can address real-world challenges in healthcare, education, agriculture, climate change, and governance—building on the momentum of global gatherings like the AI Action Summit France, AI Seoul Summit, and AI Safety Summit.
Ideatron: AI for Public Good, a hackathon organized as an official pre-summit event of the AI Impact Summit 2026, brought together innovative minds to develop AI solutions addressing societal challenges.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕Jagjeevan launch@Thoughtworks</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks, Thoughtworkers, and books share a deep and enduring connection. Over the years, hundreds of books have been authored by Thoughtworkers, reflecting a culture rooted in thought leadership, learning, and knowledge sharing.
As part of this vibrant thought-sharing community, I recently had the privilege of launching my book 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger than Life at the Thoughtworks office and signing copies for colleagues. The moment was special—not just because it was a book launch, but because it was about sharing timeless life lessons and inspirations drawn from the life of my great-grandfather, lessons that feel especially relevant in today’s fast-paced world.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Symposium Takeaways and Book Launch at IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of speaking at XR Symposium 2025, hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class symposium showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker | XR Symposium for GLOBAL SOUTH</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-symposium-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-symposium-2025/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to share that I am part of the XR Symposium 2025 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Path to AI → GenAI → Agentic AI</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-to-genai-to-agenticai/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-to-genai-to-agenticai/</guid>
            <description>The world of technology is evolving at lightning speed. Every week, new AI models, frameworks, and services make headlines. With the hype around LLMs, Agentic AI, MCPs, and A2A systems, it’s easy to feel like we’re always playing catch-up.
But here’s the truth: without strong fundamentals, chasing the “next big thing” is like building a skyscraper on sand. A strong foundation ensures stability. That’s why, before diving deep into Generative AI, it’s critical to revisit the path that got us here.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker | Pre AI Impact Summit: Openness in AI</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/pre-ai-impact-summit-openess-in-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/pre-ai-impact-summit-openess-in-ai/</guid>
            <description>India will host the AI Impact Summit 2026, reaffirming its commitment to making Artificial Intelligence (AI) accessible and beneficial for the public good. The event will explore how AI can address real-world challenges in healthcare, education, agriculture, climate change, and governance—building on the momentum of global gatherings like the AI Action Summit France, AI Seoul Summit, and AI Safety Summit.
As part of the lead-up to the summit, OpenUK and OpenHQ have been hosting pre-summit events to spark conversations around AI openness.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>DJXHack 2025 | Fostering Artificial Sense in the XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>DJXHack 2025 was an inspiring hackathon organized by DJX Labs, attracting students and professionals from across institutions. Out of many applicants, 30 XR enthusiasts were shortlisted to participate and showcase innovative ideas in extended reality (XR).
I had the honor of being invited as a speaker, where I shared my thoughts on how AI is fostering artificial sense in the XR world. Grateful to be a part of such an impactful event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>💯 Celebrating Exploring the Metaverse: A Year of Insights, Impact, and Gratitude</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-acknowledgements/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-acknowledgements/</guid>
            <description>Almost a year ago, my book Exploring the Metaverse was launched globally—available at leading retailers including Amazon and BPB Online.
With forewords and testimonials from pioneers across industries, the book aims to demystify the Metaverse and provide a thoughtful lens on its technological, business, and societal implications. It&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly fulfilling to see it resonate with readers and spark meaningful conversations.
This milestone wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the unwavering support of Thoughtworks, our ecosystem partners, and—above all—my family, friends, and colleagues.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FOMO to Flow: Building Gen AI Solutions</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-fomo-to-flow-building-genai-solutions/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-fomo-to-flow-building-genai-solutions/</guid>
            <description>Unlock the power of Generative AI by learning to interact with large language models programmatically—and take it further with fine-tuning for customized responses.
If you’re a software maker feeling the fear of missing out (FOMO) on the Gen AI revolution, you’re not alone. The way we build and interact with software is evolving rapidly. “Google it” or “check Stack Overflow” is no longer the go-to approach — AI-first, conversational tools are becoming the new standard across development, design, and decision-making.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Immersive AI at IPOS 2024: Transforming the Process Sector</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ipos-dats-conference/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ipos-dats-conference/</guid>
            <description>IPOS 2024 was an inspiring technology summit focused on the innovations, digitalization, and disruptions shaping the downstream oil &amp;amp; gas, petrochemicals, fertilizers, and process manufacturing sectors. The event provided deep insights into operational excellence, optimization, Industry 4.0, sustainability, safety, and more.
Hosted alongside the Digitalization &amp;amp; Automation Technology Summit and Expo (DATs 2024) by the Institute of Technological Excellence (ITEx), this summit brought together downstream industry leaders and technologists to exchange knowledge and ideas.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit and AWE Nite | XR with AI, Gaming, AVGC</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to announce that I’ll be part of the XR Summit 2024 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the AI-powered Metaverse is Our Next Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>📖 My Takeaways from Our Next Reality by Alvin Wang Graylin and Louis Rosenberg
☞ Buy - Exploring the Metaverse ☞ Buy - Our Next Reality 
Our Next Reality topped my reading list for months, and travel always helps me catch up on books! After meeting Alvin at AWE Asia 2024, I was eager to dive in and finally complete it. Following recent trips to Singapore and now the US, here’s what I found worth sharing from the book.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>India&#39;s Metaverse Journey - XROM Podcast</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-exploring-the-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-exploring-the-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>Exciting conversation on the future of tech with Eddie Avil, where we dive into my journey of writing Exploring the Metaverse, discuss the opportunities and challenges of the digital age, and even touch on mind-bending concepts like Programmable Dreams and Time Travel. Are we ready for what’s coming?
XROM Podcast 🎙️ XROM PODCast, hosted by serial entrepreneur and visionary Eddie Avil, is an incredible YouTube channel showcasing conversations with industry leaders in emerging tech.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ai-powered-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ai-powered-xr/</guid>
            <description>In a world where AI is ubiquitous, technologies like AR, VR, and XR often raise eyebrows, despite their vast potential. AI is not only propelling these technologies forward but also preparing them for the next stages of development. There are tremendous opportunities to leverage their potential for business transformation. I am honored to be invited by Express Computers - India Leading IT Magazine, to speak on this topic and dispel common myths.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>Season of AI, a virtual event series of the Microsoft Azure Developer Community by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a session, where I had the opportunity to guide the community and share insights from my experience in XR and AI development.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, and special thanks to Rohit Sardana and Azkar Khan for extending the invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generative XR – Space aware AI bringing new era of immersion</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</guid>
            <description>Artificial Intelligence has made significant strides with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs) or Generative AI, which are trained to understand and respond to human language naturally. Tools like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google’s Gemini, and Microsoft’s Co-pilot have become the go-to resources for &amp;ldquo;Ask me anything&amp;rdquo; queries. These innovations have been touted as potential Google Search Killer, disrupting the way we search for information, communicate with machines, and receive machine responses.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture: AI and Metaverse reshaping the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</guid>
            <description>AI is pervasive, whether we sense it or not. Staying updated has become essential for survival. We are increasingly immersed in artificially generated worlds, with the internet rapidly evolving into what is known as the metaverse. In my book, &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, I delve into its various forms and interpretations, usecases and challenges, and the way forward.
DesignersX, a company specializing in software development, invited me to speak about my book and discuss how AI and the metaverse will shape the future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Why collaboration is essential for building a successful XR future?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</guid>
            <description>The era of isolated development and secret-keeping innovation is fading. In the past, companies, individuals could thrive by becoming subject matter experts within their own walls. However, the rise of generative AI, fueled by shared knowledge, has changed the game. AI can now imagine and generate solutions faster than ever. The future belongs to those who embrace openness, collaboration, and shared learning.
 Expertise alone isn’t enough. Today, success hinges on building strong networks, fostering partnerships, and collaborating within communities.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Making the XR content usable with AI!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</guid>
            <description>Generative AI is revolutionizing content generation across various mediums, disrupting traditional methods in text, images, art, movies, and music creation. XR (Extended Reality) is also undergoing this transformation. In a previous article, Raju Kandaswamy and I discussed how AI aids in generating content for XR, meeting the dynamic needs of XR and the metaverse.
We highlighted content management as a key challenge in XR and metaverse adoption. While generative AI methods offer some solutions, the significant hurdle of content optimization remains.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>