<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>transformation on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/transformation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in transformation on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Technology and User Interactions</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</guid>
      <description>Technology defines our interactions with the ambiance, and the way we want to interact with the ambiance further defines the technology. The evolution of technology and user interactions tightly depends on each other.
 &amp;ldquo;Walls have ears!&amp;quot;, is very much true today, and not just that, now the walls can see you, feel your presence and talk to you.
 In this post, we will discuss how the user interactions evolved with time and what is next!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can IT modernization lead to revenue loss?</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/can_it_modernization_lead_to_revenue_loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/can_it_modernization_lead_to_revenue_loss/</guid>
      <description>IT Modernization is one of the key factors of today&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation. Most of the enterprises trying to define digital transformation strategy. IT organizations trying to redesign the organizations to meet the changing business need, and uplift the technology and people. Non-IT organizations are also trying to setup digital department to take care of companies digital assets and modernize them. However, IT modernization does not always result in a profit, it may lead to revenue loss if it does not fit to the organization design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another IoT Disruption: A Need of Multi-Skilled Devs</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</guid>
      <description>Technological evolution causes disruption. It replaces traditional, less optimal, complex, lengthy, and costly technology, people, and processes with economical, innovative, optimal, and simpler alternatives. We have seen disruption by mobile phones, and up next is disruption from IoT, wearables, AR-VR, machine Learning, AI, and other innovations. Software development methodology, tools, and people will also face disruption. I expect that the traditional developer will be replaced by the multi-skilled or full-stack developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>