<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development as a Design Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/software-development-as-design-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/software-development-as-design-process/</guid>
      <description>The book &amp;ldquo;Agile IT Organization Design - For digital transformation and continuous delivery&amp;rdquo; by Sriram Narayan explains software development as a design process. Following statement from the book means a lot.
 &amp;ldquo;Software development is a design process, and the production environment is the factory where product takes place. IT OPS work to keep the factory running..&amp;rdquo;
 It questions the way we traditionally think of operation support, maintenance, production bugs, rework, their costs and budgets and the focus in software development life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Effectiveness vs Software Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/software-effectiveness-vs-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/software-effectiveness-vs-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>I define software effectiveness as, doing the objective effectively, I mean correctly. Efficiency can be defined as, using the resources optimally where resources could be memory, CPU, time, files, connections, databases etc.
From my experience, in most (should I call many) of the software projects, efficiency/performance is not much accentuated during the system design and in earlier phases(requirement and estimation) as compared to the emphasis given late in the game, coding and testing and mostly in maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
