<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>university on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/university/</link>
    <description>Recent content in university on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge at Tech-Nexus Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/tech-nexus-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/tech-nexus-2021/</guid>
      <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge at HackBMU 4.0</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/bmu-hack4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/bmu-hack4/</guid>
      <description>BML Munjal University,a Hero group initiative, is organizing a 4th edition Hackathon, named HackBMU 4.0. It is a hackathon focused on promoting innovation, diversity and networking among all future hackers. We will be hosting upcoming engineers and developers from all over the World to create mobile, web, and hardware hacks for an intense session.
HackBMU seeks to provide a welcoming and supportive environment to all participants to develop their skills, regardless of their background.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>