<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>career on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/career/</link>
        <description>Recent content in career on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>How Small, How Big: Seeing Life Through the Lens of the Universe</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/how-small-how-big-analysis/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/how-small-how-big-analysis/</guid>
            <description>After a few hectic months, I recently visited a camping site with my family — a truly refreshing experience being close to nature. The trip was hosted by Camp Gopika and accompanied by Astrostop, adding a unique touch to our stay.
The serene environment gave me time to reflect on life and also work on the final touches of my upcoming book, 📕 “Jagjeevan – Living Larger than Life”, which tells the story of my great-grandfather and his belief that travel is essential for learning and introspection.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An Adventure to Remember: Making it to CareerMaker Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</guid>
            <description>The CareerMaker meetup, hosted by the Microsoft Azure Developer Community and managed by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a special keynote address at Microsoft Gurugram, where I had the opportunity to guide students from various institutes and share insights from my experience in product management.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, as engaging with the young, fresh minds of our nation is not only an opportunity to learn from them but also a responsibility to impart valuable knowledge.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>