<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talk on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talk on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Spatial Web - Life beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</guid>
      <description>Get ready: Great International Developer Summit is re-scheduled and now virtual summit will be organized.
Come and talk about the life beyond keyboard and screens, spatial web is taking over get ready&amp;hellip;
The talk is about Spatial Web is an umbrella term for the next generation web technologies that will transform every aspect of our life. It will connect the human and machines seamlessly such that the difference between physical and virtual will disappear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here  Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here  We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor - JavaOne - Rapid Modernization to Java8</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/oracle-rapid-modernization-of-java-applications-to-jdk-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/oracle-rapid-modernization-of-java-applications-to-jdk-8/</guid>
      <description>Presented At: G. Venkat, Senior Vice President of Technology &amp;amp; Solutions, at Nagarro and I have spoken at the Oracle OpenWorld / JavaOne conference on Wednesday, October 1, 2014, form 10:00 – 11:00 a.m., Pacific Time, at Ballroom 6 in the Hilton San Francisco at Union Square.
I have supported Venkat and presented the JMod tool demo with him.
Here are some coverages - https://www.nagarro.com/en/news-events/nagarro-has-java-8-covered-at-oracle-open-world I have lead the Nagarro Stall and showcased the JMod demo to 300+ visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>