<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>talk on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/talk/</link>
        <description>Recent content in talk on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</guid>
            <description>XREvolve Summit serves a comprehensive platform for exploring the latest advancements, applications, applied sciences and progresses within AR, VR, and the broader domains of the metaverse such as spatial computing and mixed reality. It is backed by Gatherverse community, that advocates humanity-first standards in accessibility, education, equality, community development, safety &amp;amp; privacy, wellness, and ethics within the metaverse and emerging technologies.
This year&amp;rsquo;s focus is XR : Interface of AI, that open up the extraordinary and near limitless possibilities for humanity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An Adventure to Remember: Making it to CareerMaker Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</guid>
            <description>The CareerMaker meetup, hosted by the Microsoft Azure Developer Community and managed by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a special keynote address at Microsoft Gurugram, where I had the opportunity to guide students from various institutes and share insights from my experience in product management.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, as engaging with the young, fresh minds of our nation is not only an opportunity to learn from them but also a responsibility to impart valuable knowledge.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Panelist at FICCI XROS Fellowship Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, the transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtending Reality (XR) at it&amp;rsquo;s core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution would be the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. I recently had the privilege of participating as a panelist at an event hosted by the pioneers shaping the future of the internet. In this article, I share my insights and a summary of this remarkable event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Rapid Prototyping Community - Products beyond software horizons!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/products-beyond-software-horizons/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/products-beyond-software-horizons/</guid>
            <description>🤖 Rapid Prototyping Community Rapid Prototyping is an internal community @Thoughtworks, focused on building a culture of rapid prototyping and innovation. They organise various learnings events, and I was invited to speak at one of their events.
I talked about the importance of holistic product development and how the modern products goes beyond software. I also discussed the impact of technological evolution on products, how to stay ahead of the curve.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Lean2Lead tech track - Twisted realities</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</guid>
            <description>Lean2Lead is a network of women at work, with will to lead and succeed in their respective areas of work. They are 400+ women from different industries together in this group for exchange of ideas, connecting and coaching, building network with industry leaders and inspiring each other for building strategies for success in leadership and executive roles.
I am speaking at their tech session series, on 15 July 2023, 3-4 PM.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Community Events are the Energy Boosters!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gta_lets_fork_together/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gta_lets_fork_together/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the opportunity to contribute to an event called &amp;ldquo;GTA Ghaziabad - Let’s Fork Together&amp;rdquo;. The event was hosted by a community of working professionals and undergraduate engineers from nearby colleges in NCR, and took place at my home office, Thoughtworks Gurgaon. Participating in this event provided me with another energy boost, and in this article, I would like to share my experience and give you a glimpse of what the event was all about!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Agility Today Fest 2023 - Generative AI and XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</guid>
            <description>Agility Today is a 2 days annual UnConference, to meet Agility needs of industry, gathered over past few years via meetups, Conferences and Webinar. This UnConference intends to give you best of Agile Psyche (Mindset Culture and Practice) and Geekery (Engineering, Tools and DevOps). This year in Agility Today Fest 2023 there are couple of programs.
I am speaking to at Agile Engineering Lab (Technical Agility &amp;amp; Engineering Excellence), on topic of Scaling content generation for XR using AI.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XConf-2022 - Thoughtworks India</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2022/</guid>
            <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
Last year XConf was virtual but this year, we are resuming to a physical one, so come meet us face to face in Bangalore at ITC Gardenia on Friday, July 29.
  &amp;nbsp; I am exited to share the stage with renowned technologists like Supriyo Ghosh, Chief Architect, Open Network for Digital Commerce (ONDC) India, our Head of Technology Bharani Subramaniam and Vanya Seth along with other techies from three streams Emerging Tech, Digital Transformation and Data.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</guid>
            <description>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table The thoughtleadership roundtable is an exclusive event hosted by VAMRR Technologies Pvt Ltd, where they invite an elite gathering of 20 ITeS leaders focused on the areas of Design Visualization, Digital Twin and Hybrid Workspaces.
This one is the 98th Conference/Round Table by VAMRR Technologies, and focus this roundtable would be on developments across Advanced Visualization, Remote Design Collaboration, Hybrid Workspaces, 3D Workflows, Data Integrated Digital Twins, Web3 and Metaverse are all converging.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XR and Sustainability - GSF Global Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</guid>
            <description>Green Software Foundation Green Software Foundation (GSF) is building a trusted ecosystem of people, standards, tooling and best practices for Green Software. GSF works with vision to change the culture of building software across the tech industry, so sustainability becomes a core priority to software teams, just as important as performance, security, cost and accessibility. Read more here.
GSF Global Summit 2022 The Green Software Foundation Global Summit 2022 is a series of free events organized by Green Software Foundation members all around the globe that are passionate about sustainable software development, maintenance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</guid>
            <description>The MasterClass This October, at Thoughtworks India, we’re celebrating our 20th anniversary! That’s 20 years of excellence in technology!
 All through the month we’re hosting 10 tech talks, delivered by some of our best-and-brightest technologists in India. Each of them will be taking you through different topics, ranging from Distributed Delivery and XR, to Security and Navigating Ambiguity.
I am sharing stage with Raju Kandaswamy who is a robotics enthusiast and taking us through &amp;ldquo;Using XR in building autonomous vehicles&amp;rdquo;.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XConf-2021 - Thoughtworks India</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2021/</guid>
            <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
This year, XConf will be a virtual experience available at two different time slots. October 7th and 8th will feature pre-recorded sessions and October 9th will feature live sessions. During the nine exciting talks spread across three days.
 I am exited to sharing the stage with renowned technologists like Neal Ford, Dr.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - AT2020 - Agility in Enterprise XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/at_2020_agilexr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/at_2020_agilexr/</guid>
            <description>Enterprise XR is gaining good traction, and software development’s best practices like Agile principles really matters due to multitude of tooling and tech stacks used for Enterprise XR solutions
Enterprises do face multiple challenges with the XR development lifecycle. One of them is the automation of testing XR applications. In response to this gap, ThoughtWorks has developed Arium – an open-source, lightweight, extensible, platform-agnostic framework that helps write automation tests that are built specifically for XR Applications.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - GIDS - Extended Machine Learning with XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_xr4ml/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 06:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_xr4ml/</guid>
            <description>Extended Reality is not only meant for humans, they can very well serve machines by producing Digital twins. Digital twins encapsulate real world elements with all important physics characteristics enabling the researcher to produce large volume of training data needed for reinforment learning and CNN based deep learning algorithms. Extended Reality environments are mature today and are capable of producing photorealistic rendering and physics emulation of real world just by using digital twins.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here LinkedIn
Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Spatial Web - Life beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</guid>
            <description>New Date is still to be announced.
Get ready: Great International Developer Summit is re-scheduled and now virtual summit will be organized.
Come and talk about the life beyond keyboard and screens, spatial web is taking over get ready&amp;hellip;
The talk is about Spatial Web is an umbrella term for the next generation web technologies that will transform every aspect of our life. It will connect the human and machines seamlessly such that the difference between physical and virtual will disappear.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
            <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here LinkedIn
We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Contributor - JavaOne - Rapid Modernization to Java8</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/oracle-rapid-modernization-of-java-applications-to-jdk-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/oracle-rapid-modernization-of-java-applications-to-jdk-8/</guid>
            <description>Presented At: G. Venkat, Senior Vice President of Technology &amp;amp; Solutions, at Nagarro and I have spoken at the Oracle OpenWorld / JavaOne conference on Wednesday, October 1, 2014, form 10:00 – 11:00 a.m., Pacific Time, at Ballroom 6 in the Hilton San Francisco at Union Square.
I have supported Venkat and presented the JMod tool demo with him.
Here are some coverages - https://www.nagarro.com/en/news-events/nagarro-has-java-8-covered-at-oracle-open-world I have lead the Nagarro Stall and showcased the JMod demo to 300+ visitors.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>