<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>life lessons on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/life-lessons/</link>
        <description>Recent content in life lessons on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Jagjeevan at Silver Jubilee of Millennium Batch NIT Kurukshetra</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-silver-jubilee/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-silver-jubilee/</guid>
            <description>In earlier article, I talked about the effort to meet and reconnect with friends and family always fills you up—it gives you a true Dose of Jagjeevan
I recently received a powerful one at the Silver Jubilee celebration of my Millennium (2K) Batch at NIT Kurukshetra. It was deeply heartwarming to reconnect with old friends, relive shared memories, and celebrate the journey we began together more than two decades ago.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Dose of Jagjeevan  - Frequently meet and greet your family!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/dose-of-jagjeevan-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/dose-of-jagjeevan-1/</guid>
            <description>Taking a break from our daily routine to spend time with family often feels harder than it should be. Busy schedules, long travel, work pressure, health concerns, distance, or even unresolved misunderstandings slowly become convenient excuses. Yet, deep down, we all know this truth: family gatherings are essential for our mental peace and happiness.
 We celebrate festivals, birthdays, anniversaries, and milestones to strengthen family bonds and create memories that last a lifetime.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕Jagjeevan launch@Thoughtworks</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks, Thoughtworkers, and books share a deep and enduring connection. Over the years, hundreds of books have been authored by Thoughtworkers, reflecting a culture rooted in thought leadership, learning, and knowledge sharing.
As part of this vibrant thought-sharing community, I recently had the privilege of launching my book 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger than Life at the Thoughtworks office and signing copies for colleagues. The moment was special—not just because it was a book launch, but because it was about sharing timeless life lessons and inspirations drawn from the life of my great-grandfather, lessons that feel especially relevant in today’s fast-paced world.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Symposium Takeaways and Book Launch at IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of speaking at XR Symposium 2025, hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class symposium showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>