<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>java on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in java on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned From Blockchain-Based Development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain or DLT (Distributed Ledger Technology) is getting good traction in the IT world these days. Earlier, this technology was being mostly explored by banks and other finance-related institutions, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum. Now, it is getting explored for other use cases for building distributed applications. Blockchain technology comes with a decentralized and immutable data structure that maintains a connected block of information. Each block is connected using a hash of the previous block, and every new block on the chain is validated (mined) before adding and replicating it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Tracing Using Nginx and Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/request-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/request-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Most web applications are hosted behind a load balancer or web-server such as Nginx/HTTPD, which intercepts all the requests and directs dynamic content requests to the application server, such as Tomcat. Correlating requests traversing from the front-end server to the backend servers are general requirements. In this post, we will discuss tracing the request in the simplest way in an Nginx and Spring Boot-based application without using an external heavyweight library like Slueth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Catch up Before Java 11</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/before_java11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/before_java11/</guid>
      <description>Java 11&amp;rsquo;s release candidate is already here, and the industry is still roaming around Java 8. Every six months, we will see a new release. It is good that Java is evolving at a fast speed to catch up the challengers, but at the same time, it is also scary to catch its speed, even the Java ecosystem (build tools, IDE, etc.) is not catching up that fast. It feels like we are losing track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Hard Lessons From Microservices Development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</guid>
      <description>Microservices-based development is happening all around the industry; more than 70% are trying development of microservice-based software. Microservices simplify integration of the businesses, processes, technology, and people by breaking down the big-bang monolith problem to a smaller set that can be handled independently. However, it also comes with the problem of managing relations between these smaller sets. We used to manage fewer independent units, so there was less operation and planning effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose ORM carefully!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/choose-orm-carefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/choose-orm-carefully/</guid>
      <description>We have recently migrated source code from Hibernate ORM to JDBC (Spring JDBC template) based implementation. Performance has been improved 10 times.
User case (Oracle 11g, JBoss 6, JDK 6, Hibernate, Spring 3) : A tree structure in database is getting populated from a deep file system (directory structure) having around 75000 nodes. Each node (directory) contains text files, which get parsed based on business rules and then populate the database ( BRANCHs representing a node, tables referring to branch, tree_nodes).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>