<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>realities on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/realities/</link>
        <description>Recent content in realities on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/realities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Testing the Ground: Reflections on 2024 and the Road Ahead for 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we bid farewell to 2024 and welcome 2025, it’s a perfect moment to reflect on the lessons this year has offered—both rewarding and challenging—and to prepare for the opportunities ahead.
This year marked a significant milestone as I celebrated 20 years in the industry. Along this journey, I shared my experiences by publishing a book, contributing over 30 articles and whitepapers on topics like the AI-powered metaverse, IoT, D&amp;amp;Iand product management.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Myths and Realities of AI-Assisted Software Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-assisted-software-development-myths/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-assisted-software-development-myths/</guid>
            <description>AI is transforming the software development process, but there are many misconceptions about its capabilities. This article explores the common myths surrounding AI in software development and sheds light on its reality.
In recent times, Artificial Intelligence (AI) has gained momentum across various fields, especially with the introduction of Generative AI (GenAI). AI is now widely accessible, often sparking discussions about its potential, its misuse, and, unfortunately, several myths. As the hype around AI intensifies, so does the Fear of Missing Out (FOMO), leading many to adopt it without fully understanding its true value.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>