<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>design on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/design/</link>
        <description>Recent content in design on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 11:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Certificates</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/certificates/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/certificates/</guid>
            <description> Generative AI Essentials 2 Expertise: Complete Concise Guide nRF Connect SDK Intermediate Bluetooth Low Energy Fundamentals nRF Connect SDK Fundamentals Building AI Elements of AI Product Management Enterprise Architecture Internet of Things (IOT) User Experience Design Taradata Certified Java Certified Programmer </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Square orientation for stereoscopic rendering</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-2/</guid>
            <description>In our day-to-day work, we often create methods, processes, approaches, or features to address specific needs and challenges. Sometimes, these solutions turn into significant innovations, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t immediately recognize them as such. This is also true in our professional work setup, where we may invent without fully realizing it.
I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share that a new patent has been granted to Lenovo for their groundbreaking work in the ThinkReality XR product line, and I am honored to be a co-inventor on this work.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patents</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/patents/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/patents/</guid>
            <description>This listing includes patent applications that are pending as well as patents that have already been granted by the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO).
 CONCURRENT RENDERING OF CANVASES FOR DIFFERENT APPS AS PART OF 3D SIMULATION This invention focuses on rendering multiple 2D mobile apps simultaneously in XR devices, arranged within a 3D spatial layout.
This browser does not support PDFs. Please download the PDF to view it: Download PDF.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Manage multiple 2D apps in a 3D layout</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-1/</guid>
            <description>In our day-to-day work, we often create methods, processes, approaches, or features to address specific needs and challenges. Sometimes, these solutions turn into significant innovations, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t immediately recognize them as such. This is also true in our professional work setup, where we may invent without fully realizing it.
I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share that a new patent has been granted to Lenovo for their groundbreaking work in the ThinkReality XR product line, and I am honored to be a co-inventor on this work.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
            <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</guid>
            <description>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table The thoughtleadership roundtable is an exclusive event hosted by VAMRR Technologies Pvt Ltd, where they invite an elite gathering of 20 ITeS leaders focused on the areas of Design Visualization, Digital Twin and Hybrid Workspaces.
This one is the 98th Conference/Round Table by VAMRR Technologies, and focus this roundtable would be on developments across Advanced Visualization, Remote Design Collaboration, Hybrid Workspaces, 3D Workflows, Data Integrated Digital Twins, Web3 and Metaverse are all converging.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Software Development as a Design Process</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/software-development-as-design-process/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/software-development-as-design-process/</guid>
            <description>The book &amp;ldquo;Agile IT Organization Design - For digital transformation and continuous delivery&amp;rdquo; by Sriram Narayan explains software development as a design process. Following statement from the book means a lot.
 &amp;ldquo;Software development is a design process, and the production environment is the factory where product takes place. IT OPS work to keep the factory running..&amp;rdquo;
 It questions the way we traditionally think of operation support, maintenance, production bugs, rework, their costs and budgets and the focus in software development life.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>