<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IOT on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IOT on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IOT 101: A primer on Internet of Things</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot_simplified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot_simplified/</guid>
      <description>IOT 101 A Primer on Internet of Things  from Kuldeep Singh  The IoT can be described as “Connecting the Things to internet”.
A comprehensive IoT ecosystem consists of many different parts such as electronic circuitry, sensing and acting capability, embedded systems, edge computing, network protocols, communication networks, cloud computing, big data management and analytics, business rules etcetera. This maze of varied parts can be better classified into 4 broad categories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another IoT Disruption: A Need of Multi-Skilled Devs</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</guid>
      <description>Technological evolution causes disruption. It replaces traditional, less optimal, complex, lengthy, and costly technology, people, and processes with economical, innovative, optimal, and simpler alternatives. We have seen disruption by mobile phones, and up next is disruption from IoT, wearables, AR-VR, machine Learning, AI, and other innovations. Software development methodology, tools, and people will also face disruption. I expect that the traditional developer will be replaced by the multi-skilled or full-stack developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOT Cloud Platforms -  A Comparative Study</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The vision of IoT can be seen from two perspectives— ‘Internet’ centric and ‘Thing’ centric. The Internet centric architecture will involve internet services being the main focus while data is contributed by the objects. In the object centric architecture, the smart objects take the center stage.
In order to realize the full potential of cloud computing as well as ubiquitous sensing, a combined framework with a cloud at the center seems to be most viable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Steps of the IoT race</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</guid>
      <description>The ‘Internet of Things’ (IoT) presents tremendous opportunity in all the industry verticals and business domains. Specifically, the ‘Industrial Internet of Things’(IIoT) promises to increase the value proposition by making self-optimizing business processes. As discussed in the post “The Driving Forces Behind IoT”, there are several challenges to be addressed to realize the full IoT potentials, but following steps will help organization to systemically make their products participate in the IoT journey and stay in the IoT race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Driving Forces Behind IoT</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/the-driving-forces-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/the-driving-forces-iot/</guid>
      <description>Everybody in the software industry is talking about IoT in terms of billions of devices, their growth in coming years, changing business models, and adaptation of the IoT in the market. Connecting the things has become so prevalent nowadays, that every software company wants to expand in IoT by building IoT-centric products and services.
There are many industrial applications which connect to sensors and actuators, and can be controlled remotely. They have been around for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIGFOX - An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/sigfox-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/sigfox-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>##Introduction SIGFOX is providing a communication solution dedicated to the Internet of Things
Dedicated to the IOT means:
 Simplicity: No configuration, no pairing, no signaling Autonomy: Very low energy consumption, allowing years of autonomy on battery without maintenance Small messages: No large assets or multimedia, only small messages  It is a LPWA (Low-Power Wide-Area) network, currently operating in 20 countries in Europe, Americas and Asia/Pacific. Communications over the SIGFOX network are bi-directional: uplink from device &amp;amp; downlink to the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework for choosing an IoT Platform</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/choosing_iot_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/choosing_iot_platform/</guid>
      <description>##IoT Platform As we understand “IoT Platform” is an essential building block of IoT Ecosystem . A platform essentially decouples the business application from low level details of the technology stack and required services. Thus, it makes more sense to go for an off-the-shelf platform that provide all the relevant features and required flexibility, instead of developing the whole IoT stack from scratch. Selection of an IoT Platform is a key to develop a scalable and robust IoT Solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a smart meeting room concept</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</guid>
      <description>##Introduction On a usual day at office, if an employee wishes to book a meeting room, he or she first has to open their outlook account, check the calendar for its availability and then send a booking invitation. If they directly go to a meeting room, they have no way of knowing whether it is booked or not without checking the calendar.
Smart Meeting Room is a step forward in automating the availability and booking procedure of a meeting room.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>