<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iot on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iot on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Juror - SMCC Startup Challenge by Nasscom</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-smcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-smcc/</guid>
      <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM CoE is launching first-of-its-kind virtual SMART MANUFACTURING COMPETENCY CENTER (SMCC). The innovation platform which will help in accelerating technology adoption by bringing enterprises, governments, researchers, and innovators together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor and Juror - MIC 2020 by Nasscom</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-iotcoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-iotcoe/</guid>
      <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM has organized Manufacturing Innovation Challenge 2020 from 12th Oct to 11th Dec, on theme of redefining enterprises and entrepreneurs engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eXtended Reality for Enterprise - a PODCast by XROM</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-enterprise-xr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-enterprise-xr/</guid>
      <description>Interesting conversation on eXtended Reality (XR) with Eddie Avil, starting from my background, how I landed up in the XR space and where are we heading…
XROM PODCast  XROM PODCast is a youtube channel maintained by serial entrepreneur, dreamer &amp;amp; a believer Mr. Eddie Avil. This channel has number of interesting conversations with industry leaders in the emerging technology space. Eddie Avil, also runs a marketplace for AR VR hardware and service, visit here https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOT 101: A primer on Internet of Things</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot_simplified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot_simplified/</guid>
      <description>IOT 101 A Primer on Internet of Things  from Kuldeep Singh  The IoT can be described as “Connecting the Things to internet”.
A comprehensive IoT ecosystem consists of many different parts such as electronic circuitry, sensing and acting capability, embedded systems, edge computing, network protocols, communication networks, cloud computing, big data management and analytics, business rules etcetera. This maze of varied parts can be better classified into 4 broad categories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panelist &amp; Organizer - Nagarro LSD - Industry 4.0</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nagarro-lsd-industory-4-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nagarro-lsd-industory-4-0/</guid>
      <description>Organized Nagarro LSD event, on Industry 4.0, demonstrated usecases on connected services concept, and was a panelist for a discussion on
 Smarter Services - Predictive, Always Connected, Personalized Global experts will debate ways to create smarter services based around predictive maintenance, always connected devices and personalized solutions.
 Whether we call Industry 4.0 an evolution or a revolution, there is little doubt that it will have a disruptive impact on the manufacturing industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another IoT Disruption: A Need of Multi-Skilled Devs</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</guid>
      <description>Technological evolution causes disruption. It replaces traditional, less optimal, complex, lengthy, and costly technology, people, and processes with economical, innovative, optimal, and simpler alternatives. We have seen disruption by mobile phones, and up next is disruption from IoT, wearables, AR-VR, machine Learning, AI, and other innovations. Software development methodology, tools, and people will also face disruption. I expect that the traditional developer will be replaced by the multi-skilled or full-stack developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT based insect monitoring concept</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-insect-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot-insect-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Insects are the most diverse species of animals found on earth. While every species is required to maintain the balance of nature, excessive accumulation of any one type can have devastating effects on humans and environment.
Insect management relies on the early detection and accuracy of insect population monitoring techniquessensors-12-15801. Integrated data gathering about insect population together with the ecological factors like temperature, humidity, light etc., makes it possible to execute appropriate pest control at the right time in the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Steps of the IoT race</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</guid>
      <description>The ‘Internet of Things’ (IoT) presents tremendous opportunity in all the industry verticals and business domains. Specifically, the ‘Industrial Internet of Things’(IIoT) promises to increase the value proposition by making self-optimizing business processes. As discussed in the post “The Driving Forces Behind IoT”, there are several challenges to be addressed to realize the full IoT potentials, but following steps will help organization to systemically make their products participate in the IoT journey and stay in the IoT race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industrial IoT (IIOT) Reference Architecture</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iiot-reference-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iiot-reference-architecture/</guid>
      <description>The industry has been going through an evolution. Industry 4.0 is the fourth industrial revolution where the key will be on digital transformation. Industry 4.0 creates what has been called a &amp;ldquo;smart factory&amp;rdquo;. Within the modular structured smart factories, cyber-physical systems monitor physical processes, create a virtual copy of the physical world and make decentralized decisions. Over the Internet of Things, cyber-physical systems communicate and cooperate with each other and with humans in real time, and via the Internet of Services, both internal and cross-organizational services are offered and used by participants of the value chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart bottle IOT concept</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/building-smart-bottle-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/building-smart-bottle-concept/</guid>
      <description>The rapid growth of Internet of Things (IoT) and miniature wearable biosensors have generated new opportunities for personalized eHealth and mHealth services. We present a case study of an intelligent cap that can measure the amount of water in the bottle, monitor activity of opening or closing of bottle cap. This paper presents a Proof of Concept implementation for such a connected smart bottle that sends measurements to the IoT Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a smart meeting room concept</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</guid>
      <description>On a usual day at office, if an employee wishes to book a meeting room, he or she first has to open their outlook account, check the calendar for its availability and then send a booking invitation. If they directly go to a meeting room, they have no way of knowing whether it is booked or not without checking the calendar.
Smart Meeting Room is a step forward in automating the availability and booking procedure of a meeting room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring AndroidThings IoT</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-android-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-android-things/</guid>
      <description>Android Things, an android based embedded operating system, is the new “it” thing in the Internet of Things(IOT) space. Developed by Google under the codename “Brillo, a.k.a. Project Brillo”, it takes the usual Android development stack—Android Studio, the official SDK, and Google Play Services—and applies it to the IOT.
Google formally took the veils off of Brillo at its I/O 2015 conference. It is aimed to be used with low-power and memory constrained IOT devices, allowing the developers to build a smart device using Android APIs and Google Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Driving Forces Behind IoT</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-driving-forces-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-driving-forces-iot/</guid>
      <description>Everybody in the software industry is talking about IoT in terms of billions of devices, their growth in coming years, changing business models, and adaptation of the IoT in the market. Connecting the things has become so prevalent nowadays, that every software company wants to expand in IoT by building IoT-centric products and services.
There are many industrial applications which connect to sensors and actuators, and can be controlled remotely. They have been around for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework for choosing an IoT Platform</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/choosing_iot_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/choosing_iot_platform/</guid>
      <description>As we understand “IoT Platform” is an essential building block of IoT Ecosystem . A platform essentially decouples the business application from low level details of the technology stack and required services. Thus, it makes more sense to go for an off-the-shelf platform that provide all the relevant features and required flexibility, instead of developing the whole IoT stack from scratch. Selection of an IoT Platform is a key to develop a scalable and robust IoT Solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIGFOX - An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/sigfox-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/sigfox-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>SIGFOX is providing a communication solution dedicated to the Internet of Things
Dedicated to the IOT means:
 Simplicity: No configuration, no pairing, no signaling Autonomy: Very low energy consumption, allowing years of autonomy on battery without maintenance Small messages: No large assets or multimedia, only small messages  It is a LPWA (Low-Power Wide-Area) network, currently operating in 20 countries in Europe, Americas and Asia/Pacific. Communications over the SIGFOX network are bi-directional: uplink from device &amp;amp; downlink to the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOT Cloud Platforms -  A Comparative Study</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</guid>
      <description>The vision of IoT can be seen from two perspectives— ‘Internet’ centric and ‘Thing’ centric. The Internet centric architecture will involve internet services being the main focus while data is contributed by the objects. In the object centric architecture, the smart objects take the center stage.
In order to realize the full potential of cloud computing as well as ubiquitous sensing, a combined framework with a cloud at the center seems to be most viable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>