<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>metaverse on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/metaverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in metaverse on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/metaverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Metaverse — a technological evolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days. In most of my sessions people ask what is the technology stack for Metaverse? what should I learn to stay relevant? etc.. I will try to cover it in this article. In my earlier article I tried to define the Metaverse, and my friend Vinodh Arumugam also attempted the same here. It is defined so loosely that every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suits their narrative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge at Tech-Nexus Hackathon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/tech-nexus-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/tech-nexus-2021/</guid>
      <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Metaverse is the next Internet, that’s what we summarized it in the previous article. We discussed it’s characteristics and building blocks. In this article we will discuss some prominent use cases of the metaverse. We understand the metaverse as a trillion dollar opportunity in the next few years. It is growing at real fast speed, but without effective rules and regulations, without effective standards and practices, and we will also touch upon this concerning part of metaverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Metaverse is the most enquired word after Facebook renamed itself to “Meta” to align to their metaversal vision. However, the term “metaverse” was coined 3 decade ago by Neal Stephenson, in his 1992 science-fiction novel “Snow Crash,” which envisions a virtual reality-based successor to the internet. In the novel, people use digital avatars of themselves to explore the online world, often as a way of escaping a dystopian reality.
Today, Metaverse is being considered as a $800 billion path with double digit growth in next 5 years, where industry is trying to get most out of it by co-creating with communities, and focusing on it’s cost-effective universal acceptance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Metaverse&#39; at NIT Hamirpur</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</guid>
      <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try everything in your space - WebXR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</guid>
      <description>Today’s websites are designed first for mobile and then for other platforms, and it is getting important to bring mobile XR functionality into the websites. Google’s scene viewer is bringing WebXR for mass adoption. Theoretically any 3D model can be tried in your space, and you can easily built AR experience for your website.
eCommerce has already transformed into mCommerse, and now taking steps into xCommerse (XR Commerce). 3D Model viewer is very common requirement for across different domains, and it will be the basic requirement of developing for Metaverse as well as for any digital business in future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
