<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>metaverse on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/metaverse/</link>
        <description>Recent content in metaverse on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/metaverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Humanizing AI: Reflections on 2025 and the Road Ahead for 2026</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2025-reflections-2026-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2025-reflections-2026-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we close 2025 and step into 2026, this moment offers more than a calendar transition—it offers clarity. The past year tested assumptions, accelerated adoption, and forced recalibration across technology, business, and society.
For me personally, 2025 was a milestone year. After reflecting on two decades in the industry, I published my second book, Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life, in both Hindi and English, while continuing to engage readers through Exploring the Metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕Jagjeevan launch@Thoughtworks</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks, Thoughtworkers, and books share a deep and enduring connection. Over the years, hundreds of books have been authored by Thoughtworkers, reflecting a culture rooted in thought leadership, learning, and knowledge sharing.
As part of this vibrant thought-sharing community, I recently had the privilege of launching my book 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger than Life at the Thoughtworks office and signing copies for colleagues. The moment was special—not just because it was a book launch, but because it was about sharing timeless life lessons and inspirations drawn from the life of my great-grandfather, lessons that feel especially relevant in today’s fast-paced world.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Symposium Takeaways and Book Launch at IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of speaking at XR Symposium 2025, hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class symposium showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker | Gatherverse Book Summit 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-booksummit-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-booksummit-2025/</guid>
            <description>📢 Gatherverse Book Summit 2025: Exploring Books, Language and Meaning in the Age of New Technology.
 In the intersection of emerging technologies and humanity, this GatherVerse event aims to deep dive into the current and future state of books in an age defined by artificial intelligence. This is a space for authors, researchers, engineers, ethicists, educators, publishers, technologists and readers. We explore what it means to write, publish, and trust books in a time where machine-generated language is flooding the landscape</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker | XR Symposium for GLOBAL SOUTH</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-symposium-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-symposium-2025/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to share that I am part of the XR Symposium 2025 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Books</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/books/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/books/</guid>
            <description>📕 Jagjeevan  Living Larger than Life 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life is a heartfelt tribute to the extraordinary life and timeless wisdom of Shri Jagguram—an enlightened soul whose values shaped generations. Blending personal memories with profound life lessons, it captures the essence of a man who lived with humility, discipline, compassion, and unwavering purpose.
 Through ten insightful chapters, the book explores heritage, resilience, responsibility, inner strength, family unity, conflict resolution, gratitude, and the power of one’s actions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How Small, How Big: Seeing Life Through the Lens of the Universe</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/how-small-how-big-analysis/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/how-small-how-big-analysis/</guid>
            <description>After a few hectic months, I recently visited a camping site with my family — a truly refreshing experience being close to nature. The trip was hosted by Camp Gopika and accompanied by Astrostop, adding a unique touch to our stay.
The serene environment gave me time to reflect on life and also work on the final touches of my upcoming book, 📕 “Jagjeevan – Living Larger than Life”, which tells the story of my great-grandfather and his belief that travel is essential for learning and introspection.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>ITU-T Technical Report - IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/itu-t-sg20-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/itu-t-sg20-2025/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the privilege of representing 🇮🇳 India at the International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) Study Group 20 (SG20) meeting in Geneva.
I’m pleased to share that my recommendations for standardizing requirements for an IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System has been accepted as an official Technical Report. Here’s a brief overview of the experience and its significance.
About ITU-T Study Group 20 The ITU-T is a global body that develops standards for telecommunications and ICT, bringing together governments, industry leaders, and academia.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker | Pre AI Impact Summit: Openness in AI</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/pre-ai-impact-summit-openess-in-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/pre-ai-impact-summit-openess-in-ai/</guid>
            <description>India will host the AI Impact Summit 2026, reaffirming its commitment to making Artificial Intelligence (AI) accessible and beneficial for the public good. The event will explore how AI can address real-world challenges in healthcare, education, agriculture, climate change, and governance—building on the momentum of global gatherings like the AI Action Summit France, AI Seoul Summit, and AI Safety Summit.
As part of the lead-up to the summit, OpenUK and OpenHQ have been hosting pre-summit events to spark conversations around AI openness.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>DJXHack 2025 | Fostering Artificial Sense in the XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>DJXHack 2025 was an inspiring hackathon organized by DJX Labs, attracting students and professionals from across institutions. Out of many applicants, 30 XR enthusiasts were shortlisted to participate and showcase innovative ideas in extended reality (XR).
I had the honor of being invited as a speaker, where I shared my thoughts on how AI is fostering artificial sense in the XR world. Grateful to be a part of such an impactful event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Livestreaming</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/streaming/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/streaming/</guid>
            <description>Machine Gaze - What Happens When Glasses Begin to Think Gatherverse Summit 2025 - ☞ More Details   The Metaverse United : How AI and XR Can Deepen Human Connections Gatherverse Summit 2025 - ☞ More Details   Defining the AI Powered Virtual World Gatherverse Virtual World Symposium 2024 - ☞ More Details   India&amp;rsquo;s Metaverse Journey: Opportunities and Challenges XROM Postcast - ☞ More Details   Global Insights from XR Leaders in India: AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR AWE Asia 2024 - ☞ More Details   Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR Express Computer Webinar - ☞ More Details   Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World Season of AI - Azure Developer Community - Rekill - ☞ More Details   Evolving into Tomorrow, Today: Enter the Metaverse Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024 - ☞ More Details   Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining the reality in the digital age Book promo - ☞ More Details   XR in practice: the engineering challenges of extending reality Thoughtworks Podcast - ☞ More Details   AI Assisted Content Pipeline for XR Thoughtworks XConf 2022 - ☞ More Details    Using XR in building autonomous vehicles Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021 - ☞ More Details   &amp;nbsp;  The Shift from Enterprise XR to Ethical XR Thoughtworks XConf 2021 - ☞ More Details   Navigating the new normal The VRARA - ☞ More Details    eXtended Reality for Enterprise XROM Podcast - ☞ More Details   XR - Nicety to Necessity Techgig Webinars - ☞ More Details    How to get started with AR VR?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2025 | AI and XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit-2025/</guid>
            <description>XREvolve Summit serves a comprehensive platform for exploring the latest advancements, applications, applied sciences and progresses within AI, AR, VR, and the broader domains of the metaverse such as spatial computing. It is backed by Gatherverse community, that advocates humanity-first standards in accessibility, education, equality, community development, safety &amp;amp; privacy, wellness, and ethics within the metaverse and emerging technologies.
This year&amp;rsquo;s focus is AR and AI: The Intersection of the Future, that open up the extraordinary and near limitless possibilities for humanity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Globally</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-globally/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-globally/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo; is now available globally!
Read the detail synopsis of the book here and testimonials from a diverse set of industry leaders
Buy Paper Back: 🇧🇪 Amazon Belgium - 👉 Get it in 32,80€ (4% off)  🇧🇷 Amazon Brazil - 👉 Get it in R$200,16  🇨🇦 Amazon Canada - 👉 Get it in $45.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>💯 Celebrating Exploring the Metaverse: A Year of Insights, Impact, and Gratitude</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-acknowledgements/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-acknowledgements/</guid>
            <description>Almost a year ago, my book Exploring the Metaverse was launched globally—available at leading retailers including Amazon and BPB Online.
With forewords and testimonials from pioneers across industries, the book aims to demystify the Metaverse and provide a thoughtful lens on its technological, business, and societal implications. It&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly fulfilling to see it resonate with readers and spark meaningful conversations.
This milestone wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the unwavering support of Thoughtworks, our ecosystem partners, and—above all—my family, friends, and colleagues.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🚀 HackVSIT 6.0 – Judging the brilliant minds</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackvsit-6-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackvsit-6-2025/</guid>
            <description>HackVSIT6.0 lived up to its name as North India’s Biggest Hackathon. Organised by ACE – Association of Computer Enthusiasts, the technical society of Vivekananda Institute of Professional Studies, New Delhi, it brought together hundreds of brilliant minds brimming with passion, purpose, and a vision to solve real-world problems with technology.
It was an absolute pleasure to join the jury panel, alongside an esteemed group of leaders from across the industry:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 13</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-13/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One notable endorsement comes from industry veteran Mr. Pradeep Khanna, who holds multiple global roles in metaverse eco-system. It is a privilege to work with Pradeep at various front on VRARA and other emerging technologies platform.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 12</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-12/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One notable endorsement comes from Sumeet Gayathri Moghe — Principal Product Manager at Thoughtworks and author of The Async-First Playbook. It is a privilege collaborating with Sumeet, who challenges the notion of being &amp;ldquo;busy&amp;rdquo; and advocates for deep, meaningful work through an async-first mindset—syncing when truly necessary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse Summit 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-summit-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-summit-2025/</guid>
            <description>📢 Gatherverse Summit 2025: Innovating for Human Betterment Now and Forever. Climb.
 GatherVerse Summit 2025 marks the fourth annual gathering of global experts and community leaders discussing humanity-first standards in the approach to AI, the metaverse, and emerging technologies
 I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be part of the Roundtable Panel Discussion on &amp;ldquo;The Metaverse United : How AI and XR Can Deepen Human Connections&amp;rdquo; alongside industry leaders and innovators!
  🗓 Session Details  Date &amp;amp; Time: Feb 25, 2025, 11:20 AM - 12:10 PM PST Roundtable Panel: The Metaverse United : How AI and XR Can Deepen Human Connections Moderator: Lynn Gitau - Director of Communications, Gatherverse Panelists:  Casey Jensen - Head of Client Partnerships, Zebrar Kuldeep Singh - Me David B.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Contributions to ITU-T SG-20 on IoT and Metaverse</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/itu-t-sg20-meeting/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/itu-t-sg20-meeting/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse: The Next Internet The Metaverse represents the next evolution of the internet, a digital realm where the physical and virtual worlds converge. In my book, 📕 Exploring the Metaverse, I delve into the current state of the Metaverse and how advancements in AI, IoT, networking, and cloud technologies are accelerating its development at an unprecedented pace.
As a call to action, I emphasize the importance of collaboration among industry leaders, academia, and individuals to establish standards and practices for the responsible use of the Metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 11</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-11/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-11/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
A notable endorsement came from Mayan Shay May-Raz — Principal Product, Amazon, who has great sense of user centric product designs, I have privilege working closely with her on Lenovo&amp;rsquo;s ThinkReality product like.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 10</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-10/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
Want to highlight a notable endorsement from Mr. Dinkar Charak — esteemed Product Manager(#ProMa), Solutionist, and author of wonderful books on 📕Product Management and 📕Product LifeCycle. His 📕Engineering Excellence to Business Outcome (EEBO) is my personal favorite.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Testing the Ground: Reflections on 2024 and the Road Ahead for 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we bid farewell to 2024 and welcome 2025, it’s a perfect moment to reflect on the lessons this year has offered—both rewarding and challenging—and to prepare for the opportunities ahead.
This year marked a significant milestone as I celebrated 20 years in the industry. Along this journey, I shared my experiences by publishing a book, contributing over 30 articles and whitepapers on topics like the AI-powered metaverse, IoT, D&amp;amp;Iand product management.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Immersive AI at IPOS 2024: Transforming the Process Sector</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ipos-dats-conference/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ipos-dats-conference/</guid>
            <description>IPOS 2024 was an inspiring technology summit focused on the innovations, digitalization, and disruptions shaping the downstream oil &amp;amp; gas, petrochemicals, fertilizers, and process manufacturing sectors. The event provided deep insights into operational excellence, optimization, Industry 4.0, sustainability, safety, and more.
Hosted alongside the Digitalization &amp;amp; Automation Technology Summit and Expo (DATs 2024) by the Institute of Technological Excellence (ITEx), this summit brought together downstream industry leaders and technologists to exchange knowledge and ideas.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 9</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-9/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-9/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is now available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
A special highlight is the endorsement from Mr. Ravindra Dastikop—an esteemed academician, entrepreneur, emerging technologies leader, and author of Metaverse Glossary: Your Gateway to the Future. Collaborating with him has been an incredible journey!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit and AWE Nite | XR with AI, Gaming, AVGC</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to announce that I’ll be part of the XR Summit 2024 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 8</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-8/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is now available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One of the standout testimonials is from Mr. Hemanth Kumar Satyanarayana, Founder, CEO at Imaginate XR, an award-winning innovator, MIT TR35 Young Innovator, IIT Madras alum, and TEDx speaker, who has dedicated over two decades to building the XR ecosystem.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the AI-powered Metaverse is Our Next Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>📖 My Takeaways from Our Next Reality by Alvin Wang Graylin and Louis Rosenberg
☞ Buy - Exploring the Metaverse ☞ Buy - Our Next Reality 
Our Next Reality topped my reading list for months, and travel always helps me catch up on books! After meeting Alvin at AWE Asia 2024, I was eager to dive in and finally complete it. Following recent trips to Singapore and now the US, here’s what I found worth sharing from the book.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse Virtual World Symposium 2024</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-virtual-world-symposium/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-virtual-world-symposium/</guid>
            <description>📢 Virtual World Symposium: Join us as we dive deep into the future of AI-powered virtual worlds:
 What are they? Where are they headed? And why is it crucial to discuss these transformative spaces to..day?
 This symposium will also unpack spatial intelligence and its role in defining and enhancing immersive environments. As we step into a new era of digital interaction, this event will provide insights into the challenges and opportunities that virtual worlds bring to society.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 7</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-7/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-7/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is now available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One of the incredible testimonials comes from Vanya Seth, Head of Technology at Thoughtworks. Vanya is a visionary tech leader, an active speaker in various tech communities, and a fellow participant in the XROS Fellowship program alongside me.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>India&#39;s Metaverse Journey - XROM Podcast</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-exploring-the-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-exploring-the-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>Exciting conversation on the future of tech with Eddie Avil, where we dive into my journey of writing Exploring the Metaverse, discuss the opportunities and challenges of the digital age, and even touch on mind-bending concepts like Programmable Dreams and Time Travel. Are we ready for what’s coming?
XROM Podcast 🎙️ XROM PODCast, hosted by serial entrepreneur and visionary Eddie Avil, is an incredible YouTube channel showcasing conversations with industry leaders in emerging tech.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Featured in XTIC Chronicle, IIT Madras Newsletter</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xtic-newsletter-sep-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xtic-newsletter-sep-2024/</guid>
            <description>I am excited to share that my article explaining my book has been featured in the recent September edition of the XTIC Chronicle, a quarterly newsletter published by XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre) at IIT Madras. As India’s first research and product innovation center dedicated to Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics. XTIC provides a platform for cutting-edge insights from academia, industry, startups, and CAVE members.
XTIC Chronicle Overview The XTIC Chronicle is a valuable resource for all levels of readers interested in the latest advancements in XR technology.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 6</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-6/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-6/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
The book explores the opportunities and concerns of the metaverse, outlining a path forward that calls for collective action from academia, industry, government, and individuals. I initiated this collective effort by gathering testimonials from a diverse group of experts.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 5</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
One of the most distinguished endorsements comes from Prof. M Manivannan, who leads the Experiential Technologies Innovation Center (XTIC) at IIT Madras.
Prof. Mani has spearheaded innovation at XTIC and have made India proud. His pioneering work in areas like iTad(interactive Touch Active Display) and integrating haptics into virtual reality solutions is noteworthy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 4</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Venkatesh Ponniah, Global Head of Emerging Technologies at Thoughtworks.
We call him Venki. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Venki on technology strategy and governance. He has great insights into emerging technology businesses, particularly in AI, SDV, Digital Twins, and XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ai-powered-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ai-powered-xr/</guid>
            <description>In a world where AI is ubiquitous, technologies like AR, VR, and XR often raise eyebrows, despite their vast potential. AI is not only propelling these technologies forward but also preparing them for the next stages of development. There are tremendous opportunities to leverage their potential for business transformation. I am honored to be invited by Express Computers - India Leading IT Magazine, to speak on this topic and dispel common myths.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR - the Enabler | XROS Fellowship Report</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, a transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtended Reality (XR) at its core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution is the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. My book, Exploring the Metaverse, available globally, outlines this kind of collaboration as a call to action for all of us.
FICCI XROS Fellowship Program Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce &amp;amp; Industry (FICCI), is the voice of india&amp;rsquo;s business and industry for policy change.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>Season of AI, a virtual event series of the Microsoft Azure Developer Community by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a session, where I had the opportunity to guide the community and share insights from my experience in XR and AI development.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, and special thanks to Rohit Sardana and Azkar Khan for extending the invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture: AI and Metaverse reshaping the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</guid>
            <description>AI is pervasive, whether we sense it or not. Staying updated has become essential for survival. We are increasingly immersed in artificially generated worlds, with the internet rapidly evolving into what is known as the metaverse. In my book, &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, I delve into its various forms and interpretations, usecases and challenges, and the way forward.
DesignersX, a company specializing in software development, invited me to speak about my book and discuss how AI and the metaverse will shape the future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 3</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Kanchan Ray, Chief Technology Officer at Nagarro. We collaborated on building and conceptualizing various cutting-edge proof-of-concepts using emerging technologies. His support and advice were always invaluable.
🙏 I extend my heartfelt thanks to Kanchan for reviewing early versions of the book, sharing his valuable insights, and writing the following foreword:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing the Metaverse at VRARA Energy Committee Event</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/exploring-metaverse-vrara-energy-committee/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/exploring-metaverse-vrara-energy-committee/</guid>
            <description>The VRAR Association(VRARA) is an international organization designed to foster collaboration between XR, mixed reality, spatial computing, and artificial intelligence (AI) solution providers and end-users that accelerates growth, fosters research and education, helps develop industry best practices, connects member organizations and promotes the services of member companies.
VRARA has various industry focused committees, and I am invited to speak at an event by Energy Committee.
Thanks Hemanth Satyanarayana and Susan Spark for invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</guid>
            <description>XREvolve Summit serves a comprehensive platform for exploring the latest advancements, applications, applied sciences and progresses within AR, VR, and the broader domains of the metaverse such as spatial computing and mixed reality. It is backed by Gatherverse community, that advocates humanity-first standards in accessibility, education, equality, community development, safety &amp;amp; privacy, wellness, and ethics within the metaverse and emerging technologies.
This year&amp;rsquo;s focus is XR : Interface of AI, that open up the extraordinary and near limitless possibilities for humanity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Dr. Rebecca J Parsons, former Chief Technology Officer at Thoughtworks. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Rebecca at numerous technology strategy events, where her insights on responsible technology usage and our collective responsibility towards sustainability and technological adaptation have been invaluable.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MIPS kick off event, XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse India Policy and Standards (MIPS) is a pioneering initiative led by Experiential Technology Innovation Centre (XTIC), serving as India’s premier research and product innovation hub for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics, hosted at IIT Madras.
It&amp;rsquo;s an honor to be the member of MIPS and showcase my book Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age, which aligns closely with the initiative&amp;rsquo;s objectives.
I extend my gratitude to Thriveni Palanivelu for orchestrating a seamless event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse — A Synopsis</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo; featured on Industry4.0. It is available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online.
 The metaverse, a loosely defined term, has gone from a virtual game world to the next internet and sparks conversations on technology’s potential. Despite eye-rolling at terms like metaverse and eXtended Reality (XR), immersive technologies are silently becoming part of our daily life through social media, virtual collaboration, and digitized experiences. We seamlessly embrace digital tools, scanning codes, engaging in virtual trials, and altering reality through digital filters.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR in India — A Whitepaper by XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</guid>
            <description>XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre), is India’s 1st Research &amp;amp; Product Innovation centre for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality and Haptics at IIT Madras. It has published a white-paper and skill gap analysis for Experiential Technologies in India.
Whitepaper - XR in India
It was great to be a contributor in this research. It is authored by 19 industry leader from various enterprises, institutes and government body. Excursions from this research also got published in The Hindu Businessline.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Vishal Shah, General Manager of XR and Metaverse at Lenovo. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of hearing Vishal speak at events like CES and AWE, where he shared invaluable insights on the metaverse and XR technology. Meeting him in person at Lenovo Tech World 2023 was a highlight, where we discussed this book, and he graciously agreed to contribute to its exploration of the metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Why collaboration is essential for building a successful XR future?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</guid>
            <description>The era of isolated development and secret-keeping innovation is fading. In the past, companies, individuals could thrive by becoming subject matter experts within their own walls. However, the rise of generative AI, fueled by shared knowledge, has changed the game. AI can now imagine and generate solutions faster than ever. The future belongs to those who embrace openness, collaboration, and shared learning.
 Expertise alone isn’t enough. Today, success hinges on building strong networks, fostering partnerships, and collaborating within communities.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead The concept of the Metaverse keeps evolving, leaving many confused. 📖 In my book, Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age I leverage my years of experience to:
 Unravel the Metaverse: Demystify the term and explore its true potential. Separate Myth from Reality: Address misconceptions surrounding the metaverse. Prepare for the Future: Equip you with insights to navigate the evolving digital landscape.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Future of Retail with Extended Reality (XR)</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-future-of-retail-with-extended-reality-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-future-of-retail-with-extended-reality-xr/</guid>
            <description>eXtended Reality (XR/AR/VR) technology is changing the reality of almost every industry today by enhancing user experiences. XR adoption in the retail industry is also quite natural, let&amp;rsquo;s understand how it is shaping up the future of retail.
In today’s retail landscape, technology is reshaping customer experiences, with XR leading the charge. Extended Reality (XR), including VR, AR, and MR, offers immersive experiences blending the physical and virtual worlds. From head-mounted displays to smart glasses and smartphones and beyond, XR is changing how we interact with retail environments.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Making the XR content usable with AI!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</guid>
            <description>Generative AI is revolutionizing content generation across various mediums, disrupting traditional methods in text, images, art, movies, and music creation. XR (Extended Reality) is also undergoing this transformation. In a previous article, Raju Kandaswamy and I discussed how AI aids in generating content for XR, meeting the dynamic needs of XR and the metaverse.
We highlighted content management as a key challenge in XR and metaverse adoption. While generative AI methods offer some solutions, the significant hurdle of content optimization remains.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Coming Soon! Exploring the Metaverse</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</guid>
            <description>In the world of tech buzzwords, “metaverse” has been topic of discussion, largely understood and misunderstood. It comes, goes, and comes again in new shapes and forms, definitions and understanding. The term has been around for three decades and is poised to continue its evolution.
In the past, it has been defined to suit the narratives of organizations and individuals alike. Some see it as a game, others as a virtual world, while some view it as a tool for global connection and collaboration.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Immersive is the new interactive</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/thoughtworks-immersive-is-the-new-interactive/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/thoughtworks-immersive-is-the-new-interactive/</guid>
            <description>The way we interact with each other, and the world around us, is changing fast. And with consumer expectations continuing to grow, enterprises are racing to find new ways to deliver immersive experiences. I am republishing this article from Thoughtworks Insights here.
 As we discuss in the evolving interactions lens of our latest Looking Glass report, extended reality (XR) technologies offer new opportunities to engage and entertain. But what exactly is XR?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughtworks&#39; Looking Glass 2024 - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/thougthworks-looking-glass-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/thougthworks-looking-glass-2024/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks unveils its latest tech trends report, &amp;lsquo;Looking Glass&amp;rsquo;, a comprehensive analysis of emerging technologies designed to empower organizations and leaders in making informed decisions. The 2024 edition of report, covering over 100 trends, is segmented through five lenses, each offering insights, signals, and strategic recommendations for adoption, analysis, and anticipation.
Key takeaways: Here are my key takeaways:
 AI&amp;rsquo;s ubiquitous reach - AI is going in every facet of technology, from conversational interfaces to AI-assisted software development and software-defined vehicles.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Foundational shifts: Reflecting on 2023 and anticipating ahead</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2023-reflections-2024-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2023-reflections-2024-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we say goodbye to 2023 and welcome 2024, it&amp;rsquo;s a time to think about the good and tough parts of the year. Not everything goes the way we want, but we can learn from both the good and bad experiences. I see 2023 as a year of making things better, like fixing the base of a building. I&amp;rsquo;ve picked my top five observations on foundational changes from this year, and some might continue into 2024.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Panelist at FICCI XROS Fellowship Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, the transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtending Reality (XR) at it&amp;rsquo;s core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution would be the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. I recently had the privilege of participating as a panelist at an event hosted by the pioneers shaping the future of the internet. In this article, I share my insights and a summary of this remarkable event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generative AI for 3D content in XR and beyond</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/generative-ai-for-3d-content-in-xr-and-beyond/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/generative-ai-for-3d-content-in-xr-and-beyond/</guid>
            <description>We touched upon Generative AI while talking about AI assisted content pipeline for XR at Thoughtworks XConf 2022. Generative AI is capable of producing outputs that closely resemble those created by humans. It is evolving in multiple forms, one of its kind is ChatGPT, a useful tool buried beneath the hype. It was touted as Google Killer, and posed a disruption to the way we search, we communicate with machines, and the way machines can respond.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Lean2Lead tech track - Twisted realities</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</guid>
            <description>Lean2Lead is a network of women at work, with will to lead and succeed in their respective areas of work. They are 400+ women from different industries together in this group for exchange of ideas, connecting and coaching, building network with industry leaders and inspiring each other for building strategies for success in leadership and executive roles.
I am speaking at their tech session series, on 15 July 2023, 3-4 PM.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Progress Review - Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/msh-progress-review-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/msh-progress-review-1/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality (XR) is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and user believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited to join the Progress Review Committee as a Judge for Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program. It is great talking to top XR startups of India.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Greening Up: Key takeaways from Green Software Foundation Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/green-software-foundation-meetup-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/green-software-foundation-meetup-2023/</guid>
            <description>As technology continues to advance, electronics are getting smaller and wires are disappearing. Even electric poles, once a familiar sight on road trips, are being phased out. With the internet now ubiquitous, physical storage devices are disappearing too, and we rely more on cloud-based solutions that seem to happen over the air.
 ‘It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder we look up when we think of clouds ☁️, but should actually look down to the earth in the mines!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Potential of XR Technology for Virtual Decoration</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-virtual-decoration/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-virtual-decoration/</guid>
            <description>In recent years, XR technology has revolutionized the way we decorate our physical environments. By utilizing AI and computer vision, XR can scan and track real-world surroundings, recognizing and remembering images and objects to enable the addition of virtual content. This technology can store and recall virtual decorations, making them visible every time someone enters the environment. While image matching is not a new concept, XR platforms like Vuforia have already implemented various mobile XR examples.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Community Events are the Energy Boosters!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gta_lets_fork_together/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gta_lets_fork_together/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the opportunity to contribute to an event called &amp;ldquo;GTA Ghaziabad - Let’s Fork Together&amp;rdquo;. The event was hosted by a community of working professionals and undergraduate engineers from nearby colleges in NCR, and took place at my home office, Thoughtworks Gurgaon. Participating in this event provided me with another energy boost, and in this article, I would like to share my experience and give you a glimpse of what the event was all about!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Agility Today Fest 2023 - Generative AI and XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</guid>
            <description>Agility Today is a 2 days annual UnConference, to meet Agility needs of industry, gathered over past few years via meetups, Conferences and Webinar. This UnConference intends to give you best of Agile Psyche (Mindset Culture and Practice) and Geekery (Engineering, Tools and DevOps). This year in Agility Today Fest 2023 there are couple of programs.
I am speaking to at Agile Engineering Lab (Technical Agility &amp;amp; Engineering Excellence), on topic of Scaling content generation for XR using AI.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
            <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI-Assisted Content Generation Pipeline for XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-generated-xr-content/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/ai-generated-xr-content/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I and Raju Kandaswamy talked at Thoughtworks XConf on how AI will play its role in content generation. We are already seeing ChatGPT, as the next revolution in textual content generation space. Let&amp;rsquo;s understand what is the need of such content generation revolution of XR space.
With games like Second Life and the impending mainstreaming of the Metaverse, more and more individuals are embracing a virtual reality that, in some ways, mirrors our own real world and, in other ways, lets us live in our imagination or apply them on the real word.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;SpatialWeb and Web3.0&#39; at NIT Calicut</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/guest_lecture_nit_calicut/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/guest_lecture_nit_calicut/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Calicut is organizing Tathva, Asia&amp;rsquo;s largest student-run Tech Startup Expo. Tathva is a techno-management fest of NIT Calicut is one of south India&amp;rsquo;s biggest scholastic endeavours. Since its inception in 2000, this annual symposium has known only growth and has flourished into one of the few promising enterprises the nation has witnessed. Pushing the barriers year after year, Tathva aims at providing a plethora of platforms to the intrigued technical heads that arrive at this fiesta with an array of events and workshops, to sharpen their skills and widen their knowledge quotient.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</guid>
            <description>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table The thoughtleadership roundtable is an exclusive event hosted by VAMRR Technologies Pvt Ltd, where they invite an elite gathering of 20 ITeS leaders focused on the areas of Design Visualization, Digital Twin and Hybrid Workspaces.
This one is the 98th Conference/Round Table by VAMRR Technologies, and focus this roundtable would be on developments across Advanced Visualization, Remote Design Collaboration, Hybrid Workspaces, 3D Workflows, Data Integrated Digital Twins, Web3 and Metaverse are all converging.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Launch | Metaverse Glossary - Your gateway to the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-glossary-book/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-glossary-book/</guid>
            <description>The Metaverse Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days, and every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suit their narrative. It would end up creating many sub-metaverses, with different sets of features and, would lead to confusions, and conflict of interests. Acceptable definition of Metaverse will evolve with time. At this stage, I treat the metaverse as a result of technological evolutions in the key areas such as ARVR, AI, Cloud, Blockchain, 5G/6G and hardware.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse Workshop - VIT-AP University</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</guid>
            <description>School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCOPE) of VIT-AP University is organizing a 1-day National Workshop on “Exploring the Blockchain in Metaverse” on June 11, 2022, from 11 am to 5 pm.
 The program is intended for students, faculty of technical institutes, professionals from Industry, R&amp;amp;D organizations, and research scholars.
I will be speaking at the workshop on &amp;ldquo;Gearing up for Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, Will touch upon metaverse step by step.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XR and Sustainability - GSF Global Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</guid>
            <description>Green Software Foundation Green Software Foundation (GSF) is building a trusted ecosystem of people, standards, tooling and best practices for Green Software. GSF works with vision to change the culture of building software across the tech industry, so sustainability becomes a core priority to software teams, just as important as performance, security, cost and accessibility. Read more here.
GSF Global Summit 2022 The Green Software Foundation Global Summit 2022 is a series of free events organized by Green Software Foundation members all around the globe that are passionate about sustainable software development, maintenance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture at VIT Vellore</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse has become the newest macro-goal for tech industries to invest in and to see the world in a new perspective with the help of AR and VR technologies.🌟
A student club at VIT Vellore named Mozilla Firefox Club invited me for a guest lecture in The Parallax View Episode 1 :Bring the world to wherever you are
 🔮✨Join us on 22nd April, 6PM to clarify all your doubts regarding AR and VR and opportunities it offers you !</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse — a technological evolution</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days. In most of my sessions people ask what is the technology stack for Metaverse? what should I learn to stay relevant? etc.. I will try to cover it in this article. In my earlier article I tried to define the Metaverse, and my friend Vinodh Arumugam also attempted the same here. It is defined so loosely that every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suits their narrative.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at Tech-Nexus Hackathon</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/tech-nexus-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/tech-nexus-2021/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the next Internet, that’s what we summarized it in the previous article. We discussed it’s characteristics and building blocks. In this article we will discuss some prominent use cases of the metaverse. We understand the metaverse as a trillion dollar opportunity in the next few years. It is growing at real fast speed, but without effective rules and regulations, without effective standards and practices, and we will also touch upon this concerning part of metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most enquired word after Facebook renamed itself to “Meta” to align to their metaversal vision. However, the term “metaverse” was coined 3 decade ago by Neal Stephenson, in his 1992 science-fiction novel “Snow Crash,” which envisions a virtual reality-based successor to the internet. In the novel, people use digital avatars of themselves to explore the online world, often as a way of escaping a dystopian reality.
Today, Metaverse is being considered as a $800 billion path with double digit growth in next 5 years, where industry is trying to get most out of it by co-creating with communities, and focusing on it’s cost-effective universal acceptance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Metaverse&#39; at NIT Hamirpur</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Try everything in your space - WebXR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</guid>
            <description>Today’s websites are designed first for mobile and then for other platforms, and it is getting important to bring mobile XR functionality into the websites. Google’s scene viewer is bringing WebXR for mass adoption. Theoretically any 3D model can be tried in your space, and you can easily built AR experience for your website.
eCommerce has already transformed into mCommerse, and now taking steps into xCommerse (XR Commerce). 3D Model viewer is very common requirement for across different domains, and it will be the basic requirement of developing for Metaverse as well as for any digital business in future.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>