<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>google on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/google/</link>
        <description>Recent content in google on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Livestreaming</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/streaming/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/streaming/</guid>
            <description>XR Symposium - User Interaction and Experience Design for Global South IIT madras hosted XR Symposium 2025 - ☞ More Details   Machine Gaze - What Happens When Glasses Begin to Think Gatherverse XR Evolve Summit 2025 - ☞ More Details   The Metaverse United : How AI and XR Can Deepen Human Connections Gatherverse Summit 2025 - ☞ More Details   Defining the AI Powered Virtual World Gatherverse Virtual World Symposium 2024 - ☞ More Details   India&amp;rsquo;s Metaverse Journey: Opportunities and Challenges XROM Postcast - ☞ More Details   Global Insights from XR Leaders in India: AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR AWE Asia 2024 - ☞ More Details   Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR Express Computer Webinar - ☞ More Details   Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World Season of AI - Azure Developer Community - Rekill - ☞ More Details   Evolving into Tomorrow, Today: Enter the Metaverse Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024 - ☞ More Details   Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining the reality in the digital age Book promo - ☞ More Details   XR in practice: the engineering challenges of extending reality Thoughtworks Podcast - ☞ More Details   AI Assisted Content Pipeline for XR Thoughtworks XConf 2022 - ☞ More Details    Using XR in building autonomous vehicles Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021 - ☞ More Details   &amp;nbsp;  The Shift from Enterprise XR to Ethical XR Thoughtworks XConf 2021 - ☞ More Details   Navigating the new normal The VRARA - ☞ More Details    eXtended Reality for Enterprise XROM Podcast - ☞ More Details   XR - Nicety to Necessity Techgig Webinars - ☞ More Details    How to get started with AR VR?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the next Internet, that’s what we summarized it in the previous article. We discussed it’s characteristics and building blocks. In this article we will discuss some prominent use cases of the metaverse. We understand the metaverse as a trillion dollar opportunity in the next few years. It is growing at real fast speed, but without effective rules and regulations, without effective standards and practices, and we will also touch upon this concerning part of metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most enquired word after Facebook renamed itself to “Meta” to align to their metaversal vision. However, the term “metaverse” was coined 3 decade ago by Neal Stephenson, in his 1992 science-fiction novel “Snow Crash,” which envisions a virtual reality-based successor to the internet. In the novel, people use digital avatars of themselves to explore the online world, often as a way of escaping a dystopian reality.
Today, Metaverse is being considered as a $800 billion path with double digit growth in next 5 years, where industry is trying to get most out of it by co-creating with communities, and focusing on it’s cost-effective universal acceptance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Try everything in your space - WebXR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</guid>
            <description>Today’s websites are designed first for mobile and then for other platforms, and it is getting important to bring mobile XR functionality into the websites. Google’s scene viewer is bringing WebXR for mass adoption. Theoretically any 3D model can be tried in your space, and you can easily built AR experience for your website.
eCommerce has already transformed into mCommerse, and now taking steps into xCommerse (XR Commerce). 3D Model viewer is very common requirement for across different domains, and it will be the basic requirement of developing for Metaverse as well as for any digital business in future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here LinkedIn
Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
            <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here LinkedIn
We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Smart Glasses</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-google-glass/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-google-glass/</guid>
            <description>This article describes the fundamentals of light-weight smart glasses such as Google Glass and Vuzix M100 It also explain the development practices with pros and cons of its usage, limitation and future of these glasses in our lives.
Google Glass Enterprise Edition Google Glass enterprise edition is a plain Android based smart glass that you can wear and performs operations just like a smartphone and with the use of a small screen located in the front of your right eye can perform a decent range of tasks.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IOT Cloud Platforms -  A Comparative Study</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</guid>
            <description>The vision of IoT can be seen from two perspectives— ‘Internet’ centric and ‘Thing’ centric. The Internet centric architecture will involve internet services being the main focus while data is contributed by the objects. In the object centric architecture, the smart objects take the center stage.
In order to realize the full potential of cloud computing as well as ubiquitous sensing, a combined framework with a cloud at the center seems to be most viable.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>