<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>architecture on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/architecture/</link>
        <description>Recent content in architecture on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Certificates</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/certificates/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/certificates/</guid>
            <description>Building AI Elements of AI Product Management Enterprise Architecture Internet of Things (IOT) User Experience Design Taradata Certified Java Certified Programmer </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lessons Learned From Blockchain-Based Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</guid>
            <description>Blockchain or DLT (Distributed Ledger Technology) is getting good traction in the IT world these days. Earlier, this technology was being mostly explored by banks and other finance-related institutions, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum. Now, it is getting explored for other use cases for building distributed applications. Blockchain technology comes with a decentralized and immutable data structure that maintains a connected block of information. Each block is connected using a hash of the previous block, and every new block on the chain is validated (mined) before adding and replicating it.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>5 Hard Lessons From Microservices Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</guid>
            <description>Microservices-based development is happening all around the industry; more than 70% are trying development of microservice-based software. Microservices simplify integration of the businesses, processes, technology, and people by breaking down the big-bang monolith problem to a smaller set that can be handled independently. However, it also comes with the problem of managing relations between these smaller sets. We used to manage fewer independent units, so there was less operation and planning effort.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Industrial IoT (IIOT) Reference Architecture</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iiot-reference-architecture/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iiot-reference-architecture/</guid>
            <description>The industry has been going through an evolution. Industry 4.0 is the fourth industrial revolution where the key will be on digital transformation. Industry 4.0 creates what has been called a &amp;ldquo;smart factory&amp;rdquo;. Within the modular structured smart factories, cyber-physical systems monitor physical processes, create a virtual copy of the physical world and make decentralized decisions. Over the Internet of Things, cyber-physical systems communicate and cooperate with each other and with humans in real time, and via the Internet of Services, both internal and cross-organizational services are offered and used by participants of the value chain.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>JavaScript Plugin Framework</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/javascript-plugin-framework/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/javascript-plugin-framework/</guid>
            <description>Javascript Plugin Framework is implemented to add extra functionality in the existing Web based application without actually changing the application code. This framework is also helpful when some functionality need to control for different user profiles.
For example, to add one extra button in a menu we can write the plugin directly, by defining what that button is going to do on click, what all events should it handle, in one javascript file rather than making changes in the application code for the same.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>