<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>ml on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/ml/</link>
        <description>Recent content in ml on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>🚀 HackVSIT 6.0 – Judging the brilliant minds</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/hackvsit-6-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/hackvsit-6-2025/</guid>
            <description>HackVSIT6.0 lived up to its name as North India’s Biggest Hackathon. Organised by ACE – Association of Computer Enthusiasts, the technical society of Vivekananda Institute of Professional Studies, New Delhi, it brought together hundreds of brilliant minds brimming with passion, purpose, and a vision to solve real-world problems with technology.
It was an absolute pleasure to join the jury panel, alongside an esteemed group of leaders from across the industry:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at MOZOHACK 4.0 by the Mozilla Students Club</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/judge-mozohack4-srmkzilla-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/judge-mozohack4-srmkzilla-2023/</guid>
            <description>MOZOHACK is a 24-hour hackathon organized by SRMKZILLA. SRMKZILLA is a Mozilla campus club of SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai(India). It is inspired by the Mozilla Learning Network, provides students an open platform to analyze and enhance their technical and non-technical skills, such as working on open-source projects, developing websites, technical fests, and workshops. The club is conducting the seventh edition of its annual flagship event – MOZOFEST&#39;23 – where they celebrate student community through technical and non-technical events.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge - Ashoka University Hackathon 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ashoka-university-hackathon-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ashoka-university-hackathon-2022/</guid>
            <description>RedBrick Hacks is flagship summer hackathon of Ashoka University, open to students from Delhi NCR. You will have the opportunity to learn, collaborate, and build meaningful projects alongside mentors from various disciplines. For 24 hours on the weekend of June 18, you will have access to free workshops, plenary lectures, prizes worth over ₹8L, games, and more!
The theme of the event was &amp;ldquo;Tech for Social Good&amp;rdquo; with three main tracks: Health &amp;amp; Wellness, Sustainable Growth, and Security &amp;amp; Privacy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge - HackInIndia - Hackathon 2020</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</guid>
            <description>I got chance to judge the HackInIndia event, India&amp;rsquo;s National Level hackathon organized by Script Foundation on 2nd July, 2020.
Around 150 teams signed up across multiple tracks (Healthcare, Open Innovation, ARVR, EdTech, RPA and FinTech) supported by couple of talented mentors. I and Raviraj Subramanian got chance to meet only top 20 teams in Jury round, and I was amazed to see their innovative ideas, and demonstrations the young blood of nation bring on the table.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>