<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>agilitytoday on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/agilitytoday/</link>
        <description>Recent content in agilitytoday on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/agilitytoday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Agility Today Fest 2023 - Generative AI and XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</guid>
            <description>Agility Today is a 2 days annual UnConference, to meet Agility needs of industry, gathered over past few years via meetups, Conferences and Webinar. This UnConference intends to give you best of Agile Psyche (Mindset Culture and Practice) and Geekery (Engineering, Tools and DevOps). This year in Agility Today Fest 2023 there are couple of programs.
I am speaking to at Agile Engineering Lab (Technical Agility &amp;amp; Engineering Excellence), on topic of Scaling content generation for XR using AI.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - AT2020 - Agility in Enterprise XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/at_2020_agilexr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/at_2020_agilexr/</guid>
            <description>Enterprise XR is gaining good traction, and software development’s best practices like Agile principles really matters due to multitude of tooling and tech stacks used for Enterprise XR solutions
Enterprises do face multiple challenges with the XR development lifecycle. One of them is the automation of testing XR applications. In response to this gap, ThoughtWorks has developed Arium – an open-source, lightweight, extensible, platform-agnostic framework that helps write automation tests that are built specifically for XR Applications.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>