<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>iit on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/iit/</link>
        <description>Recent content in iit on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/iit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit and AWE Nite | XR with AI, Gaming, AVGC</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-summit-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-summit-2024/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to announce that I’ll be part of the XR Summit 2024 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Featured in XTIC Chronicle, IIT Madras Newsletter</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xtic-newsletter-sep-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xtic-newsletter-sep-2024/</guid>
            <description>I am excited to share that my article explaining my book has been featured in the recent September edition of the XTIC Chronicle, a quarterly newsletter published by XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre) at IIT Madras. As India’s first research and product innovation center dedicated to Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics. XTIC provides a platform for cutting-edge insights from academia, industry, startups, and CAVE members.
XTIC Chronicle Overview The XTIC Chronicle is a valuable resource for all levels of readers interested in the latest advancements in XR technology.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 5</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
One of the most distinguished endorsements comes from Prof. M Manivannan, who leads the Experiential Technologies Innovation Center (XTIC) at IIT Madras.
Prof. Mani has spearheaded innovation at XTIC and have made India proud. His pioneering work in areas like iTad(interactive Touch Active Display) and integrating haptics into virtual reality solutions is noteworthy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MIPS kick off event, XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse India Policy and Standards (MIPS) is a pioneering initiative led by Experiential Technology Innovation Centre (XTIC), serving as India’s premier research and product innovation hub for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics, hosted at IIT Madras.
It&amp;rsquo;s an honor to be the member of MIPS and showcase my book Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age, which aligns closely with the initiative&amp;rsquo;s objectives.
I extend my gratitude to Thriveni Palanivelu for orchestrating a seamless event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR in India — A Whitepaper by XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</guid>
            <description>XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre), is India’s 1st Research &amp;amp; Product Innovation centre for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality and Haptics at IIT Madras. It has published a white-paper and skill gap analysis for Experiential Technologies in India.
Whitepaper - XR in India
It was great to be a contributor in this research. It is authored by 19 industry leader from various enterprises, institutes and government body. Excursions from this research also got published in The Hindu Businessline.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Progress Review - Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/msh-progress-review-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/msh-progress-review-1/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality (XR) is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and user believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited to join the Progress Review Committee as a Judge for Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program. It is great talking to top XR startups of India.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>