<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Articles on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Articles on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Spatially interact with 3D Model from a 2D app in the smart glasses</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-4/</guid>
            <description>💡 Innovation often starts with solving everyday problems. While working on XR solutions and building operating systems for smart glasses, we solved one such challenge.
Earlier, with our patented AppSpace method, we enabled rendering a phone’s 2D apps in 3D on smart glasses. But we found a gap — there was no direct way for a 2D app (like Chrome) to interact with 3D spatial content.
🏅 Thrilled to share that our solution to this is now recognized with a U.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Navigating the Challenges of Digital Transformation | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/book-navigating-challenges-of-digital-transformation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/book-navigating-challenges-of-digital-transformation/</guid>
            <description>The third industrial revolution gave birth to the digital web—a new era of global connectivity and digital intelligence. My book Exploring the Metaverse, covers it and explore what comes next. As we now step into an AI-driven world, we must ask: where are we truly heading, and how ready are we?
Transformation requires us to evolve—from traditional methods to newer, more adaptive approaches. While the digital era has been around for decades, many industries still struggle with achieving meaningful digital transformation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Globally</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-globally/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-globally/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo; is now available globally!
Read the detail synopsis of the book here and testimonials from a diverse set of industry leaders
Buy Paper Back: 🇧🇪 Amazon Belgium - 👉 Get it in 32,80€ (4% off)  🇧🇷 Amazon Brazil - 👉 Get it in R$200,16  🇨🇦 Amazon Canada - 👉 Get it in $45.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Streaming of Composite Alpha Blended AR/MR Video</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-3/</guid>
            <description>💡 Innovation Often Begins with Solving Everyday Problems
In our daily work, we regularly develop methods, processes, features, or approaches to address specific challenges. While these may initially seem like routine solutions, some of them quietly evolve into true innovations—often without us realizing it at the time.
🏅 I’m excited to share that one such innovation has now been recognized with a U.S. Patent!
Patent No : US 12,323,679 B2 This patent, titled _&amp;ldquo;Streaming of Composite Alpha Blended AR/MR Video&amp;rdquo; granted to Lenovo, introduces a novel method for web-based AR and MR streaming—allowing mixed reality experiences from a headset to be cast directly to a web browser, along with the phone screen.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>💯 Celebrating Exploring the Metaverse: A Year of Insights, Impact, and Gratitude</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-acknowledgements/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-acknowledgements/</guid>
            <description>Almost a year ago, my book Exploring the Metaverse was launched globally—available at leading retailers including Amazon and BPB Online.
With forewords and testimonials from pioneers across industries, the book aims to demystify the Metaverse and provide a thoughtful lens on its technological, business, and societal implications. It&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly fulfilling to see it resonate with readers and spark meaningful conversations.
This milestone wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the unwavering support of Thoughtworks, our ecosystem partners, and—above all—my family, friends, and colleagues.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FOMO to Flow: Building Gen AI Solutions</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/ai-fomo-to-flow-building-genai-solutions/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/ai-fomo-to-flow-building-genai-solutions/</guid>
            <description>Unlock the power of Generative AI by learning to interact with large language models programmatically—and take it further with fine-tuning for customized responses.
If you’re a software maker feeling the fear of missing out (FOMO) on the Gen AI revolution, you’re not alone. The way we build and interact with software is evolving rapidly. “Google it” or “check Stack Overflow” is no longer the go-to approach — AI-first, conversational tools are becoming the new standard across development, design, and decision-making.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 13</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-13/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One notable endorsement comes from industry veteran Mr. Pradeep Khanna, who holds multiple global roles in metaverse eco-system. It is a privilege to work with Pradeep at various front on VRARA and other emerging technologies platform.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>DNS Resolution In Thread Network</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-dns-resolution/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-dns-resolution/</guid>
            <description>In previous articles, we explored communication between a Thread device and external (non-Thread) networks, primarily over TCP/HTTP using IP addresses and ports. However, in real-world applications, we rarely use raw IP addresses. Instead, we rely on hostnames — which are resolved to IP addresses using DNS (Domain Name System).
Public DNS resolution (like Google’s 8.8.8.8) handles global domain names, typically configured at the OS or browser level. But for private, local networks — like those used in IoT and Thread-based deployments — we need a local DNS setup to resolve custom hostnames (e.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 12</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-12/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One notable endorsement comes from Sumeet Gayathri Moghe — Principal Product Manager at Thoughtworks and author of The Async-First Playbook. It is a privilege collaborating with Sumeet, who challenges the notion of being &amp;ldquo;busy&amp;rdquo; and advocates for deep, meaningful work through an async-first mindset—syncing when truly necessary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>OpenThread Commissioner Implementation in Java</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-java/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-java/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how to build and use an Android app as an external commissioner to onboard Thread devices into a network. This article takes it a step further by demonstrating how to implement a Java-based external commissioner.
The thread commissioning process involves the following key steps:
 Discovering the Border Router Connecting to the Border Router Adding Joiner Rules Joining the Thread Network  In this guide, we will implement these steps in a Java application, providing a clear and structured approach to external commissioning in OpenThread.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Building and Using OpenThread Commissioner Mobile App</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-android/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-android/</guid>
            <description>In our previous article, we set up an external commissioner outside a Thread network using a command-line tool on a PC. However, OpenThread also provides a mobile app that can serve as an external commissioner.
This guide will walk you through building and using the OpenThread Commissioner mobile app to provision a device onto a Thread network.
Building the OpenThread Commissioner Mobile App OpenThread provides an Android app source, which requires Android Studio and Android NDK to build.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>External Commissioning in Thread Network</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-cli/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-cli/</guid>
            <description>In our previous article, we set up a commissioner within a Thread network by starting the commissioner from a thread node. However, a Thread network can also be provisioned using an external commissioner outside the thread network.
This article will guide you through the configuration of an external commissioner for a Thread network using a Commissioner CLI setup on a mac/linux pc.
Commissioner CLI The Commissioner CLI can be built on macOS or Linux using the following steps:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Implementing a TCP Client in nRF Connect</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-tcp-client-implementation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-tcp-client-implementation/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we implemented a Joiner that is programmatically provisioned by a Commissioner node to join a Thread network. Once an IoT device is part of the Thread network, the next step is to enable communication with other Thread nodes or external hosts. We previously discussed and tested UDP-based communication in Connecting Thread devices to Internet. In this article, we explore a similar approach with TCP OT CLI, and here we are implementing a custom TCP client that sends data to a TCP server programmatically.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>nRF Connect SDK Advanced Practices</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk-advanced/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk-advanced/</guid>
            <description>In our previous article, we provided a brief overview of the nRF Connect SDK and demonstrated how to build a simple application. This article explores advanced practices for working with the nRF Connect SDK, focusing on Zephyr OS internals, including timers, schedulers, bootloading, DFU, and FOTA concepts. It builds on our previous introduction to the nRF Connect SDK and provides insights into developing multi-threaded firmware, troubleshooting, and deploying firmware over the air (OTA).</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Implementing a Joiner in nRF Connect SDK</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-joiner-implementation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-joiner-implementation/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how a Commissioner node provisions a Joiner in a Thread network using OpenThread&amp;rsquo;s default firmware. However, in real-world applications, custom firmware logic is often required, along with programmatic control over the commissioning process. In this article, we will implement a Joiner using the nRF Connect SDK, following these four key steps.
Joiner in Action The Joiner process involves the following steps:
 Enable Thread – Ensure that the Thread network and IPv6 are enabled.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Simplifying Thread Network Provisioning with Joiner and Commissioner</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-network-provisioning/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-network-provisioning/</guid>
            <description>In previous articles, we explored the Thread protocol and connected Thread devices to the internet using a Border Router. We joined the Thread network by manually configuring each node with a full dataset containing network credentials such as the PAN ID, Network Key, Network Name, and more (refer to Step 6.1: Access Network Credentials). While this method works, it becomes impractical when provisioning hundreds of Thread devices in real-world scenarios.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 11</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-11/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-11/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
A notable endorsement came from Mayan Shay May-Raz — Principal Product, Amazon, who has great sense of user centric product designs, I have privilege working closely with her on Lenovo&amp;rsquo;s ThinkReality product like.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting Started with Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE)</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-ble/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-ble/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how to build IoT firmware applications using the nRF Connect SDK. We examined its project structure and learned how to build and flash firmware on the nRF52840 dongle. If you missed it, you can catch up here:
For more hands-on practices, use nRF52840 Development Kit (DK), that offers advanced developer features. You need to connect this board via a high-speed data cable like this one, to get it detected on your PC.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting Started with nRF Connect SDK</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk/</guid>
            <description>In the previous article, we explored setting up a Thread Network and enabling communication within and outside the network via a Border Router using OpenThread and the nRF Connect SDK. While we covered installing and configuring the SDK during the setup, we didn’t dive into the development process for nRF Connect SDK Apps. Let’s address that now!
What We’ll Cover This article introduces the nRF Connect SDK and walks through building applications with it.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 10</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-10/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
Want to highlight a notable endorsement from Mr. Dinkar Charak — esteemed Product Manager(#ProMa), Solutionist, and author of wonderful books on 📕Product Management and 📕Product LifeCycle. His 📕Engineering Excellence to Business Outcome (EEBO) is my personal favorite.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Connecting Thread Devices to Internet</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-devices-internet/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-devices-internet/</guid>
            <description>In previous articles, we explored the Thread Network and its protocol, focusing on the formation, functionality, and topology of the network. Thread is a lightweight, low-power communication protocol for IoT devices, operating on IPv6. We discussed its ability to automatically establish a mesh network and maintain connectivity through its robust topology.
We simulated a Thread network using Docker. Now in this article, we’ll create a Thread network between physical devices and connect it to the internet.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Testing the Ground: Reflections on 2024 and the Road Ahead for 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we bid farewell to 2024 and welcome 2025, it’s a perfect moment to reflect on the lessons this year has offered—both rewarding and challenging—and to prepare for the opportunities ahead.
This year marked a significant milestone as I celebrated 20 years in the industry. Along this journey, I shared my experiences by publishing a book, contributing over 30 articles and whitepapers on topics like the AI-powered metaverse, IoT, D&amp;amp;Iand product management.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 9</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-9/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-9/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is now available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
A special highlight is the endorsement from Mr. Ravindra Dastikop—an esteemed academician, entrepreneur, emerging technologies leader, and author of Metaverse Glossary: Your Gateway to the Future. Collaborating with him has been an incredible journey!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 8</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-8/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is now available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One of the standout testimonials is from Mr. Hemanth Kumar Satyanarayana, Founder, CEO at Imaginate XR, an award-winning innovator, MIT TR35 Young Innovator, IIT Madras alum, and TEDx speaker, who has dedicated over two decades to building the XR ecosystem.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the AI-powered Metaverse is Our Next Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>📖 My Takeaways from Our Next Reality by Alvin Wang Graylin and Louis Rosenberg
☞ Buy - Exploring the Metaverse ☞ Buy - Our Next Reality 
Our Next Reality topped my reading list for months, and travel always helps me catch up on books! After meeting Alvin at AWE Asia 2024, I was eager to dive in and finally complete it. Following recent trips to Singapore and now the US, here’s what I found worth sharing from the book.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Understanding the Thread Protocol and Network</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-the-thread-protocol-and-network/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-the-thread-protocol-and-network/</guid>
            <description>In previous articles, we explored MQTT in-depth, even setting up a web-based remote controller that simulated a physical button. We did this in a “Soft IoT” way, avoiding hardware intricacies. However, in IoT, networking between devices plays a crucial role. Not all IoT devices are connected to the Internet or can communicate via MQTT over the internet, as shown in our earlier examples. These devices need a low-latency, low-power network that can auto-discover and manage device communication seamlessly.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Soft IoT Continued: Bringing the Internet into IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot-continued/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot-continued/</guid>
            <description>Simplifying IoT learning doesn’t have to mean getting bogged down with hardware details. Instead, let’s dive into Soft IoT — where we focus on software-driven IoT exploration. In this article, we’ll learn how to read inputs from a button and turn it into a web based remote control for an LED, all while keeping things software-centric..
In the previous article, we introduced Soft IoT using a Grove Pi board, which simplifies IoT learning by hiding wiring and connections complexity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Myths and Realities of AI-Assisted Software Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/ai-assisted-software-development-myths/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/ai-assisted-software-development-myths/</guid>
            <description>AI is transforming the software development process, but there are many misconceptions about its capabilities. This article explores the common myths surrounding AI in software development and sheds light on its reality.
In recent times, Artificial Intelligence (AI) has gained momentum across various fields, especially with the introduction of Generative AI (GenAI). AI is now widely accessible, often sparking discussions about its potential, its misuse, and, unfortunately, several myths. As the hype around AI intensifies, so does the Fear of Missing Out (FOMO), leading many to adopt it without fully understanding its true value.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting Started with Soft IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot/</guid>
            <description>Learning IoT doesn’t have to be complex, especially when starting out. In this post, we’ll explore how to get started with IoT without diving deep into hardware complexities like wiring or understanding intricate sensor details.
In an earlier article, we set up a Raspberry Pi. My son initially saw it as just another, albeit slower, computer. There was no “IoT” in it yet, just a basic device. But IoT is about more than just the device itself; it’s about integrating sensors and actuators.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 7</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-7/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-7/</guid>
            <description>🚀 My Book, Exploring the Metaverse, is now available in stores worldwide, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from industry pioneers, and it aims to uncover the concept of the Metaverse, offering insights into its technological and business implications.
One of the incredible testimonials comes from Vanya Seth, Head of Technology at Thoughtworks. Vanya is a visionary tech leader, an active speaker in various tech communities, and a fellow participant in the XROS Fellowship program alongside me.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Booting Up the Internet of Things</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-rebooting/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-rebooting/</guid>
            <description>A few years ago, I bought a Raspberry Pi 3, but during a house move, I misplaced it. Fast forward to this Diwali cleaning, and to my surprise, I found it! My son’s curiosity was piqued, so we decided to set it up together. While my recent focus has been on XR technologies and we setup XRPractices, but this moment brought me back to IoT — sparking the idea to share my journey and experiences through a series of articles on getting started with IoT.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Featured in XTIC Chronicle, IIT Madras Newsletter</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xtic-newsletter-sep-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xtic-newsletter-sep-2024/</guid>
            <description>I am excited to share that my article explaining my book has been featured in the recent September edition of the XTIC Chronicle, a quarterly newsletter published by XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre) at IIT Madras. As India’s first research and product innovation center dedicated to Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics. XTIC provides a platform for cutting-edge insights from academia, industry, startups, and CAVE members.
XTIC Chronicle Overview The XTIC Chronicle is a valuable resource for all levels of readers interested in the latest advancements in XR technology.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Square orientation for stereoscopic rendering</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-2/</guid>
            <description>In our day-to-day work, we often create methods, processes, approaches, or features to address specific needs and challenges. Sometimes, these solutions turn into significant innovations, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t immediately recognize them as such. This is also true in our professional work setup, where we may invent without fully realizing it.
I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share that a new patent has been granted to Lenovo for their groundbreaking work in the ThinkReality XR product line, and I am honored to be a co-inventor on this work.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 6</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-6/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-6/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
The book explores the opportunities and concerns of the metaverse, outlining a path forward that calls for collective action from academia, industry, government, and individuals. I initiated this collective effort by gathering testimonials from a diverse group of experts.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 5</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
One of the most distinguished endorsements comes from Prof. M Manivannan, who leads the Experiential Technologies Innovation Center (XTIC) at IIT Madras.
Prof. Mani has spearheaded innovation at XTIC and have made India proud. His pioneering work in areas like iTad(interactive Touch Active Display) and integrating haptics into virtual reality solutions is noteworthy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 4</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Venkatesh Ponniah, Global Head of Emerging Technologies at Thoughtworks.
We call him Venki. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Venki on technology strategy and governance. He has great insights into emerging technology businesses, particularly in AI, SDV, Digital Twins, and XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR - the Enabler | XROS Fellowship Report</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, a transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtended Reality (XR) at its core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution is the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. My book, Exploring the Metaverse, available globally, outlines this kind of collaboration as a call to action for all of us.
FICCI XROS Fellowship Program Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce &amp;amp; Industry (FICCI), is the voice of india&amp;rsquo;s business and industry for policy change.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>20 reflections of 20 years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/20-of-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/20-of-20/</guid>
            <description>On July 5, 2004, I embarked on my professional journey. These past 20 years have been nothing short of adventurous and fulfilling.
 &amp;ldquo;Learning is a natural process, and it matures by sharing&amp;rdquo;
 I&amp;rsquo;ve had a wealth of learnings throughout these two decades, as I worked on over 50 projects spanning various domains and technologies. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of directly working with over a thousand individuals from diverse backgrounds across different organizations.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generative XR – Space aware AI bringing new era of immersion</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</guid>
            <description>Artificial Intelligence has made significant strides with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs) or Generative AI, which are trained to understand and respond to human language naturally. Tools like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google’s Gemini, and Microsoft’s Co-pilot have become the go-to resources for &amp;ldquo;Ask me anything&amp;rdquo; queries. These innovations have been touted as potential Google Search Killer, disrupting the way we search for information, communicate with machines, and receive machine responses.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Manage multiple 2D apps in a 3D layout</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/patent-granted-xr-1/</guid>
            <description>In our day-to-day work, we often create methods, processes, approaches, or features to address specific needs and challenges. Sometimes, these solutions turn into significant innovations, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t immediately recognize them as such. This is also true in our professional work setup, where we may invent without fully realizing it.
I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share that a new patent has been granted to Lenovo for their groundbreaking work in the ThinkReality XR product line, and I am honored to be a co-inventor on this work.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 3</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Kanchan Ray, Chief Technology Officer at Nagarro. We collaborated on building and conceptualizing various cutting-edge proof-of-concepts using emerging technologies. His support and advice were always invaluable.
🙏 I extend my heartfelt thanks to Kanchan for reviewing early versions of the book, sharing his valuable insights, and writing the following foreword:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Dr. Rebecca J Parsons, former Chief Technology Officer at Thoughtworks. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Rebecca at numerous technology strategy events, where her insights on responsible technology usage and our collective responsibility towards sustainability and technological adaptation have been invaluable.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse — A Synopsis</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo; featured on Industry4.0. It is available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online.
 The metaverse, a loosely defined term, has gone from a virtual game world to the next internet and sparks conversations on technology’s potential. Despite eye-rolling at terms like metaverse and eXtended Reality (XR), immersive technologies are silently becoming part of our daily life through social media, virtual collaboration, and digitized experiences. We seamlessly embrace digital tools, scanning codes, engaging in virtual trials, and altering reality through digital filters.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR in India — A Whitepaper by XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-in-india-a-whitepaper-by-xtic-iit-madras/</guid>
            <description>XTIC (Experiential Technology Innovation Centre), is India’s 1st Research &amp;amp; Product Innovation centre for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality and Haptics at IIT Madras. It has published a white-paper and skill gap analysis for Experiential Technologies in India.
Whitepaper - XR in India
It was great to be a contributor in this research. It is authored by 19 industry leader from various enterprises, institutes and government body. Excursions from this research also got published in The Hindu Businessline.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Vishal Shah, General Manager of XR and Metaverse at Lenovo. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of hearing Vishal speak at events like CES and AWE, where he shared invaluable insights on the metaverse and XR technology. Meeting him in person at Lenovo Tech World 2023 was a highlight, where we discussed this book, and he graciously agreed to contribute to its exploration of the metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Why collaboration is essential for building a successful XR future?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</guid>
            <description>The era of isolated development and secret-keeping innovation is fading. In the past, companies, individuals could thrive by becoming subject matter experts within their own walls. However, the rise of generative AI, fueled by shared knowledge, has changed the game. AI can now imagine and generate solutions faster than ever. The future belongs to those who embrace openness, collaboration, and shared learning.
 Expertise alone isn’t enough. Today, success hinges on building strong networks, fostering partnerships, and collaborating within communities.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead The concept of the Metaverse keeps evolving, leaving many confused. 📖 In my book, Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age I leverage my years of experience to:
 Unravel the Metaverse: Demystify the term and explore its true potential. Separate Myth from Reality: Address misconceptions surrounding the metaverse. Prepare for the Future: Equip you with insights to navigate the evolving digital landscape.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Future of Retail with Extended Reality (XR)</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-future-of-retail-with-extended-reality-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-future-of-retail-with-extended-reality-xr/</guid>
            <description>eXtended Reality (XR/AR/VR) technology is changing the reality of almost every industry today by enhancing user experiences. XR adoption in the retail industry is also quite natural, let&amp;rsquo;s understand how it is shaping up the future of retail.
In today’s retail landscape, technology is reshaping customer experiences, with XR leading the charge. Extended Reality (XR), including VR, AR, and MR, offers immersive experiences blending the physical and virtual worlds. From head-mounted displays to smart glasses and smartphones and beyond, XR is changing how we interact with retail environments.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Product Management Untangled | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/book-product-management-untangled/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/book-product-management-untangled/</guid>
            <description>Product management is a unique blend of art and science, distinct from roles such as project management, program management, business analysis, or business development. Some projects or products may have dedicated product managers, but I believe these skills are valuable for various roles, even if not explicitly labeled as a product manager. Even technologists can benefit from these skills to enhance the value of their work.
This is where Dinker Charak&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;lsquo;Product Management Untangled&amp;rsquo; becomes essential.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Making the XR content usable with AI!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</guid>
            <description>Generative AI is revolutionizing content generation across various mediums, disrupting traditional methods in text, images, art, movies, and music creation. XR (Extended Reality) is also undergoing this transformation. In a previous article, Raju Kandaswamy and I discussed how AI aids in generating content for XR, meeting the dynamic needs of XR and the metaverse.
We highlighted content management as a key challenge in XR and metaverse adoption. While generative AI methods offer some solutions, the significant hurdle of content optimization remains.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Coming Soon! Exploring the Metaverse</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</guid>
            <description>In the world of tech buzzwords, “metaverse” has been topic of discussion, largely understood and misunderstood. It comes, goes, and comes again in new shapes and forms, definitions and understanding. The term has been around for three decades and is poised to continue its evolution.
In the past, it has been defined to suit the narratives of organizations and individuals alike. Some see it as a game, others as a virtual world, while some view it as a tool for global connection and collaboration.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Being inclusive, being me</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/being-inclusive-being-me/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/being-inclusive-being-me/</guid>
            <description>🙋‍ ️As International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day is celebrated worldwide, efforts are underway to recognize women&amp;rsquo;s representation across diverse fields. In India, the spirit of &amp;lsquo;Nari Shakti&amp;rsquo; is alive as discussions focus on various schemes and initiatives. Increased enforcement is advocating for equal opportunities in underrepresented sectors. The promising shift towards inclusivity is shaping a future grounded in equity and equality.
👩‍💻 Thoughtworks is synonymous with diversity and inclusion, a leading brand in this space.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Immersive is the new interactive</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/thoughtworks-immersive-is-the-new-interactive/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/thoughtworks-immersive-is-the-new-interactive/</guid>
            <description>The way we interact with each other, and the world around us, is changing fast. And with consumer expectations continuing to grow, enterprises are racing to find new ways to deliver immersive experiences. I am republishing this article from Thoughtworks Insights here.
 As we discuss in the evolving interactions lens of our latest Looking Glass report, extended reality (XR) technologies offer new opportunities to engage and entertain. But what exactly is XR?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughtworks&#39; Looking Glass 2024 - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/thougthworks-looking-glass-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/thougthworks-looking-glass-2024/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks unveils its latest tech trends report, &amp;lsquo;Looking Glass&amp;rsquo;, a comprehensive analysis of emerging technologies designed to empower organizations and leaders in making informed decisions. The 2024 edition of report, covering over 100 trends, is segmented through five lenses, each offering insights, signals, and strategic recommendations for adoption, analysis, and anticipation.
Key takeaways: Here are my key takeaways:
 AI&amp;rsquo;s ubiquitous reach - AI is going in every facet of technology, from conversational interfaces to AI-assisted software development and software-defined vehicles.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Foundational shifts: Reflecting on 2023 and anticipating ahead</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2023-reflections-2024-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2023-reflections-2024-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we say goodbye to 2023 and welcome 2024, it&amp;rsquo;s a time to think about the good and tough parts of the year. Not everything goes the way we want, but we can learn from both the good and bad experiences. I see 2023 as a year of making things better, like fixing the base of a building. I&amp;rsquo;ve picked my top five observations on foundational changes from this year, and some might continue into 2024.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>thinkuldeep.com | 100 Articles and 50 Events</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/100-articles-50-events/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/100-articles-50-events/</guid>
            <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve reached a milestone: 100 articles and 50 events at thinkuldeep.com. This experience has improved my writing, boosted my confidence, and fueled my passion for self-expression. I&amp;rsquo;m thankful to readers, authors, speakers, and mentors who inspired me.
I want to share common obstacles I overcame, hoping to inspire others on their creative journeys.
1. I am not a great writer/speaker, I can&amp;rsquo;t express well Blocker#1 is doubting our abilities, it is natural when we haven&amp;rsquo;t explored our potential.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Effective communication: five key insights</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/effective-communication-5-insights/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/effective-communication-5-insights/</guid>
            <description>Communication is a puzzle - will others understand us as we hope? What&amp;rsquo;s the secret to effective communication? In this article, I share my top five lessons from books, personal exploration, and experts in the field.
I&amp;rsquo;m still learning this art, and it&amp;rsquo;s ever-evolving. I&amp;rsquo;ve read couple books and followed communication pros, they shed light on how crucial communication is, especially in our modern ways of working. But it&amp;rsquo;s clear even they&amp;rsquo;re always learning.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generative AI for 3D content in XR and beyond</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-ai-for-3d-content-in-xr-and-beyond/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-ai-for-3d-content-in-xr-and-beyond/</guid>
            <description>We touched upon Generative AI while talking about AI assisted content pipeline for XR at Thoughtworks XConf 2022. Generative AI is capable of producing outputs that closely resemble those created by humans. It is evolving in multiple forms, one of its kind is ChatGPT, a useful tool buried beneath the hype. It was touted as Google Killer, and posed a disruption to the way we search, we communicate with machines, and the way machines can respond.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My thoughtworkings from five thoughtful years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/five-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/five-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks is celebrating its 30th year in industry, and I have completed five years here, and to celebrate this, I have compiled thoughts from thoughtworkers, and published them as an ebook. I am grateful for the wealth of knowledge and experiences shared by my colleagues. These thoughts have resonated with me and shaped my journey within the organization and life.
I am excited to launch the ebook with this post. I believe this compilation of thoughts will not only serve as a personal reflection but also as a valuable resource for others on their own professional journeys.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Potential of XR Technology for Virtual Decoration</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-virtual-decoration/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-virtual-decoration/</guid>
            <description>In recent years, XR technology has revolutionized the way we decorate our physical environments. By utilizing AI and computer vision, XR can scan and track real-world surroundings, recognizing and remembering images and objects to enable the addition of virtual content. This technology can store and recall virtual decorations, making them visible every time someone enters the environment. While image matching is not a new concept, XR platforms like Vuforia have already implemented various mobile XR examples.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Habit Matters - The change is a side effect</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/habitmatters/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/habitmatters/</guid>
            <description>“Change is the only constant, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether we like it or not, it takes place”- shared and reflected in my change stories.
 Over the years, I have been following my theory of change Accept-Observe-Absorb. It helped me to traverse through the change year 2020, and understand the role of “Will” and how to cultivate it. I shared how just one change “working from my native home” brought so many other changes in lifestyle and behavior.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI-Assisted Content Generation Pipeline for XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/ai-generated-xr-content/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/ai-generated-xr-content/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I and Raju Kandaswamy talked at Thoughtworks XConf on how AI will play its role in content generation. We are already seeing ChatGPT, as the next revolution in textual content generation space. Let&amp;rsquo;s understand what is the need of such content generation revolution of XR space.
With games like Second Life and the impending mainstreaming of the Metaverse, more and more individuals are embracing a virtual reality that, in some ways, mirrors our own real world and, in other ways, lets us live in our imagination or apply them on the real word.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
            <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Corporate lessons from a Home Makeover</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</guid>
            <description>Recently I shared an article on my life lessons from my father’s work life, and mentioned that I dedicated a new home to my father’s work life, also promised that I will share some corporate lessons learned from making-over this new home. I can well relate my takeaways to the corporate experiences such as vendor selection, negotiation, solutioning, estimation, prioritization, agility and being a trusted partner and many more..
 As I keep saying “we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad”</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lessons of Life - Father’s Retirement</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</guid>
            <description>I started thinkuldeep.com keeping in mind that we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad. Our learning matures by sharing, we explore more of us by giving it away to others.
 Recently my father turned 60, and has retired from government services. 60 years full of life is a quite big experience, where around 38 years he spent in serving the same Govt of Rajasthan.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtending the Reality of Museum with XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending-reality-of-museum-wtih-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending-reality-of-museum-wtih-xr/</guid>
            <description>eXtended Reality (XR/AR/VR) technology is changing the reality of almost every industry today by enhancing user experiences. XR adoption in the museum industry is also quite natural, let&amp;rsquo;s understand how it is shaping up the Museums of Future.
Museum is a place that displays artifacts from history, culture, science, art and more. As per International Council of Museums (ICOM), there are around 55000 museums worldwide designed with different themes serving different types of artifacts.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse — a technological evolution</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days. In most of my sessions people ask what is the technology stack for Metaverse? what should I learn to stay relevant? etc.. I will try to cover it in this article. In my earlier article I tried to define the Metaverse, and my friend Vinodh Arumugam also attempted the same here. It is defined so loosely that every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suits their narrative.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-2/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the next Internet, that’s what we summarized it in the previous article. We discussed it’s characteristics and building blocks. In this article we will discuss some prominent use cases of the metaverse. We understand the metaverse as a trillion dollar opportunity in the next few years. It is growing at real fast speed, but without effective rules and regulations, without effective standards and practices, and we will also touch upon this concerning part of metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting into the Metaverse — Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/getting-into-the-metaverse-part-1/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most enquired word after Facebook renamed itself to “Meta” to align to their metaversal vision. However, the term “metaverse” was coined 3 decade ago by Neal Stephenson, in his 1992 science-fiction novel “Snow Crash,” which envisions a virtual reality-based successor to the internet. In the novel, people use digital avatars of themselves to explore the online world, often as a way of escaping a dystopian reality.
Today, Metaverse is being considered as a $800 billion path with double digit growth in next 5 years, where industry is trying to get most out of it by co-creating with communities, and focusing on it’s cost-effective universal acceptance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Try everything in your space - WebXR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/try-everything-in-your-space-webxr/</guid>
            <description>Today’s websites are designed first for mobile and then for other platforms, and it is getting important to bring mobile XR functionality into the websites. Google’s scene viewer is bringing WebXR for mass adoption. Theoretically any 3D model can be tried in your space, and you can easily built AR experience for your website.
eCommerce has already transformed into mCommerse, and now taking steps into xCommerse (XR Commerce). 3D Model viewer is very common requirement for across different domains, and it will be the basic requirement of developing for Metaverse as well as for any digital business in future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Managing enterprise complexity with XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/managing-enterprise-complexity-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/managing-enterprise-complexity-xr/</guid>
            <description>Modern enterprises must manage multiple layers of complexity across thousands of assets, workflows, and processes — and there’s near-zero tolerance for issues that interrupt operations, damage profitability, or put workers’ safety at risk.
These layers of enterprise complexity create significant challenges in four key areas:
 Design and development are often slow and expensive An inability to demo and customize complex products can make them difficult to sell Users need continuously updated training to operate products effectively and safely A shortage of on-the-spot expertise endangers employee safety and increases downtime risk and cost  However, many enterprises are beginning to use extended reality (XR) technologies to overcome these challenges.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Leadership - A result of conscious and continuous effort!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/leadership-development-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/leadership-development-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>Sep 2020, a year ago, I was excited for getting nominated for an year long Global Leadership Development Program at Thoughtworks. At the same time was little confused on what we are going to do in this program for that long. I must say it was so well executed, despite the challenges of Covid#19, where we all(participants, speakers, coaches and other enablers) are globally distributed working from their home. Expectations were set, virtual meetings were set with options to attend at per individual comfort.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My impactful change stories</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/my-impactful-change-stories/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/my-impactful-change-stories/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I have been invited to share my 3 years Thoughtworks Journey, at “Impact Series” by Social Change Group TW, India.
 &amp;ldquo;Striving for positive social change is at the heart of our purpose, culture and work&amp;rdquo; — /thoughtworks
 I believe an impactful change is the change that changes you, and any social change start from within, our own journey. I shared my change journey, and received number of comments, and feedbacks.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The BlackBox!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/story-blackbox/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/story-blackbox/</guid>
            <description>A good consultant, have to be a good story-teller. I feel you become a storyteller when you start making your own stories, so that you can explain the point of view in better way. I started writing stories while practicing storytelling and found that story writing is so powerful and it helps bring our imagination into reality. Here I am sharing a story of the BlackBox, a character that inspire me the most, and will inspire you too.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Enterprise XR to Ethical XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/enterprise-to-ethical-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/enterprise-to-ethical-xr/</guid>
            <description>eXtended Reality or XR is an umbrella term for scenarios where AR, VR, and MR devices interact with peripheral devices such as ambient sensors, actuators, 3D printers and internet enabled smart-devices such as home appliances, industrial connected machines, connected vehicles and more. Find here more details
At Thoughtworks, we have been talking about Rise of XR for enterprises, and evolving human interactions thru our lens of looking glasses.
 Evolving interactions - Consumers aren’t just demanding availability and accessibility — they expect interactions to be seamless, and richer.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Navigating the new normal with augmented reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/navigating-new-normal-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/navigating-new-normal-xr/</guid>
            <description>This article is originally published at Thoughtworks Insights, co-authored with Aileen Pistorius, Julie Woods-Moss and Anna Bäckström.
Time was when virtual and augmented reality was regarded as simply gaming technology — the preserve of fun, consumer applications with little serious consideration for the enterprise. But that’s in the past, in the post-COVID world, remote working will be ubiquitous — forcing enterprise leaders to find innovative ways to improve collaboration. This, it transpires, is the sweet spot for what’s termed enterprise XR (extended reality) — a group of related technologies that enable us to blend the physical and digital worlds.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Making pandemic-proof workplaces a reality with XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/making-pandemic-proof-workplaces-a-reality-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/making-pandemic-proof-workplaces-a-reality-xr/</guid>
            <description>The IMF called the COVID-19 crisis ‘unlike any other,’ where the global growth contraction for 2020 was estimated at -3.5 percent. Image source : Using Lenovo ThinkReality A6 Glass at Workplace
Here is a quick overview of the biggest challenges that CXOs (and their businesses) have faced over the recent past, to better illustrate how the pandemic is affecting businesses:
 Businesses are grappling with slowing global supply chains Sales and production growth is further impacted with a subsequent dive in opportunities for partnerships and growth The flattened or negative growth market result in less manpower and resources to work with, further affecting productivity  ​The five biggest challenges that CXOs are facing today</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Coaching is not what you think!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/coaching-workshop-key-takaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/coaching-workshop-key-takaways/</guid>
            <description>When the word “Coaching” comes into my mind, one name always pops up, the cricket legend Sachin Tendulkar and his coach Mr. Ramakant Achrekar who gave him cricket. This example also helps us break the myths that coaching is needed when there are performance issues or people who are under-performing need the most.
Sachin Tendulkar with his coach — Source
If Sachin Tendulkar needs a coach then we all need a coach in our life to get going.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Training autonomous vehicles with XR simulation</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/training-autonomous-vehicles-in-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/training-autonomous-vehicles-in-xr/</guid>
            <description>Self driving cars are a good example of what artificial intelligence can accomplish today. Such tech-centered advances are built on the back of highly trained Machine Learning (ML) algorithms.
These algorithms require exhaustive data that help the AI effectively model all possible scenarios. Accessing and pooling all that data needs complex and very expensive real-world hardware setups, aside from the extensive time it takes to gather the necessary training-data in the cloud (to train ML).</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Stories of Will Cultivation from 2020</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/will-cultivation-2020/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/will-cultivation-2020/</guid>
            <description>The year 2020 was the year of change, it may be painful for some, but at the same time, it has taught us lessons in life. I have written about it earlier that we have to accept it, and it will be remembered and will have an impact on our whole life and after our life, no matter what we do. So it is important that we live the present fully.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Best Practices for Building Spatial Solutions</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-best-practices/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-best-practices/</guid>
            <description>Covid19 is forcing us into a ‘new normal’, A new normal that makes most of us work from home, and that leads to spending long hours on Zoom, or other video conferencing platforms. Meetings, inceptions, discovery workshops, conferences, and webinars are happening in the same monotonous ways. We are stuck with a screen in almost the same pose and posture. Some might use their mobile phone or tablet but that limits us to a small screen.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtended Reality - the new norm?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_new_norm/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_new_norm/</guid>
            <description>This article is originally published at TechTag.de, you may find the German version here too.
The interaction between humans and technology is evolving radically. We need to develop our thinking and skills beyond the keyboard and screen. But what does this new technological reality look like? Here it is worth taking a closer look at the different forms of extended reality and how they can change our everyday lives.
The way we interact with technology today isn&amp;rsquo;t too far from what was predicted by futuristic sci-fi pop culture.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR enabled me to renovate my home!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</guid>
            <description>Covid19 is still unmeasurable, and we are more or less getting adjusted to this new normal. We are eagerly waiting to say goodbye to this year 2020 and welcome the coming year of hope, 2021. Read more here to know why I call this year 2020, as the year of change.
In April this year, I explained XR development from home, and that was still near shore to office, I was less than an hour away from the office.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Learning Equation</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-learning-equation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-learning-equation/</guid>
            <description>Today, The world is celebrating teacher’s day. I wish Happy Teacher&amp;rsquo;s day to all of us! We all are teachers and learners as every one of us has something to learn from others and something to teach others. I am thinking of an equation of learning that defines my way of learning and hope it would be helpful for you too.  The learning equation — Learning is proportional to Sharing; Learning ∝ Sharing</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two Thoughtful Years!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/two-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/two-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>It’s now two years since I accepted a challenging change to leave the previous organization after 13 long years, and join ThoughtWorks. Any change requires sacrifices and dedication before it becomes a positive change, but the journey becomes easy when we believe in the change and accept it. A change introduces us to a new environment and enables new thoughts, and new energy. The two years journey at ThoughtWorks is no different.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The future of shopping</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/future-of-shoping/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/future-of-shoping/</guid>
            <description>eXtended Reality (XR) that includes AR and VR technologies have been silently disrupting the gaming industry for more than a decade. In the recent past, the tech has gained some traction in the education and training space.
Today, however, COVID-19 with its mandates of social distancing and less to no physical interactions has accelerated adoption for XR. The tech is virtual, contactless, and delivers outstanding brand experiences - perfect for the new normal that multiple industries like retail will benefit from.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>2020 — The year of Change</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2020-year-of-change/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2020-year-of-change/</guid>
            <description>Change is the only constant, early we accept, early we get ready for the future. 2020 is a year of change, accept it, and change our lifestyle and get ready for the future.
I have been writing about the change in the past, right from accepting the change to change for good to have a purposeful and balanced life and uncover human potential in this Covid19 time.
Today, June 20, is my younger son Lovyansh’s 3rd Birthday, and June month is really time to rejuvenate and celebrate for the kids when they are free from school.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Growing List of XR Devices</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-growing-list-of-xr-devices/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-growing-list-of-xr-devices/</guid>
            <description>In my earlier article, I have explained the fundamentals of XR and the type of XR, and the popular devices in those XR types. ARVR is not the only about Head-Mounted Display(HMD) devices. There is an ever-growing list of Google ARCore supported smartphones/tablets and ARKit is being supported in recent Apple phones. But still, when when it comes to AR and VR devices, the first thing that comes in mind is head-mounted display devices (HMD), however, the newer mobile phones/tablets are now coming with AR/VR support with a minimal set of tools attached.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A new form of WebXR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/a-new-form-of-webxr/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/a-new-form-of-webxr/</guid>
            <description>Accessing native XR features from the device using a web page is another form of WebXR.
In this article, I want to share an experiment where I tried to control the android device’s native features such as controlling volume and camera torch from a web page. This use case can be really useful in the XR world, where I can control the feature access in the device from cloud services, even the whole look and feel for showing the device controls can be managed from a hosted web page.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Uncovering the human potential</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</guid>
            <description>Covid19 has challenged the way work, I have penned down my earlier article to cover my workday and our shift toward new ways of working. Covid19 has impacted not just the way we work, but also our lives. All-day, we keep hearing how it is hitting hard on humanity and it has brought so much negativity around us.
Enough of negativity, let’s uncover human potential to cop with it. In this article, I will cover how the ways of our regular life are shifting, and uncovering new human potentials to try out new things and performing our chores own our own.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Run a 2D App in XR Container</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/run-a-2d-app-in-xr-container/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/run-a-2d-app-in-xr-container/</guid>
            <description>There are a number of Enterprise XR use cases where we have a need to open the existing 2D apps in the XR devices in a wrapper app, and this article covers a concept, have a look!
After trying the OS level customization on an XR device, you may like to run your XR apps as a system app. Here is a simple article by Raju K
 Android System Apps development - Android Emulator Setup and guidelines to develop system applications</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>OS Customization for XR Device</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/os-customization-for-xr-devices/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/os-customization-for-xr-devices/</guid>
            <description>The Operating System of XR (AR VR) devices is mostly customized to the hardware of the device, and not just that the OS level customizations are needed to meet the enterprise needs such as integration with Enterprise MDM (Mobile Device Management) solutions (such as Intune, MobileIron and Airwatch), 3D lock screen, idle-timeout, custom home screen, custom settings, security, as so on.
Most organizations currently using traditional hardware and software assets such as mobile devices, laptops, and desktops, and the processes and policies for managing these devices are quite stable and straightforward by now.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
            <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>User Account Management In XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/user-account-management-in-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/user-account-management-in-xr/</guid>
            <description>In the previous article, we described the importance of interoperability in while building Enterprise XR solutions, In the article, we will discuss how to manage user accounts in the XR device, and implement single sign-on across the XR apps. We will use Android’s AccountManger approach to login into active directory and integrated it into Unity. Please read my earlier article on setting up the app in active directory, log in using android webview, considering a web-based company login form should appear for login, and no custom login form is allowed to capture the credentials.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>WebXR - the new Web</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/webxr-the-new-web/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/webxr-the-new-web/</guid>
            <description>The web has grown from a read-only web (Web 1.0) to interactive web (Web 2.0) and then moved into the semantic web which is more connected and more immersive. 3D content on the web is there for quite some time, the most web-browsers support rendering 3D content natively. The rise for XR technologies and advancements in devices and the internet is leading the demand for Web-based XR. It will be a norm for web-based development.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-2/</guid>
            <description>In Part I of the article, we summarized our observations of eXtended reality’s foundational blocks - AR, VR and MR. We also discussed the popular and most relevant tools and implementations of the new technology. In Part II of the article, we will be looking at a few accessible and novel implementations of the tech.
At ThoughtWorks, we have delivered both XR solutions and components of XR SDK (Software Development Kit) on the back of which XR solutions are built.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</guid>
            <description>The way we interact with technology today is not too far from what was predicted by futuristic, sci-fi pop culture. We are living in a world where sophisticated touch and gesture based interactions are collaborating with state of the art wearables, sensors, Augmented Reality (AR), Virtual Reality (VR) and Mixed Reality (MR). And, this is eXtending user experiences to be extremely immersive.
Add to this, Gartner’s expectation that 5G and AR/VR implementation will transform not only customer engagement but brands’ entire product management cycles as well.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR development from home</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-development-from-home/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-development-from-home/</guid>
            <description>Covid19 has challenged the way we eat, the way we commute, the way we socialize, and the way we work. In short, it impacted the way we live. More than a million people got infected and the number is growing exponentially, it has impacted the whole world. We need to find new ways of life and change our focus and priorities to save nature and humanity. Technology can play a great role in coping with it.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Enterprise XR - Interoperability</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/enterprise-xr-interoperability/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/enterprise-xr-interoperability/</guid>
            <description>In the previous article, we discussed implementing multi-factor authentication for an andorid application, and in the article we will cover another enterprise aspect, Interoperability.
Interoperability is key aspect when we build enterprise solutions using XR technologies. The enterprises have digital assets in form of mobile apps, libraries, system APIs, and they can’t just throw away these existing investments, in fact, the XR apps must be implemented in such a way that it is interoperable with them seamlessly.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Enterprise XR - Multi-Factor Authentication</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/enterprise-xr-multi-factor-authentication/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/enterprise-xr-multi-factor-authentication/</guid>
            <description>XR use cases are growing with advancements in the devices, internet and development technologies. There is an ever-growing demand to build enterprise use cases using ARVR technology. Most enterprise use cases eventually require integration with an enterprise ecosystem such as IAM (Identity and Access Management), ERP, CRM, and single sign-on with other systems.
Most organizations protect digital assets with a single sign-on using Multiple Factor Authentication (MFA). The MFA is generally a web-browser based authentication where the browser redirects to tenant’s authentication page where the user provides their credentials and then the user confirms another factor (PIN, OTP, SMS or mobile notifications), once it succeeds, it gets redirected back to the protected resource.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Success Mantra</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/success_mantra_amazon/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/success_mantra_amazon/</guid>
            <description>Everyone in India is talking about Jeff Bezos, the richest of the world, who was on India&amp;rsquo;s visit recently. People are talking about the investments he is making in India, talking about his prediction about India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;21st Century is going to be the Indian century&amp;rdquo;, and discussing the impact on small businesses. We have seen disruptions lead by Amazon in multiple sectors, now people have a fear that whatever Amazon touch, it becomes Amazon&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Augmenting the Travel Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/augmenting_the_travel_reality/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/augmenting_the_travel_reality/</guid>
            <description>Travel and transportation have faced and continue facing disruptions. Many of the traditional ways are no more in the choice. Earlier our parents used to warn us for taking rides with strangers, but now Uber/Ola/Lyft/Didi, etc are the preferred ways. Owning a car may be an absurd idea now. We are now dreaming of Autonomous vehicles, Flying Cars, Hyperloop, and Space travel in the near future. Do read, how the user interactions have been evolved with time in my earlier post.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Static Code Analysis for Unity3D — Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/static_code_analysis_unity_2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/static_code_analysis_unity_2/</guid>
            <description>This article is in continuation of Static Code Analysis for Unity3D — Part 1 where we talked about setting up a local sonar server, sonar scanner and running the analysis for a Unity3D project.
It this article, we will discuss setting up the Static Code Analysis with SonarCube in IDE — Rider. We are using Rider as the “External Script Editor” in Unity. Configure Rider here in Unity&amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; External Tools &amp;gt; External Script Editor.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Static Code Analysis for Unity3D — Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/static_code_analysis_unity_1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/static_code_analysis_unity_1/</guid>
            <description>Static code analysis is a standard practice in software development. There are code scanner tools, which scans the code to find vulnerabilities. There are some nice tools for visualizing and managing code quality. One of the most used tool is SonarQube, supports 25+ languages and flexible configurations of the rules.
There are not enough resources talking about static code analysis for Unity3D. This post covers steps to configure SonarQube and use it for scanning Unity projects.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Inception Workshop | Key Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</guid>
            <description>Inception exercise is very common in software development, where we gather the business requirements and define the delivery plan for the MVP(Minimum Viable Product) on a shared understanding. There are a set of tools and practices available to define the MVP requirements and its delivery plan. Famous tools are Lean Value Tree, Business Model Canvas, Plane Map, Elevator Pitch, Futurespective, Empathy Maps, Value Proposition Canvas, User Journey Map, Gamestorming, Process Diagram, MoSCoW, Communication Plan, Project Plan etc.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Evolution of Technology and User Interactions</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</guid>
            <description>Technology defines our interactions with the ambiance, and the way we want to interact with the ambiance further defines the technology. The evolution of technology and user interactions tightly depends on each other.
 &amp;ldquo;Walls have ears!&amp;rdquo;, is very much true today, and not just that, now the walls can see you, feel your presence and talk to you.
 In this post, we will discuss how the user interactions evolved with time and what is next!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Can IT modernization lead to revenue loss?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/can_it_modernization_lead_to_revenue_loss/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/can_it_modernization_lead_to_revenue_loss/</guid>
            <description>IT Modernization is one of the key factors of today&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation. Most of the enterprises trying to define digital transformation strategy. IT organizations trying to redesign the organizations to meet the changing business need, and uplift the technology and people. Non-IT organizations are also trying to setup digital department to take care of companies digital assets and modernize them. However, IT modernization does not always result in a profit, it may lead to revenue loss if it does not fit to the organization design.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Embibe purpose and balance in life</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</guid>
            <description>I just finished a book &amp;ldquo;Life&amp;rsquo;s Amazing Secrets&amp;rdquo; by Gaur Gopal Das. It covers the topic of balance and purpose in life nicely. Few of the concepts from the book I can very well relate to my current organization&amp;rsquo;s focus on cultivation and collaboration culture.
It&amp;rsquo;s now more than 6 months of my journey with Thoughtworks, an organization which started as a social experiment more than 25 years ago, and believes in balancing 3 pillars in life ; sustainability, excellence and purpose.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lessons Learned From Blockchain-Based Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</guid>
            <description>Blockchain or DLT (Distributed Ledger Technology) is getting good traction in the IT world these days. Earlier, this technology was being mostly explored by banks and other finance-related institutions, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum. Now, it is getting explored for other use cases for building distributed applications. Blockchain technology comes with a decentralized and immutable data structure that maintains a connected block of information. Each block is connected using a hash of the previous block, and every new block on the chain is validated (mined) before adding and replicating it.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Software Development as a Design Process</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/software-development-as-design-process/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/software-development-as-design-process/</guid>
            <description>The book &amp;ldquo;Agile IT Organization Design - For digital transformation and continuous delivery&amp;rdquo; by Sriram Narayan explains software development as a design process. Following statement from the book means a lot.
 &amp;ldquo;Software development is a design process, and the production environment is the factory where product takes place. IT OPS work to keep the factory running..&amp;rdquo;
 It questions the way we traditionally think of operation support, maintenance, production bugs, rework, their costs and budgets and the focus in software development life.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Request Tracing Using Nginx and Spring Boot</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/request-tracing/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/request-tracing/</guid>
            <description>Most web applications are hosted behind a load balancer or web-server such as Nginx/HTTPD, which intercepts all the requests and directs dynamic content requests to the application server, such as Tomcat. Correlating requests traversing from the front-end server to the backend servers are general requirements. In this post, we will discuss tracing the request in the simplest way in an Nginx and Spring Boot-based application without using an external heavyweight library like Slueth.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Boost your organisation agility by test-first-pair development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/test-first-pair-development/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/test-first-pair-development/</guid>
            <description>Agile software development methodology is the key selling point for most of the IT organisations, however many of the organisations have gone by the literal meaning of the word &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo;. They follow agile practices without really being agile. If we go by Manifesto for Agile Software Development, it focus more on human factor (people, interaction, collaboration) which produces working software as per the need of time, than on processes, tools and strict planning.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Quick Catch up Before Java 11</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/before_java11/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/before_java11/</guid>
            <description>Java 11&amp;rsquo;s release candidate is already here, and the industry is still roaming around Java 8. Every six months, we will see a new release. It is good that Java is evolving at a fast speed to catch up the challengers, but at the same time, it is also scary to catch its speed, even the Java ecosystem (build tools, IDE, etc.) is not catching up that fast. It feels like we are losing track.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Accept the change!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/accept_the_change/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/accept_the_change/</guid>
            <description>The change is inevitable and constant; it is a part of our life. Sooner or later, we have to accept the change. 13 years ago, I joined a small IT organisation of around 100 people, as a developer. I have grown with the organisation; a 40 times growth journey. I really thank the organisation for giving me opportunity, and transforming me, what I am today. Now, the time has come to accept a change, and start a new journey.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>5 Hard Lessons From Microservices Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</guid>
            <description>Microservices-based development is happening all around the industry; more than 70% are trying development of microservice-based software. Microservices simplify integration of the businesses, processes, technology, and people by breaking down the big-bang monolith problem to a smaller set that can be handled independently. However, it also comes with the problem of managing relations between these smaller sets. We used to manage fewer independent units, so there was less operation and planning effort.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Apache Spark on Windows</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/apache_spark_on_windows/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/apache_spark_on_windows/</guid>
            <description>This article is for the Java developer who wants to learn Apache Spark but don&amp;rsquo;t know much of Linux, Python, Scala, R, and Hadoop. Around 50% of developers are using Microsoft Windows environment for development, and they don&amp;rsquo;t need to change their development environment to learn Spark. This is the first article of a series, &amp;ldquo;Apache Spark on Windows&amp;rdquo;, which covers a step-by-step guide to start the Apache Spark application on Windows environment with challenges faced and thier resolutions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IOT 101: A primer on Internet of Things</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_simplified/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_simplified/</guid>
            <description>IOT 101 A Primer on Internet of Things  from Kuldeep Singh  The IoT can be described as “Connecting the Things to internet”.
A comprehensive IoT ecosystem consists of many different parts such as electronic circuitry, sensing and acting capability, embedded systems, edge computing, network protocols, communication networks, cloud computing, big data management and analytics, business rules etcetera. This maze of varied parts can be better classified into 4 broad categories:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Smart Glasses</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-google-glass/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-google-glass/</guid>
            <description>This article describes the fundamentals of light-weight smart glasses such as Google Glass and Vuzix M100 It also explain the development practices with pros and cons of its usage, limitation and future of these glasses in our lives.
Google Glass Enterprise Edition Google Glass enterprise edition is a plain Android based smart glass that you can wear and performs operations just like a smartphone and with the use of a small screen located in the front of your right eye can perform a decent range of tasks.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Another IoT Disruption: A Need of Multi-Skilled Devs</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</guid>
            <description>Technological evolution causes disruption. It replaces traditional, less optimal, complex, lengthy, and costly technology, people, and processes with economical, innovative, optimal, and simpler alternatives. We have seen disruption by mobile phones, and up next is disruption from IoT, wearables, AR-VR, machine Learning, AI, and other innovations. Software development methodology, tools, and people will also face disruption. I expect that the traditional developer will be replaced by the multi-skilled or full-stack developers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IoT based insect monitoring concept</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-insect-monitoring/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-insect-monitoring/</guid>
            <description>Insects are the most diverse species of animals found on earth. While every species is required to maintain the balance of nature, excessive accumulation of any one type can have devastating effects on humans and environment.
Insect management relies on the early detection and accuracy of insect population monitoring techniquessensors-12-15801. Integrated data gathering about insect population together with the ecological factors like temperature, humidity, light etc., makes it possible to execute appropriate pest control at the right time in the right place.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>5 Steps of the IoT race</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</guid>
            <description>The ‘Internet of Things’ (IoT) presents tremendous opportunity in all the industry verticals and business domains. Specifically, the ‘Industrial Internet of Things’(IIoT) promises to increase the value proposition by making self-optimizing business processes. As discussed in the post “The Driving Forces Behind IoT”, there are several challenges to be addressed to realize the full IoT potentials, but following steps will help organization to systemically make their products participate in the IoT journey and stay in the IoT race.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Industrial IoT (IIOT) Reference Architecture</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iiot-reference-architecture/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iiot-reference-architecture/</guid>
            <description>The industry has been going through an evolution. Industry 4.0 is the fourth industrial revolution where the key will be on digital transformation. Industry 4.0 creates what has been called a &amp;ldquo;smart factory&amp;rdquo;. Within the modular structured smart factories, cyber-physical systems monitor physical processes, create a virtual copy of the physical world and make decentralized decisions. Over the Internet of Things, cyber-physical systems communicate and cooperate with each other and with humans in real time, and via the Internet of Services, both internal and cross-organizational services are offered and used by participants of the value chain.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Smart bottle IOT concept</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-bottle-concept/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-bottle-concept/</guid>
            <description>The rapid growth of Internet of Things (IoT) and miniature wearable biosensors have generated new opportunities for personalized eHealth and mHealth services. We present a case study of an intelligent cap that can measure the amount of water in the bottle, monitor activity of opening or closing of bottle cap. This paper presents a Proof of Concept implementation for such a connected smart bottle that sends measurements to the IoT Platform.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Building a smart meeting room concept</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</guid>
            <description>On a usual day at office, if an employee wishes to book a meeting room, he or she first has to open their outlook account, check the calendar for its availability and then send a booking invitation. If they directly go to a meeting room, they have no way of knowing whether it is booked or not without checking the calendar.
Smart Meeting Room is a step forward in automating the availability and booking procedure of a meeting room.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring AndroidThings IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-android-things/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-android-things/</guid>
            <description>Android Things, an android based embedded operating system, is the new “it” thing in the Internet of Things(IOT) space. Developed by Google under the codename “Brillo, a.k.a. Project Brillo”, it takes the usual Android development stack—Android Studio, the official SDK, and Google Play Services—and applies it to the IOT.
Google formally took the veils off of Brillo at its I/O 2015 conference. It is aimed to be used with low-power and memory constrained IOT devices, allowing the developers to build a smart device using Android APIs and Google Services.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Writing maintainable code is like house cleaning</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/clean-code/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/clean-code/</guid>
            <description>Your house will remain clean for longer duration if you follow certain rules strictly such as put things at right place after use, clear any mesh just after doing it, repair/upgrade things on time, daily dusting, vacuum cleaning etc. We may avoid a massive cleanup if we apply a series of small efforts daily.
 Let for the same while writing the code –  Your code will remain maintainable for longer duration if you follow certain rules strictly such as follow the coding standards and guidelines, clean the code just after it, fix/refactor on time, periodic design review and refactoring.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Driving Forces Behind IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-driving-forces-iot/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-driving-forces-iot/</guid>
            <description>Everybody in the software industry is talking about IoT in terms of billions of devices, their growth in coming years, changing business models, and adaptation of the IoT in the market. Connecting the things has become so prevalent nowadays, that every software company wants to expand in IoT by building IoT-centric products and services.
There are many industrial applications which connect to sensors and actuators, and can be controlled remotely. They have been around for a long time.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Framework for choosing an IoT Platform</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/choosing_iot_platform/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/choosing_iot_platform/</guid>
            <description>As we understand “IoT Platform” is an essential building block of IoT Ecosystem . A platform essentially decouples the business application from low level details of the technology stack and required services. Thus, it makes more sense to go for an off-the-shelf platform that provide all the relevant features and required flexibility, instead of developing the whole IoT stack from scratch. Selection of an IoT Platform is a key to develop a scalable and robust IoT Solution.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>SIGFOX - An Introduction</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/sigfox-an-introduction/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/sigfox-an-introduction/</guid>
            <description>SIGFOX is providing a communication solution dedicated to the Internet of Things
Dedicated to the IOT means:
 Simplicity: No configuration, no pairing, no signaling Autonomy: Very low energy consumption, allowing years of autonomy on battery without maintenance Small messages: No large assets or multimedia, only small messages  It is a LPWA (Low-Power Wide-Area) network, currently operating in 20 countries in Europe, Americas and Asia/Pacific. Communications over the SIGFOX network are bi-directional: uplink from device &amp;amp; downlink to the device.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Choose ORM carefully!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/choose-orm-carefully/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/choose-orm-carefully/</guid>
            <description>We have recently migrated source code from Hibernate ORM to JDBC (Spring JDBC template) based implementation. Performance has been improved 10 times.
User case (Oracle 11g, JBoss 6, JDK 6, Hibernate, Spring 3) : A tree structure in database is getting populated from a deep file system (directory structure) having around 75000 nodes. Each node (directory) contains text files, which get parsed based on business rules and then populate the database ( BRANCHs representing a node, tables referring to branch, tree_nodes).</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Object Oriented JavaScript</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/oojs/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/oojs/</guid>
            <description>JavaScript has been regarded as a functional programing language by most of the developers. This book is targeted for all the JavaScript developers to shift their thinking from the functional to the object oriented programing language.
The course requires basic knowledge of JavaScript syntax. If you already know some JavaScript, you will find a lot of eye-openers as you go along and learn what more the JavaScript can do for you.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Software Effectiveness vs Software Efficiency</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/software-effectiveness-vs-efficiency/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/software-effectiveness-vs-efficiency/</guid>
            <description>I define software effectiveness as, doing the objective effectively, I mean correctly. Efficiency can be defined as, using the resources optimally where resources could be memory, CPU, time, files, connections, databases etc.
From my experience, in most (should I call many) of the software projects, efficiency/performance is not much accentuated during the system design and in earlier phases(requirement and estimation) as compared to the emphasis given late in the game, coding and testing and mostly in maintenance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>HashMap Performance Improvement in Java 8</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-hashmap-performance-improvement/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-hashmap-performance-improvement/</guid>
            <description>Hash collision degrades the performance of HashMap significantly. Java 8 has introduced a new strategy to deal with hash collisions, thus improving the performance of HashMaps. Considering this improvement in Java 8 for hash collisions, existing applications can expect performance improvements in case they are using HashMaps having large number of elements by simply upgrading to Java 8.
Earlier, when multiple keys ends up in the same bucket, then values along with their keys are placed in a linked list.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introduction to Java Lambda Expression</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-lambda-expression/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-lambda-expression/</guid>
            <description>After Java 8, developers can apply functional programming constructs in a pure Object-Oriented programming language through lambda expressions. Using lambda expression sequential and parallel execution can be achieved by passing behavior into methods. In Java world lambdas can be thought of as an anonymous method with a more compact syntax. Here compact means it is not mandatory to specify access modifiers, return type and parameter types while defining the expression.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introduction to Java Stream API</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-stream-api/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-stream-api/</guid>
            <description>Prior to JDK 8, collections can only be managed through iterators with the use of for, foreach or while loops. It means that we instruct a computer to execute the algorithm steps.
int sum(List&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt; list) {  Iterator&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt; intIterator = list.iterator();  int sum = 0;  while (intIterator.hasNext()) {  int number = intIterator.next();  if (number &amp;gt; 5) {  sum += number;  }  }  return sum; } The above approach has the following tailbacks:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IOT Cloud Platforms -  A Comparative Study</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_cloud_platform_comparision/</guid>
            <description>The vision of IoT can be seen from two perspectives— ‘Internet’ centric and ‘Thing’ centric. The Internet centric architecture will involve internet services being the main focus while data is contributed by the objects. In the object centric architecture, the smart objects take the center stage.
In order to realize the full potential of cloud computing as well as ubiquitous sensing, a combined framework with a cloud at the center seems to be most viable.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>HTTP Router with Apache Camel </title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/apache-camel-http-route/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/apache-camel-http-route/</guid>
            <description>This article explains the http integration using Apache Camel. Create a configurable router to any http URL having place holders.
 Prerequisite  Windows7, Eclipse Juno Java 1.7    Creating HTTP Router Please follow below steps to generate POC for HTTP routing using apache camel.
Create Sample Camel Example   Create eclipse project using archetype “camel-archetype-spring”
mvn archetype:generate DarchetypeGroupId=com.tk.poc.camel -DarchetypeArtifactId=camel-archetype-spring -DarchetypeVersion=2.11.0 -DarchetypeRepository=https://repository.apache.org/content/groups/snapshots-group   Create following Java file</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Apache Camel SSH Component</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/apache-camel-ssh-component/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/apache-camel-ssh-component/</guid>
            <description>This article is about troubleshooting issues we have faced while using apache camel’s SSH routes. It also covers step wise guide to setup apache camel routes.
Prerequisites  Windows7 Eclipse Juno Java 1.7  Problem Statement We were getting following issues in the logs when connecting to one of the SSH server using Apache Camel-SSH. This was happening in one of the instance in production environment.
Here are few logs :</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Groovy - Getting Started</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/groovy-getting-started/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/groovy-getting-started/</guid>
            <description>This article help you start with Groovy, with step by step guide and series of examples. It starts with an overview and then covers in detail examples.
Groovy Overview Groovy is an Object Oriented Scripting Language which provides Dynamic, Easy-to-use and Integration capabilities to the Java Virtual Machine. It absorbs most of the syntax from Java and it is much powerful in terms of functionalities which is manifested in the form Closures, Dynamic Typing, Builders etc.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Scala - Getting Started - Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part2/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part2/</guid>
            <description>In previous article we learned basics of Scala, in this articles we will learn how to setup build scripts for scala and build applications using scala.
We will also learn few web development frameworks for Scala and compare them with similar framework in Java.
Building Scala Applications Below program demonstrates the use of Scala script with Maven, Ant, and logging library – LogBack.
Integration with Ant Below example shows how Scala project can be built by the ant build.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Scala - Getting Started - Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part1/</guid>
            <description>This article help you to start with Scala, with step by step guide and series of examples. It starts with an overview and then covers in detail examples. In later articles, I will write about feature comparison with other languages. It article is helpful for people coming from Java background, how it is not the prerequisites.
Scala Overview Scala is a general purpose programming language designed to express common programming patterns in a concise, elegant, and type-safe way.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Charset configuration in JVM</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-charset-configuration/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-charset-configuration/</guid>
            <description>This article describes how to configure charset for a JVM.
We faced an issue on a Linux environment, a file containing some Swedish character was not being read correctly by underlying JVM since the default charset of JVM was picked as UTF-8 (which does not support some Swedish character). But on the other hand, in Windows environment, it was working fine since the default charset was picked as Windows-1252 (which does support these characters).</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Working with Embedded OLE Objects in Java</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-working-with-ole-objects/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-working-with-ole-objects/</guid>
            <description>Document introduction contains a proof of concept for the research done on reading and writing OLE objects in Java. This research has been done using Apache POI. Please go thru the references for information about apache POI.
This article covers a POC to fetch OLE objects from RIF formatted XML. Not just that, we need to store them in a in some viewable format.
For a given XML in RIF format, parse it and read the embedded OLE object and represent in some viewable format using Java.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>JavaScript Plugin Framework</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/javascript-plugin-framework/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/javascript-plugin-framework/</guid>
            <description>Javascript Plugin Framework is implemented to add extra functionality in the existing Web based application without actually changing the application code. This framework is also helpful when some functionality need to control for different user profiles.
For example, to add one extra button in a menu we can write the plugin directly, by defining what that button is going to do on click, what all events should it handle, in one javascript file rather than making changes in the application code for the same.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Strange JSP Compilation Issue </title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/jsp-compilation-issues/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/jsp-compilation-issues/</guid>
            <description>We were getting following error on the production sever (Linux, Jboss). We were in the middle of user acceptance testing with the client, many users were accessing the application to simulate various scenarios in a live session.
the application was crashing just after 2-3 minute of start with above error, and no user were able to access the application. We were expected for fix the issue ASAP, as the users were assembled for the web session, all were waiting for the server up.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Default Timezone in Java and MySQL</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-mysql-timezone-configuration/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-mysql-timezone-configuration/</guid>
            <description>On one of our production environments, we had an issue our application related to time, specially modified time and creation time of the entities. It was quite random in nature for some entities.
We suspected that there might be issue in the timezone configuration.
Analysing the problem On production environment, we had limited permissions. We were not allowed to change system timezone. We noticed that Jboss is automatically picking the system timezone “Europe/Berlin” (which was configured from root user) and if we check the timezone for the linux user for which we have access it shows GMT time.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MySQL Tuning</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/mysql-tuning/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/mysql-tuning/</guid>
            <description>We have faced &amp;lsquo;out of space&amp;rsquo; issue on disk even after clearing old data on database server(MySQL) and temporary data on application. We noticed that 90% of the space was occupied by the database tables which were used to store very large de-normalized statistical data and when we track the database table we noticed there is not much data in the database in the tables but they were still occupying space on disk.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Rule Engine - Getting Started with Drools</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/rule-engine-getting-started/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/rule-engine-getting-started/</guid>
            <description>This article let you start with Rule Engine Drools, with step by step guide and series of examples. It starts with an overview and then covers in detail examples.
Rule Engine Overview The underlying idea of a rule engine is to externalize the business or application logic. A rule engine can be viewed as a sophisticated interpreter of if-then statements. The if-then statements are the rules. A rule is composed of two parts, a condition and an action: When the condition is met, the action is executed.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Compiling Java Native C/C&#43;&#43; Code</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-jni-cpp/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-jni-cpp/</guid>
            <description>We have faced multiple issues while compiling a native c/c++ code and using it with JNI in our Java application
 How to write a JNI program. jni_md.h not found. Incompatible data types. On widows cygwin1.dll is required when running Java code on the native library. and more.  Actually we were compiling NLP Solver’s native library (IPOPT) on windows 32 bit and on 64bit linux machine.
Solving the chaos! Here are the steps we have followed to solve the above issues:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Using Apache CFX and Apache Camel in ESB</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/esb-introduction-part2/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/esb-introduction-part2/</guid>
            <description>In the previous article, we learned about ESB and deployed our first OSGi bundle on FuseESB.
In this article, we will learn how to build Apache CXF and Apache Camel component and deploy them on FuseESB.
Lets understand what are these components :
Apache Camel ™ Powerful open source integration framework based on known Enterprise Integration Patterns with powerful Bean Integration.
Camel lets you create the Enterprise Integration Patterns to implement routing and mediation rules in either a Java based Domain Specific Language (or Fluent API), via Spring or Blueprint based Xml Configuration files or via the Scala DSL.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Managing Calendar and Invites in Java</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-calendar-and-invite/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-calendar-and-invite/</guid>
            <description>Calendars are used to store formation for various events. Calendar viewer displays the month-date view and for each day displays the events/reminders information.
Invites are the events in the form of email. Once the invite for an event sent to a user via email then that event will be stored in the calendar view and same can be seen in the day information of the calendar view.
Calendars Calendar data can be stored in files; there are some standard formats for storing calendars iCalendar is a computer file format which allows Internet users to send meeting requests and tasks to other Internet users, via email, or sharing files with an extension of .</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Working with Enterprise Service Bus</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/esb-introduction-part1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/esb-introduction-part1/</guid>
            <description>This article starts from basic terms of ESB worlds and then provides details of the FuseESB with various examples.
It contains step by step guide to install FuseESB, and develop and deploy OSGi bundle on FuseESB.
Lets understand terminologies of the ESB world :
ESB An Enterprise Service Bus (ESB) is a software architecture model used for designing and implementing the interaction and communication between mutually interacting software applications in Service Oriented Architecture.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Mail Merge in Java</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-mail-merge/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-mail-merge/</guid>
            <description>MailMerge is a process to create personalized letters and pre-addressed envelopes or mailing labels for mass mailings from a word processing document (Template). A template contains placeholders (Fields) along with the actual content. The placeholders are filled by the data source which is typically a spreadsheet or a database having column for each place holders.
This article talks about the java approach for generating multiple documents from a single MS Word template.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Font configuration in JVM</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-font-mapping/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java-font-mapping/</guid>
            <description>Last year we have migrated one of our application from Java 5 to Java 6. The Java 6(OpenJDK) installation was done by client on a fresh system. After installing our application (under JBoss app), we found the fonts on JFreeCharts and on the images generated from AWT were not correct.
We have solved the issue by configuring the fonts at JVM level. Let understand it better.
How AWT / JFreeCharts shows the fonts AWT rely on native fonts, it usages default Java fonts (which best fits) if no native fonts mapping found.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>