<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>event on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/event/</link>
        <description>Recent content in event on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Globally</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-globally/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-globally/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo; is now available globally!
Read the detail synopsis of the book here and testimonials from a diverse set of industry leaders
Buy Paper Back: 🇦🇺 Amazon Australia - 👉 Get it in less than $95 - Not in stock  🇧🇷 Amazon Brazil - 👉 Get it in less than R$215 - Available  🇨🇦 Amazon Canada - 👉 Get it in less than $46 - Available  🇩🇪 Amazon Germany - 👉 Get it in less than €34 - Available  🇪🇸 Amazon Spain - 👉 Get it in less than 33€ - Available  🇫🇷 Amazon France - 👉 Get it in less than 33€ - Available  🇮🇳 Amazon India - 👉 Get it in less than ₹810 (10% off) - Available  🇮🇹 Amazon Italy - 👉 Get it in less than 33€ - Available  🇯🇵 Amazon Japan - 👉 Get it in less than ¥5,556 - Available  🇳🇱 Amazon Netherlands - 👉 Get it in less than €34 - Available  🇲🇽 Amazon Mexico - 👉 Get it in less than $640 - Available  🇬🇧 Amazon UK - 👉 Get it in less than £27 - Available  🇺🇸 Amazon US and RoW - 👉 Get it in less than $33 - Available</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 4</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-4/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Venkatesh Ponniah, Global Head of Emerging Technologies at Thoughtworks.
We call him Venki. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Venki on technology strategy and governance. He has great insights into emerging technology businesses, particularly in AI, SDV, Digital Twins, and XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ai-powered-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ai-powered-xr/</guid>
            <description>In a world where AI is ubiquitous, technologies like AR, VR, and XR often raise eyebrows, despite their vast potential. AI is not only propelling these technologies forward but also preparing them for the next stages of development. There are tremendous opportunities to leverage their potential for business transformation. I am honored to be invited by Express Computers - India Leading IT Magazine, to speak on this topic and dispel common myths.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>Season of AI, a virtual event series of the Microsoft Azure Developer Community by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a session, where I had the opportunity to guide the community and share insights from my experience in XR and AI development.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, and special thanks to Rohit Sardana and Azkar Khan for extending the invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generative XR – Space aware AI bringing new era of immersion</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</guid>
            <description>Artificial Intelligence has made significant strides with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs) or Generative AI, which are trained to understand and respond to human language naturally. Tools like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google’s Gemini, and Microsoft’s Co-pilot have become the go-to resources for &amp;ldquo;Ask me anything&amp;rdquo; queries. These innovations have been touted as potential Google Search Killer, disrupting the way we search for information, communicate with machines, and receive machine responses.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture: AI and Metaverse reshaping the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</guid>
            <description>AI is pervasive, whether we sense it or not. Staying updated has become essential for survival. We are increasingly immersed in artificially generated worlds, with the internet rapidly evolving into what is known as the metaverse. In my book, &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, I delve into its various forms and interpretations, usecases and challenges, and the way forward.
DesignersX, a company specializing in software development, invited me to speak about my book and discuss how AI and the metaverse will shape the future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 3</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-3/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Kanchan Ray, Chief Technology Officer at Nagarro. We collaborated on building and conceptualizing various cutting-edge proof-of-concepts using emerging technologies. His support and advice were always invaluable.
🙏 I extend my heartfelt thanks to Kanchan for reviewing early versions of the book, sharing his valuable insights, and writing the following foreword:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing the Metaverse at VRARA Energy Committee Event</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/exploring-metaverse-vrara-energy-committee/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/exploring-metaverse-vrara-energy-committee/</guid>
            <description>The VRAR Association(VRARA) is an international organization designed to foster collaboration between XR, mixed reality, spatial computing, and artificial intelligence (AI) solution providers and end-users that accelerates growth, fosters research and education, helps develop industry best practices, connects member organizations and promotes the services of member companies.
VRARA has various industry focused committees, and I am invited to speak at an event by Energy Committee.
Thanks Hemanth Satyanarayana and Susan Spark for invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</guid>
            <description>XREvolve Summit serves a comprehensive platform for exploring the latest advancements, applications, applied sciences and progresses within AR, VR, and the broader domains of the metaverse such as spatial computing and mixed reality. It is backed by Gatherverse community, that advocates humanity-first standards in accessibility, education, equality, community development, safety &amp;amp; privacy, wellness, and ethics within the metaverse and emerging technologies.
This year&amp;rsquo;s focus is XR : Interface of AI, that open up the extraordinary and near limitless possibilities for humanity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-2/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Dr. Rebecca J Parsons, former Chief Technology Officer at Thoughtworks. It has been a privilege to receive guidance from Rebecca at numerous technology strategy events, where her insights on responsible technology usage and our collective responsibility towards sustainability and technological adaptation have been invaluable.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MIPS kick off event, XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse India Policy and Standards (MIPS) is a pioneering initiative led by Experiential Technology Innovation Centre (XTIC), serving as India’s premier research and product innovation hub for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics, hosted at IIT Madras.
It&amp;rsquo;s an honor to be the member of MIPS and showcase my book Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age, which aligns closely with the initiative&amp;rsquo;s objectives.
I extend my gratitude to Thriveni Palanivelu for orchestrating a seamless event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse — A Synopsis</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-a-synopsis/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo; featured on Industry4.0. It is available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online.
 The metaverse, a loosely defined term, has gone from a virtual game world to the next internet and sparks conversations on technology’s potential. Despite eye-rolling at terms like metaverse and eXtended Reality (XR), immersive technologies are silently becoming part of our daily life through social media, virtual collaboration, and digitized experiences. We seamlessly embrace digital tools, scanning codes, engaging in virtual trials, and altering reality through digital filters.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Vishal Shah, General Manager of XR and Metaverse at Lenovo. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of hearing Vishal speak at events like CES and AWE, where he shared invaluable insights on the metaverse and XR technology. Meeting him in person at Lenovo Tech World 2023 was a highlight, where we discussed this book, and he graciously agreed to contribute to its exploration of the metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An Adventure to Remember: Making it to CareerMaker Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</guid>
            <description>The CareerMaker meetup, hosted by the Microsoft Azure Developer Community and managed by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a special keynote address at Microsoft Gurugram, where I had the opportunity to guide students from various institutes and share insights from my experience in product management.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, as engaging with the young, fresh minds of our nation is not only an opportunity to learn from them but also a responsibility to impart valuable knowledge.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Why collaboration is essential for building a successful XR future?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</guid>
            <description>The era of isolated development and secret-keeping innovation is fading. In the past, companies, individuals could thrive by becoming subject matter experts within their own walls. However, the rise of generative AI, fueled by shared knowledge, has changed the game. AI can now imagine and generate solutions faster than ever. The future belongs to those who embrace openness, collaboration, and shared learning.
 Expertise alone isn’t enough. Today, success hinges on building strong networks, fostering partnerships, and collaborating within communities.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead The concept of the Metaverse keeps evolving, leaving many confused. 📖 In my book, Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age I leverage my years of experience to:
 Unravel the Metaverse: Demystify the term and explore its true potential. Separate Myth from Reality: Address misconceptions surrounding the metaverse. Prepare for the Future: Equip you with insights to navigate the evolving digital landscape.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Coming Soon! Exploring the Metaverse</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-comming-soon/</guid>
            <description>In the world of tech buzzwords, “metaverse” has been topic of discussion, largely understood and misunderstood. It comes, goes, and comes again in new shapes and forms, definitions and understanding. The term has been around for three decades and is poised to continue its evolution.
In the past, it has been defined to suit the narratives of organizations and individuals alike. Some see it as a game, others as a virtual world, while some view it as a tool for global connection and collaboration.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Being inclusive, being me</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/being-inclusive-being-me/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/being-inclusive-being-me/</guid>
            <description>🙋‍ ️As International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day is celebrated worldwide, efforts are underway to recognize women&amp;rsquo;s representation across diverse fields. In India, the spirit of &amp;lsquo;Nari Shakti&amp;rsquo; is alive as discussions focus on various schemes and initiatives. Increased enforcement is advocating for equal opportunities in underrepresented sectors. The promising shift towards inclusivity is shaping a future grounded in equity and equality.
👩‍💻 Thoughtworks is synonymous with diversity and inclusion, a leading brand in this space.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Panelist at FICCI XROS Fellowship Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, the transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtending Reality (XR) at it&amp;rsquo;s core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution would be the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. I recently had the privilege of participating as a panelist at an event hosted by the pioneers shaping the future of the internet. In this article, I share my insights and a summary of this remarkable event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XConf-2023 - Thoughtworks India - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2023/</guid>
            <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
Last year, I presented on the topic of AI Assisted Content Pipeline for XR. This year, we took it a step further by hosting an immersive experience booth. We featured cutting-edge AR/VR devices and engaged in in-depth discussions about various industrial applications. It was truly enriching to interact with participants, share our insights, and absorb their perspectives.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Rapid Prototyping Community - Products beyond software horizons!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/products-beyond-software-horizons/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/products-beyond-software-horizons/</guid>
            <description>🤖 Rapid Prototyping Community Rapid Prototyping is an internal community @Thoughtworks, focused on building a culture of rapid prototyping and innovation. They organise various learnings events, and I was invited to speak at one of their events.
I talked about the importance of holistic product development and how the modern products goes beyond software. I also discussed the impact of technological evolution on products, how to stay ahead of the curve.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Lean2Lead tech track - Twisted realities</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</guid>
            <description>Lean2Lead is a network of women at work, with will to lead and succeed in their respective areas of work. They are 400+ women from different industries together in this group for exchange of ideas, connecting and coaching, building network with industry leaders and inspiring each other for building strategies for success in leadership and executive roles.
I am speaking at their tech session series, on 15 July 2023, 3-4 PM.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Progress Review - Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/msh-progress-review-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/msh-progress-review-1/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality (XR) is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and user believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited to join the Progress Review Committee as a Judge for Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program. It is great talking to top XR startups of India.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Greening Up: Key takeaways from Green Software Foundation Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/green-software-foundation-meetup-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/green-software-foundation-meetup-2023/</guid>
            <description>As technology continues to advance, electronics are getting smaller and wires are disappearing. Even electric poles, once a familiar sight on road trips, are being phased out. With the internet now ubiquitous, physical storage devices are disappearing too, and we rely more on cloud-based solutions that seem to happen over the air.
 ‘It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder we look up when we think of clouds ☁️, but should actually look down to the earth in the mines!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughtworks TWinnoFest 3.0</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-twinnofest3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-twinnofest3/</guid>
            <description>The TWiinoFest 3.0 The third edition of innovation fest, named at TWinnoFest, a month-long hackathon, was recently held by Innovation Labs at Thoughtworks. This year&amp;rsquo;s event was conducted remotely, with participants spread across different cities. I was fortunate enough to be invited to judge the finale of the event.
The sheer variety and quality of ideas presented was truly astounding. It was incredibly difficult to compare them, as each one was unique and innovative in its own way.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Community Events are the Energy Boosters!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gta_lets_fork_together/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gta_lets_fork_together/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the opportunity to contribute to an event called &amp;ldquo;GTA Ghaziabad - Let’s Fork Together&amp;rdquo;. The event was hosted by a community of working professionals and undergraduate engineers from nearby colleges in NCR, and took place at my home office, Thoughtworks Gurgaon. Participating in this event provided me with another energy boost, and in this article, I would like to share my experience and give you a glimpse of what the event was all about!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Agility Today Fest 2023 - Generative AI and XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</guid>
            <description>Agility Today is a 2 days annual UnConference, to meet Agility needs of industry, gathered over past few years via meetups, Conferences and Webinar. This UnConference intends to give you best of Agile Psyche (Mindset Culture and Practice) and Geekery (Engineering, Tools and DevOps). This year in Agility Today Fest 2023 there are couple of programs.
I am speaking to at Agile Engineering Lab (Technical Agility &amp;amp; Engineering Excellence), on topic of Scaling content generation for XR using AI.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
            <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at MOZOHACK 4.0 by the Mozilla Students Club</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/judge-mozohack4-srmkzilla-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/judge-mozohack4-srmkzilla-2023/</guid>
            <description>MOZOHACK is a 24-hour hackathon organized by SRMKZILLA. SRMKZILLA is a Mozilla campus club of SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai(India). It is inspired by the Mozilla Learning Network, provides students an open platform to analyze and enhance their technical and non-technical skills, such as working on open-source projects, developing websites, technical fests, and workshops. The club is conducting the seventh edition of its annual flagship event – MOZOFEST&#39;23 – where they celebrate student community through technical and non-technical events.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
            <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;SpatialWeb and Web3.0&#39; at NIT Calicut</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest_lecture_nit_calicut/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest_lecture_nit_calicut/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Calicut is organizing Tathva, Asia&amp;rsquo;s largest student-run Tech Startup Expo. Tathva is a techno-management fest of NIT Calicut is one of south India&amp;rsquo;s biggest scholastic endeavours. Since its inception in 2000, this annual symposium has known only growth and has flourished into one of the few promising enterprises the nation has witnessed. Pushing the barriers year after year, Tathva aims at providing a plethora of platforms to the intrigued technical heads that arrive at this fiesta with an array of events and workshops, to sharpen their skills and widen their knowledge quotient.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Podcast : XR in practice: the engineering challenges of extending reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-in-practice-engineering-challenges-extending-reality/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-in-practice-engineering-challenges-extending-reality/</guid>
            <description>Brief summary Extended Reality technology — XR — has had a lot of hype in recent years thanks to the concept of the metaverse. But bold visions of the future can obscure the reality of what engineers and organizations are doing today.
In this episode of the Technology Podcast, the host Scott Shaw and Birgitta Boeckeler are joined by Cam Jackson and Kuldeep Singh to discuss the XR work Thoughtworks has been doing with clients.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judging the Smart India Hackathon Juniors 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/sih-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/sih-2022/</guid>
            <description>After a wonderful experience of participating as a judge and mentor at Smart India Hackathon 2019 and 2020, I am delighted to share that I got a chance to meet and judge India&amp;rsquo;s young winners and innovators at Grand Finale of Smart India Hackathon Juniors 2022, Smart India Hackathon 2022 is a nationwide initiative to provide students a platform to solve some of the pressing problems we face in our daily lives, and thus inculcate a culture of product innovation and a mindset of problem solving.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XConf-2022 - Thoughtworks India</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2022/</guid>
            <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
Last year XConf was virtual but this year, we are resuming to a physical one, so come meet us face to face in Bangalore at ITC Gardenia on Friday, July 29.
  &amp;nbsp; I am exited to share the stage with renowned technologists like Supriyo Ghosh, Chief Architect, Open Network for Digital Commerce (ONDC) India, our Head of Technology Bharani Subramaniam and Vanya Seth along with other techies from three streams Emerging Tech, Digital Transformation and Data.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/leadership-roundtable-vamrr/</guid>
            <description>The VAMRR ITeS Leaders Round Table The thoughtleadership roundtable is an exclusive event hosted by VAMRR Technologies Pvt Ltd, where they invite an elite gathering of 20 ITeS leaders focused on the areas of Design Visualization, Digital Twin and Hybrid Workspaces.
This one is the 98th Conference/Round Table by VAMRR Technologies, and focus this roundtable would be on developments across Advanced Visualization, Remote Design Collaboration, Hybrid Workspaces, 3D Workflows, Data Integrated Digital Twins, Web3 and Metaverse are all converging.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Launch | Metaverse Glossary - Your gateway to the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-glossary-book/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-glossary-book/</guid>
            <description>The Metaverse Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days, and every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suit their narrative. It would end up creating many sub-metaverses, with different sets of features and, would lead to confusions, and conflict of interests. Acceptable definition of Metaverse will evolve with time. At this stage, I treat the metaverse as a result of technological evolutions in the key areas such as ARVR, AI, Cloud, Blockchain, 5G/6G and hardware.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge - Ashoka University Hackathon 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ashoka-university-hackathon-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ashoka-university-hackathon-2022/</guid>
            <description>RedBrick Hacks is flagship summer hackathon of Ashoka University, open to students from Delhi NCR. You will have the opportunity to learn, collaborate, and build meaningful projects alongside mentors from various disciplines. For 24 hours on the weekend of June 18, you will have access to free workshops, plenary lectures, prizes worth over ₹8L, games, and more!
The theme of the event was &amp;ldquo;Tech for Social Good&amp;rdquo; with three main tracks: Health &amp;amp; Wellness, Sustainable Growth, and Security &amp;amp; Privacy.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse Workshop - VIT-AP University</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</guid>
            <description>School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCOPE) of VIT-AP University is organizing a 1-day National Workshop on “Exploring the Blockchain in Metaverse” on June 11, 2022, from 11 am to 5 pm.
 The program is intended for students, faculty of technical institutes, professionals from Industry, R&amp;amp;D organizations, and research scholars.
I will be speaking at the workshop on &amp;ldquo;Gearing up for Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, Will touch upon metaverse step by step.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XR and Sustainability - GSF Global Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</guid>
            <description>Green Software Foundation Green Software Foundation (GSF) is building a trusted ecosystem of people, standards, tooling and best practices for Green Software. GSF works with vision to change the culture of building software across the tech industry, so sustainability becomes a core priority to software teams, just as important as performance, security, cost and accessibility. Read more here.
GSF Global Summit 2022 The Green Software Foundation Global Summit 2022 is a series of free events organized by Green Software Foundation members all around the globe that are passionate about sustainable software development, maintenance.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Indian Achievers&#39; Award 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</guid>
            <description>Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Awards is India’s Most Coveted Award For Outstanding Achievements, organized by Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum. It draws attention on the theme “how the successful Achievers can help the social development in and around the country.” It provides examples of social entrepreneurs, successful models of the society and business community partnership. It promotes achievements that inspire businesses and communities, and recognizes the outstanding professional achievers&amp;rsquo; and their contribution in nation building.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture at VIT Vellore</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse has become the newest macro-goal for tech industries to invest in and to see the world in a new perspective with the help of AR and VR technologies.🌟
A student club at VIT Vellore named Mozilla Firefox Club invited me for a guest lecture in The Parallax View Episode 1 :Bring the world to wherever you are
 🔮✨Join us on 22nd April, 6PM to clarify all your doubts regarding AR and VR and opportunities it offers you !</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Recognitions</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/recognitions/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/recognitions/</guid>
            <description>Awards Indian Achiever&amp;rsquo;s Awards 2022 ☞ More Details
Recognitions Judge at Smart India Hackathon ☞ More Details ☞ More events like this
Guest Lecture at NIT Calicut ☞ More Details ☞ More events like this
Guest Lecture at DesignersX ☞ More Details ☞ More events like this
Coverage  </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at HackBMU 5.0</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/bmu-hack5/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/bmu-hack5/</guid>
            <description>BML Munjal University, a Hero group initiative, is organizing a 5th edition Hackathon, named HackBMU 5.0. It is a hackathon focused on promoting innovation, diversity and networking among all future hackers. We will be hosting upcoming engineers and developers from all over the World to create mobile, web, and hardware hacks for an intense session.
HackBMU seeks to provide a welcoming and supportive environment to all participants to develop their skills, regardless of their background.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Your Hackathon Guide at IEEE WIE - BU - The Times Groups</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ieee-bu-wie-discussion/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ieee-bu-wie-discussion/</guid>
            <description>IEEE WIE (Women In Engineering) at Bennett University - The Times Group, has hosted a panel discussion with students preparing and participating in hackathons.
 I joined the panel of 🌟 Swati Anuj Arya (chief information security officer, Amazon Pay) and 🌟Srishti Gupta (Senior data analyst at Ernst &amp;amp; Young) to share our experience with students.
Highlights of the event! It was a great discussion, we started with questions on prerequisites of hackathon, and skills required to participate in hackathon, where we talked about being a thinker, solution oriented mindset, authenticity and practicality of the ideas and stay aligned to the problem statements.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at Tech-Nexus Hackathon</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/tech-nexus-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/tech-nexus-2021/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Metaverse&#39; at NIT Hamirpur</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</guid>
            <description>The MasterClass This October, at Thoughtworks India, we’re celebrating our 20th anniversary! That’s 20 years of excellence in technology!
 All through the month we’re hosting 10 tech talks, delivered by some of our best-and-brightest technologists in India. Each of them will be taking you through different topics, ranging from Distributed Delivery and XR, to Security and Navigating Ambiguity.
I am sharing stage with Raju Kandaswamy who is a robotics enthusiast and taking us through &amp;ldquo;Using XR in building autonomous vehicles&amp;rdquo;.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge - Thoughtworks iFest 2.0</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-ifest2/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-ifest2/</guid>
            <description>The iFest This October, at Thoughtworks India, we’re celebrating our 20th anniversary! That’s 20 years of excellence in technology!
Innovation Lab&amp;rsquo;s at Thoughtworks comes second edition of iFest - a month long hackathon. I got opportunity to participate in iFest as a judge.
I was amazed to see the verity of idea. All the ideas were great and it was so hard to compare them.
Ideas were touching were reflecting the Thougthworks culture, use technology to solve challenges society is facing.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XConf-2021 - Thoughtworks India</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2021/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks-xconf-2021/</guid>
            <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
This year, XConf will be a virtual experience available at two different time slots. October 7th and 8th will feature pre-recorded sessions and October 9th will feature live sessions. During the nine exciting talks spread across three days.
 I am exited to sharing the stage with renowned technologists like Neal Ford, Dr.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Discussion - Navigating the new normal</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-navigating-new-normal/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-navigating-new-normal/</guid>
            <description>The world is finding the ways to get out of Covid impact, some are on recovery path and some are still bettling it. At ThoughtWorks, we have recently published our insights on navigating the new normal with augmented reality. Members of Communities of Practice of The VRARA come together to discuss the topic and share the opinion on way forward for XR.
I presented thoughtworks insights to other renowned industry leaders and VRARA members like Pradeep Sharma, Swarup Choudhury and Rajiv Madane, and technology exports like Pradeep Naik and Dhruv.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge at HackBMU 4.0</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/bmu-hack4/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/bmu-hack4/</guid>
            <description>BML Munjal University,a Hero group initiative, is organizing a 4th edition Hackathon, named HackBMU 4.0. It is a hackathon focused on promoting innovation, diversity and networking among all future hackers. We will be hosting upcoming engineers and developers from all over the World to create mobile, web, and hardware hacks for an intense session.
HackBMU seeks to provide a welcoming and supportive environment to all participants to develop their skills, regardless of their background.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - AT2020 - Agility in Enterprise XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/at_2020_agilexr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/at_2020_agilexr/</guid>
            <description>Enterprise XR is gaining good traction, and software development’s best practices like Agile principles really matters due to multitude of tooling and tech stacks used for Enterprise XR solutions
Enterprises do face multiple challenges with the XR development lifecycle. One of them is the automation of testing XR applications. In response to this gap, ThoughtWorks has developed Arium – an open-source, lightweight, extensible, platform-agnostic framework that helps write automation tests that are built specifically for XR Applications.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Juror - SMCC Startup Challenge by Nasscom</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/nasscom-smcc/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/nasscom-smcc/</guid>
            <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM CoE is launching first-of-its-kind virtual SMART MANUFACTURING COMPETENCY CENTER (SMCC). The innovation platform which will help in accelerating technology adoption by bringing enterprises, governments, researchers, and innovators together.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge - DotSlash 4.0 - Hackthon by NIT Surat</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/dotstash_2021_hackathon/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/dotstash_2021_hackathon/</guid>
            <description>SVNIT Surat has organized a hackathon - DotSlash 4.0, a 30 hours long hackathon. More information here - https://www.hackdotslash.co.in/
I have participated in this event as a Judge.
The Event Details - 30-31st Jan 2021  It was really proud feeling to head interesting ideas from the young innovators, use the technology to find solutions during Covid and Post-Covid. Ideas to track and optimize carbon generation even from digitization (emails, internet and more), help specially-abled using technology to communicate, build digital restaurant menu to provide contactless experience, make the online exam cheat-proof, and many more.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Mentor and Juror - MIC 2020 by Nasscom</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/nasscom-iotcoe/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/nasscom-iotcoe/</guid>
            <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM has organized Manufacturing Innovation Challenge 2020 from 12th Oct to 11th Dec, on theme of redefining enterprises and entrepreneurs engagement.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtended Reality for Enterprise - a PODCast by XROM</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xrom-podcast-enterprise-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xrom-podcast-enterprise-xr/</guid>
            <description>Interesting conversation on eXtended Reality (XR) with Eddie Avil, starting from my background, how I landed up in the XR space and where are we heading…
XROM PODCast XROM PODCast is a youtube channel maintained by serial entrepreneur, dreamer &amp;amp; a believer Mr. Eddie Avil. This channel has number of interesting conversations with industry leaders in the emerging technology space. Eddie Avil, also runs a marketplace for AR VR hardware and service, visit here https://www.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - GIDS - Extended Machine Learning with XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_xr4ml/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 06:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_xr4ml/</guid>
            <description>Extended Reality is not only meant for humans, they can very well serve machines by producing Digital twins. Digital twins encapsulate real world elements with all important physics characteristics enabling the researcher to produce large volume of training data needed for reinforment learning and CNN based deep learning algorithms. Extended Reality environments are mature today and are capable of producing photorealistic rendering and physics emulation of real world just by using digital twins.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Webinar - Essentials of XR Product Design and Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</guid>
            <description>The VRAR Association&amp;rsquo;s Product Design and Development (PDD) Communities of Practice (COP) brings its first webinar on &amp;ldquo;Essentials of XR Product Design and Development&amp;rdquo;.
I will be sharing the stage with industry leader Mr. Pradeep Khanna, VR AR Association, and XR innovator Mr. Raju Kandaswamy, ThoughtWorks.
Spread the words  Registration Only Please register at the below link, and save the date Oct 17, 2020, 4:30 PM IST.
https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/14711/445904
The webinar will be available at https://www.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Geeknight - XR - eXtending the Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</guid>
            <description>Geek Night is a regular event to promote the sharing of technical knowledge and increase collaboration among the geeks. It is organized by a passionate group of programmers and sponsored by ThoughtWorks.
Sep month&amp;rsquo;s geek night has covered Extended Reality - An umbrella term covering various technologies like AR,VR and MR. I will be discussing what is XR, its usage and significance today, that is stretching beyond gaming.
Embracing an Agile approach is essential to any successful XR implementation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Webinar - XR - Nicety to Necessity</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</guid>
            <description>Techgig is the largest community of developers, also organizes webinars on emerging technologies.
I have spoken at a webinar on Extended Reality (XR) - Moving from Nicety to Necessity on coming Aug 13, at 3PM IST.
Join @thinkuldeep, Head- ARVR Practice, #ThoughtWorksIndia, for a webinar on &amp;quot;why XR is moving from nicety to necessity in the new normal?&amp;quot;
Registrations are now open: https://t.co/IHcOpLgLXZ@techgigdotcom #ExtendedReality #ThoughtWorks pic.twitter.com/MCf7EcWSjV
&amp;mdash; ThoughtWorks India (@thoughtworksIN) August 11, 2020  Highlights COVID-19 has impacted economies, businesses and human behaviour.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2020</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/sih-2020/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/sih-2020/</guid>
            <description>After a wonderful experience of participating as a judge and mentor at Smart India Hackathon 2019, I am delighted to share that I again got a chance to meet and judge India&amp;rsquo;s young winners and innovators at Grand Finale of Smart India Hackathon 2020, world’s biggest open innovation modal, organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. This time it is no more a hackathon but a hackathon of hackathons — 4 Lacks students, 1500 small hackathons, 40 Nodal centers, around 2000 mentors and 1000 evaluators, 11000 finalists and more…</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge - HackInIndia - Hackathon 2020</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</guid>
            <description>I got chance to judge the HackInIndia event, India&amp;rsquo;s National Level hackathon organized by Script Foundation on 2nd July, 2020.
Around 150 teams signed up across multiple tracks (Healthcare, Open Innovation, ARVR, EdTech, RPA and FinTech) supported by couple of talented mentors. I and Raviraj Subramanian got chance to meet only top 20 teams in Jury round, and I was amazed to see their innovative ideas, and demonstrations the young blood of nation bring on the table.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Spatial Web - Life beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</guid>
            <description>New Date is still to be announced.
Get ready: Great International Developer Summit is re-scheduled and now virtual summit will be organized.
Come and talk about the life beyond keyboard and screens, spatial web is taking over get ready&amp;hellip;
The talk is about Spatial Web is an umbrella term for the next generation web technologies that will transform every aspect of our life. It will connect the human and machines seamlessly such that the difference between physical and virtual will disappear.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XR Day - ThoughtWorks India</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_xrday/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_xrday/</guid>
            <description>The XR Day Organized XR Days at ThoughtWorks, India in different cities and conducted awareness sessions and ideation workshop and more..
The talks are about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen xr day 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Event Summary It was well recevied the participats.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - AwayDay 2019 - SLAM Aware Applications</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</guid>
            <description>Presented At : Thoutworks&amp;rsquo;s Awayday 2019, where the entire ThoughtWorks India travelled to celebrate togetherness.
I and my colleague Raju Kandaswamy presented this talk in the breakout sessions in category Seismic Shifts Around 2000 Thoghtworkers get together, and enjoyed fusion of technology showcases, cultural event and more. Glimpse here
 The talk is about  What is SLAM (Simultaneous Localization And Mapping)? The use cases of SLAM? How does it work?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
            <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here LinkedIn
We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2019</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/sih_2019_an_experience/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/sih_2019_an_experience/</guid>
            <description>Recently got a chance to judge and mentor india&amp;rsquo;s young innovators at Smart India Hackathon 2019, world&amp;rsquo;s largest hackathon with 11000 shortlisted participants, hosted by 48 centers across India. It was organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. I was invited to Judge the event at Panipat Institute of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology, Panipat. I am delighted to contribute in the journey of India&amp;rsquo;s transformation, and see innovative ideas from the new generation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Contributor - JavaOne - Rapid Modernization to Java8</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/oracle-rapid-modernization-of-java-applications-to-jdk-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/oracle-rapid-modernization-of-java-applications-to-jdk-8/</guid>
            <description>Presented At: G. Venkat, Senior Vice President of Technology &amp;amp; Solutions, at Nagarro and I have spoken at the Oracle OpenWorld / JavaOne conference on Wednesday, October 1, 2014, form 10:00 – 11:00 a.m., Pacific Time, at Ballroom 6 in the Hilton San Francisco at Union Square.
I have supported Venkat and presented the JMod tool demo with him.
Here are some coverages - https://www.nagarro.com/en/news-events/nagarro-has-java-8-covered-at-oracle-open-world I have lead the Nagarro Stall and showcased the JMod demo to 300+ visitors.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>