<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughtworks on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/thoughtworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughtworks on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/thoughtworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XR enabled me to renovate my home!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 is still unmeasurable, and we are getting more or less getting adjusted to this new normal. We are eagerly waiting to say goodbye to this year 2020, and welcome the coming 2021, the year of hope. Read more here to know why I call this year 2020 as year of change.
In April this year, I explained XR development from home, and that was still near shore to office, I was less than an hour away from the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geeknight - XR - eXtending the Reality</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</guid>
      <description>Geek Night is a regular event to promote the sharing of technical knowledge and increase collaboration among the geeks. It is organized by a passionate group of programmers and sponsored by ThoughtWorks.
Sep month&amp;rsquo;s geek night has covered Extended Reality - An umbrella term covering various technologies like AR,VR and MR. I will be discussing what is XR, its usage and significance today, that is stretching beyond gaming.
Embracing an Agile approach is essential to any successful XR implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Learning Equation</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</guid>
      <description>Today, The world is celebrating teacher’s day. I wish Happy Teacher&amp;rsquo;s day to all of us! We all are teachers and learners as every one of us has something to learn from others and something to teach others. I am thinking of an equation of learning that defines my way of learning and hope it would be helpful for you too.  The learning equation — Learning is proportional to Sharing; Learning ∝ Sharing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Thoughtful Years!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/two-thoughtful-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/two-thoughtful-years/</guid>
      <description>It’s now two years since I accepted a challenging change to leave the previous organization after 13 long years, and join ThoughtWorks. Any change requires sacrifices and dedication before it becomes a positive change, but the journey becomes easy when we believe in the change and accept it. A change introduces us to a new environment and enables new thoughts, and new energy. The two years journey at ThoughtWorks is no different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of shopping</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/future-of-shoping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/future-of-shoping/</guid>
      <description>eXtended Reality (XR) that includes AR and VR technologies have been silently disrupting the gaming industry for more than a decade. In the recent past, the tech has gained some traction in the education and training space.
Today, however, COVID-19 with its mandates of social distancing and less to no physical interactions has accelerated adoption for XR. The tech is virtual, contactless, and delivers outstanding brand experiences - perfect for the new normal that multiple industries like retail will benefit from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-2/</guid>
      <description>In Part I of the article, we summarized our observations of eXtended reality’s foundational blocks - AR, VR and MR. We also discussed the popular and most relevant tools and implementations of the new technology. In Part II of the article, we will be looking at a few accessible and novel implementations of the tech.
At ThoughtWorks, we have delivered both XR solutions and components of XR SDK (Software Development Kit) on the back of which XR solutions are built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</guid>
      <description>The way we interact with technology today is not too far from what was predicted by futuristic, sci-fi pop culture. We are living in a world where sophisticated touch and gesture based interactions are collaborating with state of the art wearables, sensors, Augmented Reality (AR), Virtual Reality (VR) and Mixed Reality (MR). And, this is eXtending user experiences to be extremely immersive.
Add to this, Gartner’s expectation that 5G and AR/VR implementation will transform not only customer engagement but brands’ entire product management cycles as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XR development from home</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-development-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-development-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 has challenged the way we eat, the way we commute, the way we socialize, and the way we work. In short, it impacted the way we live. More than a million people got infected and the number is growing exponentially, it has impacted the whole world. We need to find new ways of life and change our focus and priorities to save nature and humanity. Technology can play a great role in coping with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - XR Day - ThoughtWorks India</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_xrday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_xrday/</guid>
      <description>The XR Day Organized XR Days at ThoughtWorks, India in different cities and conducted awareness sessions and ideation workshop and more..
The talks are about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen xr day 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Event Summary It was well recevied the participats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - AwayDay 2019 - SLAM Aware Applications</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Thoutworks&amp;rsquo;s Awayday 2019, where the entire ThoughtWorks India travelled to celebrate togetherness.
I and my colleague Raju Kandaswamy presented this talk in the breakout sessions in category Seismic Shifts Around 2000 Thoghtworkers get together, and enjoyed fusion of technology showcases, cultural event and more. Glimpse here
 The talk is about  What is SLAM (Simultaneous Localization And Mapping)? The use cases of SLAM? How does it work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception Workshop | Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</guid>
      <description>Inception exercise is very common in software development, where we gather the business requirements and define the delivery plan for the MVP(Minimum Viable Product) on a shared understanding. There are a set of tools and practices available to define the MVP requirements and its delivery plan. Famous tools are Lean Value Tree, Business Model Canvas, Plane Map, Elevator Pitch, Futurespective, Empathy Maps, Value Proposition Canvas, User Journey Map, Gamestorming, Process Diagram, MoSCoW, Communication Plan, Project Plan etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embibe purpose and balance in life</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</guid>
      <description>I just finished a book &amp;ldquo;Life&amp;rsquo;s Amazing Secrets&amp;rdquo; by Gaur Gopal Das. It covers the topic of balance and purpose in life nicely. Few of the concepts from the book I can very well relate to my current organization&amp;rsquo;s focus on cultivation and collaboration culture.
It&amp;rsquo;s now more than 6 months of my journey with Thoughtworks, an organization which started as a social experiment more than 25 years ago, and believes in balancing 3 pillars in life ; sustainability, excellence and purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your organisation agility by test-first-pair development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/test-first-pair-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/test-first-pair-development/</guid>
      <description>Agile software development methodology is the key selling point for most of the IT organisations, however many of the organisations have gone by the literal meaning of the word &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo;. They follow agile practices without really being agile. If we go by Manifesto for Agile Software Development, it focus more on human factor (people, interaction, collaboration) which produces working software as per the need of time, than on processes, tools and strict planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept the change!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/accept_the_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/accept_the_change/</guid>
      <description>The change is inevitable and constant; it is a part of our life. Sooner or later, we have to accept the change. 13 years ago, I joined a small IT organisation of around 100 people, as a developer. I have grown with the organisation; a 40 times growth journey. I really thank the organisation for giving me opportunity, and transforming me, what I am today. Now, the time has come to accept a change, and start a new journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Kuldeep has built his career empowering businesses with the Tech@Core approach. He has incubated IoT and AR/VR Centres of Excellence with a strong focus on building development practices such as CICD, TDD, automation testing and XP around new technologies.
Kuldeep has developed innovative solutions that impact effectiveness and efficiency across domains, right from manufacturing to aviation, commodity trading and more. Kuldeep also invests time into evangelizing concepts like connected worker, installation assistant, remote expert, indoor positioning and digital twin, using smart glasses, IoT, blockchain and ARVR technologies within the CXO circles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>