<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webinar on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/webinar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webinar on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:58:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar - Extended Reality (XR) - Nicety to Necessity</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</guid>
      <description>Techgig is the largest community of developers, also organizes webinars on emerging technologies.
I will be speaking a webinar on Extended Reality (XR) - Moving from Nicety to Necessity on coming Aug 13, at 3PM IST. Please book your seat and explore new realities.
Highlights COVID-19 has impacted economies, businesses and human behaviour. The sudden change has forced organizations to embrace digital-first at accelerated speeds. The ensuing chaos has given emerging tech like XR the opportunity to become a need-to-have over a nice-to-have in industries like health, retail, manufacturing and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panelist &amp; Organizer - Essentials of XR Product Development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar-1/</guid>
      <description>The VRAR Association&amp;rsquo;s Product Design and Development (PDD) Community of Practice (COP) bring series of webinars,
First was planned on 11th July 2020, and supposed to be hosted by Mr. Tejinder Jassal , and with co-speaker/panelist Mr. Aditya Bhatnagar and Mr. Raju Kandasamy
Highlights  Understanding XR technologies What it takes to build XR products and solutions XR in Education How it is going from &amp;ldquo;nice to have&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;must have&amp;rdquo; choice in this COVID time?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>