<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>webinar on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/webinar/</link>
        <description>Recent content in webinar on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing the Metaverse at VRARA Energy Committee Event</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/exploring-metaverse-vrara-energy-committee/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/exploring-metaverse-vrara-energy-committee/</guid>
            <description>The VRAR Association(VRARA) is an international organization designed to foster collaboration between XR, mixed reality, spatial computing, and artificial intelligence (AI) solution providers and end-users that accelerates growth, fosters research and education, helps develop industry best practices, connects member organizations and promotes the services of member companies.
VRARA has various industry focused committees, and I am invited to speak at an event by Energy Committee.
Thanks Hemanth Satyanarayana and Susan Spark for invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse Workshop - VIT-AP University</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</guid>
            <description>School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCOPE) of VIT-AP University is organizing a 1-day National Workshop on “Exploring the Blockchain in Metaverse” on June 11, 2022, from 11 am to 5 pm.
 The program is intended for students, faculty of technical institutes, professionals from Industry, R&amp;amp;D organizations, and research scholars.
I will be speaking at the workshop on &amp;ldquo;Gearing up for Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, Will touch upon metaverse step by step.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Indian Achievers&#39; Award 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</guid>
            <description>Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Awards is India’s Most Coveted Award For Outstanding Achievements, organized by Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum. It draws attention on the theme “how the successful Achievers can help the social development in and around the country.” It provides examples of social entrepreneurs, successful models of the society and business community partnership. It promotes achievements that inspire businesses and communities, and recognizes the outstanding professional achievers&amp;rsquo; and their contribution in nation building.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture at VIT Vellore</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse has become the newest macro-goal for tech industries to invest in and to see the world in a new perspective with the help of AR and VR technologies.🌟
A student club at VIT Vellore named Mozilla Firefox Club invited me for a guest lecture in The Parallax View Episode 1 :Bring the world to wherever you are
 🔮✨Join us on 22nd April, 6PM to clarify all your doubts regarding AR and VR and opportunities it offers you !</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Your Hackathon Guide at IEEE WIE - BU - The Times Groups</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ieee-bu-wie-discussion/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ieee-bu-wie-discussion/</guid>
            <description>IEEE WIE (Women In Engineering) at Bennett University - The Times Group, has hosted a panel discussion with students preparing and participating in hackathons.
 I joined the panel of 🌟 Swati Anuj Arya (chief information security officer, Amazon Pay) and 🌟Srishti Gupta (Senior data analyst at Ernst &amp;amp; Young) to share our experience with students.
Highlights of the event! It was a great discussion, we started with questions on prerequisites of hackathon, and skills required to participate in hackathon, where we talked about being a thinker, solution oriented mindset, authenticity and practicality of the ideas and stay aligned to the problem statements.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Metaverse&#39; at NIT Hamirpur</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Webinar - Essentials of XR Product Design and Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</guid>
            <description>The VRAR Association&amp;rsquo;s Product Design and Development (PDD) Communities of Practice (COP) brings its first webinar on &amp;ldquo;Essentials of XR Product Design and Development&amp;rdquo;.
I will be sharing the stage with industry leader Mr. Pradeep Khanna, VR AR Association, and XR innovator Mr. Raju Kandaswamy, ThoughtWorks.
Spread the words  Registration Only Please register at the below link, and save the date Oct 17, 2020, 4:30 PM IST.
https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/14711/445904
The webinar will be available at https://www.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Geeknight - XR - eXtending the Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</guid>
            <description>Geek Night is a regular event to promote the sharing of technical knowledge and increase collaboration among the geeks. It is organized by a passionate group of programmers and sponsored by ThoughtWorks.
Sep month&amp;rsquo;s geek night has covered Extended Reality - An umbrella term covering various technologies like AR,VR and MR. I will be discussing what is XR, its usage and significance today, that is stretching beyond gaming.
Embracing an Agile approach is essential to any successful XR implementation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Webinar - XR - Nicety to Necessity</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</guid>
            <description>Techgig is the largest community of developers, also organizes webinars on emerging technologies.
I have spoken at a webinar on Extended Reality (XR) - Moving from Nicety to Necessity on coming Aug 13, at 3PM IST.
Join @thinkuldeep, Head- ARVR Practice, #ThoughtWorksIndia, for a webinar on &amp;quot;why XR is moving from nicety to necessity in the new normal?&amp;quot;
Registrations are now open: https://t.co/IHcOpLgLXZ@techgigdotcom #ExtendedReality #ThoughtWorks pic.twitter.com/MCf7EcWSjV
&amp;mdash; ThoughtWorks India (@thoughtworksIN) August 11, 2020  Highlights COVID-19 has impacted economies, businesses and human behaviour.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>