<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mips on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/mips/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mips on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/mips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>XR Symposium Takeaways and Book Launch at IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-symposium-takeaways-and-book-launch/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of speaking at XR Symposium 2025, hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class symposium showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>ITU-T Technical Report - IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/itu-t-sg20-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/itu-t-sg20-2025/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the privilege of representing 🇮🇳 India at the International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) Study Group 20 (SG20) meeting in Geneva.
I’m pleased to share that my recommendations for standardizing requirements for an IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System has been accepted as an official Technical Report. Here’s a brief overview of the experience and its significance.
About ITU-T Study Group 20 The ITU-T is a global body that develops standards for telecommunications and ICT, bringing together governments, industry leaders, and academia.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Contributions to ITU-T SG-20 on IoT and Metaverse</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/itu-t-sg20-meeting/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/itu-t-sg20-meeting/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse: The Next Internet The Metaverse represents the next evolution of the internet, a digital realm where the physical and virtual worlds converge. In my book, 📕 Exploring the Metaverse, I delve into the current state of the Metaverse and how advancements in AI, IoT, networking, and cloud technologies are accelerating its development at an unprecedented pace.
As a call to action, I emphasize the importance of collaboration among industry leaders, academia, and individuals to establish standards and practices for the responsible use of the Metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 5</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-5/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
One of the most distinguished endorsements comes from Prof. M Manivannan, who leads the Experiential Technologies Innovation Center (XTIC) at IIT Madras.
Prof. Mani has spearheaded innovation at XTIC and have made India proud. His pioneering work in areas like iTad(interactive Touch Active Display) and integrating haptics into virtual reality solutions is noteworthy.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>