<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>get together on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/get-together/</link>
        <description>Recent content in get together on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/get-together/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Jagjeevan at Silver Jubilee of Millennium Batch NIT Kurukshetra</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-silver-jubilee/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-silver-jubilee/</guid>
            <description>In earlier article, I talked about the effort to meet and reconnect with friends and family always fills you up—it gives you a true Dose of Jagjeevan
I recently received a powerful one at the Silver Jubilee celebration of my Millennium (2K) Batch at NIT Kurukshetra. It was deeply heartwarming to reconnect with old friends, relive shared memories, and celebrate the journey we began together more than two decades ago.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Dose of Jagjeevan  - Frequently meet and greet your family!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/dose-of-jagjeevan-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/dose-of-jagjeevan-1/</guid>
            <description>Taking a break from our daily routine to spend time with family often feels harder than it should be. Busy schedules, long travel, work pressure, health concerns, distance, or even unresolved misunderstandings slowly become convenient excuses. Yet, deep down, we all know this truth: family gatherings are essential for our mental peace and happiness.
 We celebrate festivals, birthdays, anniversaries, and milestones to strengthen family bonds and create memories that last a lifetime.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>