<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>judge on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/judge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in judge on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/judge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Juror - SMCC Startup Challenge by Nasscom</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-smcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-smcc/</guid>
      <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM CoE is launching first-of-its-kind virtual SMART MANUFACTURING COMPETENCY CENTER (SMCC). The innovation platform which will help in accelerating technology adoption by bringing enterprises, governments, researchers, and innovators together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor and Juror - MIC 2020 by Nasscom</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-iotcoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-iotcoe/</guid>
      <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM has organized Manufacturing Innovation Challenge 2020 from 12th Oct to 11th Dec, on theme of redefining enterprises and entrepreneurs engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</guid>
      <description>After a wonderful experience of participating as a judge and mentor at Smart India Hackathon 2019, I am delighted to share that I again got a chance to meet and judge India&amp;rsquo;s young winners and innovators at Grand Finale of Smart India Hackathon 2020, world’s biggest open innovation modal, organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. This time it is no more a hackathon but a hackathon of hackathons — 4 Lacks students, 1500 small hackathons, 40 Nodal centers, around 2000 mentors and 1000 evaluators, 11000 finalists and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge - HackInIndia - Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</guid>
      <description>I got chance to judge the HackInIndia event, India&amp;rsquo;s National Level hackathon organized by Script Foundation on 2nd July, 2020.
Around 150 teams signed up across multiple tracks (Healthcare, Open Innovation, ARVR, EdTech, RPA and FinTech) supported by couple of talented mentors. I and Raviraj Subramanian got chance to meet only top 20 teams in Jury round, and I was amazed to see their innovative ideas, and demonstrations the young blood of nation bring on the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2019</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</guid>
      <description>Recently got a chance to judge and mentor india&amp;rsquo;s young innovators at Smart India Hackathon 2019, world&amp;rsquo;s largest hackathon with 11000 shortlisted participants, hosted by 48 centers across India. It was organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. I was invited to Judge the event at Panipat Institute of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology, Panipat. I am delighted to contribute in the journey of India&amp;rsquo;s transformation, and see innovative ideas from the new generation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>