<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>covid19 on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/covid19/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid19 on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/covid19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Building Spatial Solutions</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 is forcing us into a ‘new normal’, A new normal that makes most of us work from home, and that leads to spending long hours on Zoom, or other video conferencing platforms. Meetings, inceptions, discovery workshops, conferences, and webinars are happening in the same monotonous ways. We are stuck with a screen in almost the same pose and posture. Some might use their mobile phone or tablet but that limits us to a small screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Will Cultivation from 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/will-cultivation-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/will-cultivation-2020/</guid>
      <description>The year 2020 was the year of change, it may be painful for some, but at the same time, it has taught us lessons in life. I have written about it earlier that we have to accept it, and it will be remembered and will have an impact on our whole life and after our life, no matter what we do. So it is important that we live the present fully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XR enabled me to renovate my home!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 is still unmeasurable, and we are more or less getting adjusted to this new normal. We are eagerly waiting to say goodbye to this year 2020 and welcome the coming year of hope, 2021. Read more here to know why I call this year 2020, as the year of change.
In April this year, I explained XR development from home, and that was still near shore to office, I was less than an hour away from the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar - XR - Nicety to Necessity</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</guid>
      <description>Techgig is the largest community of developers, also organizes webinars on emerging technologies.
I have spoken at a webinar on Extended Reality (XR) - Moving from Nicety to Necessity on coming Aug 13, at 3PM IST.
Join @thinkuldeep, Head- ARVR Practice, #ThoughtWorksIndia, for a webinar on &amp;quot;why XR is moving from nicety to necessity in the new normal?&amp;quot;
Registrations are now open: https://t.co/IHcOpLgLXZ@techgigdotcom #ExtendedReality #ThoughtWorks pic.twitter.com/MCf7EcWSjV
&amp;mdash; ThoughtWorks India (@thoughtworksIN) August 11, 2020  Highlights COVID-19 has impacted economies, businesses and human behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge - HackInIndia - Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</guid>
      <description>I got chance to judge the HackInIndia event, India&amp;rsquo;s National Level hackathon organized by Script Foundation on 2nd July, 2020.
Around 150 teams signed up across multiple tracks (Healthcare, Open Innovation, ARVR, EdTech, RPA and FinTech) supported by couple of talented mentors. I and Raviraj Subramanian got chance to meet only top 20 teams in Jury round, and I was amazed to see their innovative ideas, and demonstrations the young blood of nation bring on the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 — The year of Change</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2020-year-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2020-year-of-change/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, early we accept, early we get ready for the future. 2020 is a year of change, accept it, and change our lifestyle and get ready for the future.
I have been writing about the change in the past, right from accepting the change to change for good to have a purposeful and balanced life and uncover human potential in this Covid19 time.
Today, June 20, is my younger son Lovyansh’s 3rd Birthday, and June month is really time to rejuvenate and celebrate for the kids when they are free from school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the human potential</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 has challenged the way work, I have penned down my earlier article to cover my workday and our shift toward new ways of working. Covid19 has impacted not just the way we work, but also our lives. All-day, we keep hearing how it is hitting hard on humanity and it has brought so much negativity around us.
Enough of negativity, let’s uncover human potential to cop with it. In this article, I will cover how the ways of our regular life are shifting, and uncovering new human potentials to try out new things and performing our chores own our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XR development from home</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-development-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-development-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 has challenged the way we eat, the way we commute, the way we socialize, and the way we work. In short, it impacted the way we live. More than a million people got infected and the number is growing exponentially, it has impacted the whole world. We need to find new ways of life and change our focus and priorities to save nature and humanity. Technology can play a great role in coping with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>