<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>commissioner on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/commissioner/</link>
        <description>Recent content in commissioner on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 11:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/commissioner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>OpenThread Commissioner Implementation in Java</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-java/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-java/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how to build and use an Android app as an external commissioner to onboard Thread devices into a network. This article takes it a step further by demonstrating how to implement a Java-based external commissioner.
The thread commissioning process involves the following key steps:
 Discovering the Border Router Connecting to the Border Router Adding Joiner Rules Joining the Thread Network  In this guide, we will implement these steps in a Java application, providing a clear and structured approach to external commissioning in OpenThread.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Building and Using OpenThread Commissioner Mobile App</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-android/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-external-commissioner-android/</guid>
            <description>In our previous article, we set up an external commissioner outside a Thread network using a command-line tool on a PC. However, OpenThread also provides a mobile app that can serve as an external commissioner.
This guide will walk you through building and using the OpenThread Commissioner mobile app to provision a device onto a Thread network.
Building the OpenThread Commissioner Mobile App OpenThread provides an Android app source, which requires Android Studio and Android NDK to build.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>