<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>general on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Learning Equation</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</guid>
      <description>Today, when the world is celebrating teacher’s day, Happy teachers day to all of us. We all are teachers and learners as every one of us has something to learn from others and something to teach others. I am thinking of an equation of learning that defines my way of learning and hope it would be helpful for you too.  The learning equation — Learning is proportional to Sharing; Learning ∝ Sharing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Thoughtful Years!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/two-thoughtful-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/two-thoughtful-years/</guid>
      <description>It’s now two years since I accepted a challenging change to leave the previous organization after 13 long years, and join ThoughtWorks. Any change requires sacrifices and dedication before it becomes a positive change, but the journey becomes easy when we believe in the change and accept it. A change introduces us to a new environment and enables new thoughts, and new energy. The two years journey at ThoughtWorks is no different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 — The year of Change</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2020-year-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/2020-year-of-change/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, early we accept, early we get ready for the future. 2020 is a year of change, accept it, and change our lifestyle and get ready for the future.
I have been writing about the change in the past, right from accepting the change to change for good to have a purposeful and balanced life and uncover human potential in this Covid19 time.
Today, June 20, is my younger son Lovyansh’s 3rd Birthday, and June month is really time to rejuvenate and celebrate for the kids when they are free from school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here LinkedIn
Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growing List of XR Devices</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-growing-list-of-xr-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-growing-list-of-xr-devices/</guid>
      <description>In my earlier article, I have explained the fundamentals of XR and the type of XR, and the popular devices in those XR types. ARVR is not the only about Head-Mounted Display(HMD) devices. There is an ever-growing list of Google ARCore supported smartphones/tablets and ARKit is being supported in recent Apple phones. But still, when when it comes to AR and VR devices, the first thing that comes in mind is head-mounted display devices (HMD), however, the newer mobile phones/tablets are now coming with AR/VR support with a minimal set of tools attached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the human potential</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 has challenged the way work, I have penned down my earlier article to cover my workday and our shift toward new ways of working. Covid19 has impacted not just the way we work, but also our lives. All-day, we keep hearing how it is hitting hard on humanity and it has brought so much negativity around us.
Enough of negativity, let’s uncover human potential to cop with it. In this article, I will cover how the ways of our regular life are shifting, and uncovering new human potentials to try out new things and performing our chores own our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebXR - the new Web</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/webxr-the-new-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/webxr-the-new-web/</guid>
      <description>The web has grown from a read-only web (Web 1.0) to interactive web (Web 2.0) and then moved into the semantic web which is more connected and more immersive. 3D content on the web is there for quite some time, the most web-browsers support rendering 3D content natively. The rise for XR technologies and advancements in devices and the internet is leading the demand for Web-based XR. It will be a norm for web-based development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success Mantra</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/success_mantra_amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/success_mantra_amazon/</guid>
      <description>Everyone in India is talking about Jeff Bezos, the richest of the world, who was on India&amp;rsquo;s visit recently. People are talking about the investments he is making in India, talking about his prediction about India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;21st Century is going to be the Indian century&amp;rdquo;, and discussing the impact on small businesses. We have seen disruptions lead by Amazon in multiple sectors, now people have a fear that whatever Amazon touch, it becomes Amazon&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here LinkedIn
We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Technology and User Interactions</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</guid>
      <description>Technology defines our interactions with the ambiance, and the way we want to interact with the ambiance further defines the technology. The evolution of technology and user interactions tightly depends on each other.
 &amp;ldquo;Walls have ears!&amp;quot;, is very much true today, and not just that, now the walls can see you, feel your presence and talk to you.
 In this post, we will discuss how the user interactions evolved with time and what is next!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can IT modernization lead to revenue loss?</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/can_it_modernization_lead_to_revenue_loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/can_it_modernization_lead_to_revenue_loss/</guid>
      <description>IT Modernization is one of the key factors of today&amp;rsquo;s digital transformation. Most of the enterprises trying to define digital transformation strategy. IT organizations trying to redesign the organizations to meet the changing business need, and uplift the technology and people. Non-IT organizations are also trying to setup digital department to take care of companies digital assets and modernize them. However, IT modernization does not always result in a profit, it may lead to revenue loss if it does not fit to the organization design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept the change!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/accept_the_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/accept_the_change/</guid>
      <description>The change is inevitable and constant; it is a part of our life. Sooner or later, we have to accept the change. 13 years ago, I joined a small IT organisation of around 100 people, as a developer. I have grown with the organisation; a 40 times growth journey. I really thank the organisation for giving me opportunity, and transforming me, what I am today. Now, the time has come to accept a change, and start a new journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Effectiveness vs Software Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/software-effectiveness-vs-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/software-effectiveness-vs-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>I define software effectiveness as, doing the objective effectively, I mean correctly. Efficiency can be defined as, using the resources optimally where resources could be memory, CPU, time, files, connections, databases etc.
From my experience, in most (should I call many) of the software projects, efficiency/performance is not much accentuated during the system design and in earlier phases(requirement and estimation) as compared to the emphasis given late in the game, coding and testing and mostly in maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>