<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>conference on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/conference/</link>
        <description>Recent content in conference on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>XConf-2024 - Thoughtworks India - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thoughtworks-xconf-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thoughtworks-xconf-2024/</guid>
            <description>November was a month filled with learning and sharing! After the inspiring XR Summit 2024 at IIT Madras, I had the privilege of attending another fantastic event—XConf 2024 by Thoughtworks India. Here are my key takeaways from this incredible gathering of technologists.
About XConf XConf is Thoughtworks&amp;rsquo; annual technology event, designed by technologists for technologists. Sponsored this year by AWS and CockroachDB, it celebrates innovation and the transformative power of software in the real world.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XConf-2023 - Thoughtworks India - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thoughtworks-xconf-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thoughtworks-xconf-2023/</guid>
            <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
Last year, I presented on the topic of AI Assisted Content Pipeline for XR. This year, we took it a step further by hosting an immersive experience booth. We featured cutting-edge AR/VR devices and engaged in in-depth discussions about various industrial applications. It was truly enriching to interact with participants, share our insights, and absorb their perspectives.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
            <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>