<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work from home on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/work-from-home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work from home on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/work-from-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Will Cultivation from 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/will-cultivation-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/will-cultivation-2020/</guid>
      <description>The year 2020 was the year of change, it may be painful for some, but at the same time, it has taught us lessons in life. I have written about it earlier that we have to accept it, and it will be remembered and will have an impact on our whole life and after our life, no matter what we do. So it is important that we live the present fully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XR enabled me to renovate my home!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/xr-enabled-home-renovation/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 is still unmeasurable, and we are more or less getting adjusted to this new normal. We are eagerly waiting to say goodbye to this year 2020 and welcome the coming year of hope, 2021. Read more here to know why I call this year 2020, as the year of change.
In April this year, I explained XR development from home, and that was still near shore to office, I was less than an hour away from the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XR development from home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/xr-development-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/xr-development-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 has challenged the way we eat, the way we commute, the way we socialize, and the way we work. In short, it impacted the way we live. More than a million people got infected and the number is growing exponentially, it has impacted the whole world. We need to find new ways of life and change our focus and priorities to save nature and humanity. Technology can play a great role in coping with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
