<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>fundamentals on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/fundamentals/</link>
        <description>Recent content in fundamentals on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fundamentals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Soft IoT Continued: Bringing the Internet into IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot-continued/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot-continued/</guid>
            <description>Simplifying IoT learning doesn’t have to mean getting bogged down with hardware details. Instead, let’s dive into Soft IoT — where we focus on software-driven IoT exploration. In this article, we’ll learn how to read inputs from a button and turn it into a web based remote control for an LED, all while keeping things software-centric..
In the previous article, we introduced Soft IoT using a Grove Pi board, which simplifies IoT learning by hiding wiring and connections complexity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting Started with Soft IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/soft-iot/</guid>
            <description>Learning IoT doesn’t have to be complex, especially when starting out. In this post, we’ll explore how to get started with IoT without diving deep into hardware complexities like wiring or understanding intricate sensor details.
In an earlier article, we set up a Raspberry Pi. My son initially saw it as just another, albeit slower, computer. There was no “IoT” in it yet, just a basic device. But IoT is about more than just the device itself; it’s about integrating sensors and actuators.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Booting Up the Internet of Things</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-rebooting/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-rebooting/</guid>
            <description>A few years ago, I bought a Raspberry Pi 3, but during a house move, I misplaced it. Fast forward to this Diwali cleaning, and to my surprise, I found it! My son’s curiosity was piqued, so we decided to set it up together. While my recent focus has been on XR technologies and we setup XRPractices, but this moment brought me back to IoT — sparking the idea to share my journey and experiences through a series of articles on getting started with IoT.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Podcast : XR in practice: the engineering challenges of extending reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-in-practice-engineering-challenges-extending-reality/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-in-practice-engineering-challenges-extending-reality/</guid>
            <description>Brief summary Extended Reality technology — XR — has had a lot of hype in recent years thanks to the concept of the metaverse. But bold visions of the future can obscure the reality of what engineers and organizations are doing today.
In this episode of the Technology Podcast, the host Scott Shaw and Birgitta Boeckeler are joined by Cam Jackson and Kuldeep Singh to discuss the XR work Thoughtworks has been doing with clients.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtended Reality - the new norm?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_new_norm/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_new_norm/</guid>
            <description>This article is originally published at TechTag.de, you may find the German version here too.
The interaction between humans and technology is evolving radically. We need to develop our thinking and skills beyond the keyboard and screen. But what does this new technological reality look like? Here it is worth taking a closer look at the different forms of extended reality and how they can change our everyday lives.
The way we interact with technology today isn&amp;rsquo;t too far from what was predicted by futuristic sci-fi pop culture.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here LinkedIn
Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</guid>
            <description>The way we interact with technology today is not too far from what was predicted by futuristic, sci-fi pop culture. We are living in a world where sophisticated touch and gesture based interactions are collaborating with state of the art wearables, sensors, Augmented Reality (AR), Virtual Reality (VR) and Mixed Reality (MR). And, this is eXtending user experiences to be extremely immersive.
Add to this, Gartner’s expectation that 5G and AR/VR implementation will transform not only customer engagement but brands’ entire product management cycles as well.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - XR Day - ThoughtWorks India</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_xrday/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thougthworks_xrday/</guid>
            <description>The XR Day Organized XR Days at ThoughtWorks, India in different cities and conducted awareness sessions and ideation workshop and more..
The talks are about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen xr day 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Event Summary It was well recevied the participats.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
            <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here LinkedIn
We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IOT 101: A primer on Internet of Things</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_simplified/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_simplified/</guid>
            <description>IOT 101 A Primer on Internet of Things  from Kuldeep Singh  The IoT can be described as “Connecting the Things to internet”.
A comprehensive IoT ecosystem consists of many different parts such as electronic circuitry, sensing and acting capability, embedded systems, edge computing, network protocols, communication networks, cloud computing, big data management and analytics, business rules etcetera. This maze of varied parts can be better classified into 4 broad categories:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Driving Forces Behind IoT</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-driving-forces-iot/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/the-driving-forces-iot/</guid>
            <description>Everybody in the software industry is talking about IoT in terms of billions of devices, their growth in coming years, changing business models, and adaptation of the IoT in the market. Connecting the things has become so prevalent nowadays, that every software company wants to expand in IoT by building IoT-centric products and services.
There are many industrial applications which connect to sensors and actuators, and can be controlled remotely. They have been around for a long time.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>