<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>selfhelp on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/selfhelp/</link>
        <description>Recent content in selfhelp on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/selfhelp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Books</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</guid>
            <description>📕 Exploring the Metaverse  Redefining Reality in the Digital Age ☞ Amazon.in ☞ BPB Online ☞ Free Preview ☞ More Details 
Natural evolution in technology and human interactions converge to the metaverse
☞ Amazon.in ☞ eBook ☞ BPB Online ☞ Free Preview ☞ More Details 
   📕 My Thoughtworkings The guiding thoughts that work for me ☞ Book launch - Five thoughtful years ☞ Download</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>thinkuldeep.com | 100 Articles and 50 Events</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/100-articles-50-events/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/100-articles-50-events/</guid>
            <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve reached a milestone: 100 articles and 50 events at thinkuldeep.com. This experience has improved my writing, boosted my confidence, and fueled my passion for self-expression. I&amp;rsquo;m thankful to readers, authors, speakers, and mentors who inspired me.
I want to share common obstacles I overcame, hoping to inspire others on their creative journeys.
1. I am not a great writer/speaker, I can&amp;rsquo;t express well Blocker#1 is doubting our abilities, it is natural when we haven&amp;rsquo;t explored our potential.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Effective communication: five key insights</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/effective-communication-5-insights/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/effective-communication-5-insights/</guid>
            <description>Communication is a puzzle - will others understand us as we hope? What&amp;rsquo;s the secret to effective communication? In this article, I share my top five lessons from books, personal exploration, and experts in the field.
I&amp;rsquo;m still learning this art, and it&amp;rsquo;s ever-evolving. I&amp;rsquo;ve read couple books and followed communication pros, they shed light on how crucial communication is, especially in our modern ways of working. But it&amp;rsquo;s clear even they&amp;rsquo;re always learning.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Habit Matters - The change is a side effect</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/habitmatters/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/habitmatters/</guid>
            <description>“Change is the only constant, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether we like it or not, it takes place”- shared and reflected in my change stories.
 Over the years, I have been following my theory of change Accept-Observe-Absorb. It helped me to traverse through the change year 2020, and understand the role of “Will” and how to cultivate it. I shared how just one change “working from my native home” brought so many other changes in lifestyle and behavior.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>2020 — The year of Change</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2020-year-of-change/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2020-year-of-change/</guid>
            <description>Change is the only constant, early we accept, early we get ready for the future. 2020 is a year of change, accept it, and change our lifestyle and get ready for the future.
I have been writing about the change in the past, right from accepting the change to change for good to have a purposeful and balanced life and uncover human potential in this Covid19 time.
Today, June 20, is my younger son Lovyansh’s 3rd Birthday, and June month is really time to rejuvenate and celebrate for the kids when they are free from school.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Uncovering the human potential</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</guid>
            <description>Covid19 has challenged the way work, I have penned down my earlier article to cover my workday and our shift toward new ways of working. Covid19 has impacted not just the way we work, but also our lives. All-day, we keep hearing how it is hitting hard on humanity and it has brought so much negativity around us.
Enough of negativity, let’s uncover human potential to cop with it. In this article, I will cover how the ways of our regular life are shifting, and uncovering new human potentials to try out new things and performing our chores own our own.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
            <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Success Mantra</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/success_mantra_amazon/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/success_mantra_amazon/</guid>
            <description>Everyone in India is talking about Jeff Bezos, the richest of the world, who was on India&amp;rsquo;s visit recently. People are talking about the investments he is making in India, talking about his prediction about India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;21st Century is going to be the Indian century&amp;rdquo;, and discussing the impact on small businesses. We have seen disruptions lead by Amazon in multiple sectors, now people have a fear that whatever Amazon touch, it becomes Amazon&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Embibe purpose and balance in life</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</guid>
            <description>I just finished a book &amp;ldquo;Life&amp;rsquo;s Amazing Secrets&amp;rdquo; by Gaur Gopal Das. It covers the topic of balance and purpose in life nicely. Few of the concepts from the book I can very well relate to my current organization&amp;rsquo;s focus on cultivation and collaboration culture.
It&amp;rsquo;s now more than 6 months of my journey with Thoughtworks, an organization which started as a social experiment more than 25 years ago, and believes in balancing 3 pillars in life ; sustainability, excellence and purpose.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>