<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>startup on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/startup/</link>
        <description>Recent content in startup on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>XR - the Enabler | XROS Fellowship Report</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, a transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtended Reality (XR) at its core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution is the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. My book, Exploring the Metaverse, available globally, outlines this kind of collaboration as a call to action for all of us.
FICCI XROS Fellowship Program Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce &amp;amp; Industry (FICCI), is the voice of india&amp;rsquo;s business and industry for policy change.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Panelist at FICCI XROS Fellowship Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, the transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtending Reality (XR) at it&amp;rsquo;s core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution would be the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. I recently had the privilege of participating as a panelist at an event hosted by the pioneers shaping the future of the internet. In this article, I share my insights and a summary of this remarkable event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Progress Review - Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/msh-progress-review-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/msh-progress-review-1/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality (XR) is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and user believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited to join the Progress Review Committee as a Judge for Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program. It is great talking to top XR startups of India.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Community Events are the Energy Boosters!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gta_lets_fork_together/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gta_lets_fork_together/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the opportunity to contribute to an event called &amp;ldquo;GTA Ghaziabad - Let’s Fork Together&amp;rdquo;. The event was hosted by a community of working professionals and undergraduate engineers from nearby colleges in NCR, and took place at my home office, Thoughtworks Gurgaon. Participating in this event provided me with another energy boost, and in this article, I would like to share my experience and give you a glimpse of what the event was all about!</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
            <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>