<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>india on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/india/</link>
        <description>Recent content in india on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 6</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-6/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-6/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores globally, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders, adding valuable perspectives to the content.
The book explores the opportunities and concerns of the metaverse, outlining a path forward that calls for collective action from academia, industry, government, and individuals. I initiated this collective effort by gathering testimonials from a diverse group of experts.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MIPS kick off event, XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse India Policy and Standards (MIPS) is a pioneering initiative led by Experiential Technology Innovation Centre (XTIC), serving as India’s premier research and product innovation hub for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics, hosted at IIT Madras.
It&amp;rsquo;s an honor to be the member of MIPS and showcase my book Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age, which aligns closely with the initiative&amp;rsquo;s objectives.
I extend my gratitude to Thriveni Palanivelu for orchestrating a seamless event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Indian Achievers&#39; Award 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</guid>
            <description>Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Awards is India’s Most Coveted Award For Outstanding Achievements, organized by Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum. It draws attention on the theme “how the successful Achievers can help the social development in and around the country.” It provides examples of social entrepreneurs, successful models of the society and business community partnership. It promotes achievements that inspire businesses and communities, and recognizes the outstanding professional achievers&amp;rsquo; and their contribution in nation building.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>