<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>product management on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/product-management/</link>
        <description>Recent content in product management on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/product-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Books</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</guid>
            <description>📕 Jagjeevan  Living Larger than Life 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life is a heartfelt tribute to the extraordinary life and timeless wisdom of Shri Jagguram—an enlightened soul whose values shaped generations. Blending personal memories with profound life lessons, it captures the essence of a man who lived with humility, discipline, compassion, and unwavering purpose.
 Through ten insightful chapters, the book explores heritage, resilience, responsibility, inner strength, family unity, conflict resolution, gratitude, and the power of one’s actions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Certificates</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/certificates/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/certificates/</guid>
            <description> Microsoft Certified: Azure AI Fundamentals Generative AI Essentials 2 Expertise: Complete Concise Guide nRF Connect SDK Intermediate Bluetooth Low Energy Fundamentals nRF Connect SDK Fundamentals Building AI Elements of AI Product Management Enterprise Architecture Internet of Things (IOT) User Experience Design Taradata Certified Java Certified Programmer </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An Adventure to Remember: Making it to CareerMaker Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</guid>
            <description>The CareerMaker meetup, hosted by the Microsoft Azure Developer Community and managed by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a special keynote address at Microsoft Gurugram, where I had the opportunity to guide students from various institutes and share insights from my experience in product management.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, as engaging with the young, fresh minds of our nation is not only an opportunity to learn from them but also a responsibility to impart valuable knowledge.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Product Management Untangled | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/book-product-management-untangled/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/book-product-management-untangled/</guid>
            <description>Product management is a unique blend of art and science, distinct from roles such as project management, program management, business analysis, or business development. Some projects or products may have dedicated product managers, but I believe these skills are valuable for various roles, even if not explicitly labeled as a product manager. Even technologists can benefit from these skills to enhance the value of their work.
This is where Dinker Charak&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;lsquo;Product Management Untangled&amp;rsquo; becomes essential.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Rapid Prototyping Community - Products beyond software horizons!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/products-beyond-software-horizons/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/products-beyond-software-horizons/</guid>
            <description>🤖 Rapid Prototyping Community Rapid Prototyping is an internal community @Thoughtworks, focused on building a culture of rapid prototyping and innovation. They organise various learnings events, and I was invited to speak at one of their events.
I talked about the importance of holistic product development and how the modern products goes beyond software. I also discussed the impact of technological evolution on products, how to stay ahead of the curve.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>