<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>3d on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/3d/</link>
        <description>Recent content in 3d on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/3d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Open-sources and Apps</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/open-sources/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/open-sources/</guid>
            <description>Gen AI Hands On Practices Google Colab Hands-on practice for developing Gen AI applications, and understanding the concepts.
☞ Github ☞ Learn More
 SSO Proxy A lightweight proxy tool for accessing APIs and websites that require SSO authentication. It uses Puppeteer to open a browser window for login and then reuses the authenticated cookies to access the proxied URL.
This tool is particularly helpful for:
 Showcasing integration with portal APIs that require SSO (before SSO is actually set up).</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Spatially interact with 3D Model from a 2D app in the smart glasses</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/patent-granted-xr-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/patent-granted-xr-4/</guid>
            <description>💡 Innovation often starts with solving everyday problems. While working on XR solutions and building operating systems for smart glasses, we solved one such challenge.
Earlier, with our patented AppSpace method, we enabled rendering a phone’s 2D apps in 3D on smart glasses. But we found a gap — there was no direct way for a 2D app (like Chrome) to interact with 3D spatial content.
🏅 Thrilled to share that our solution to this is now recognized with a U.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>DJXHack 2025 | Fostering Artificial Sense in the XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>DJXHack 2025 was an inspiring hackathon organized by DJX Labs, attracting students and professionals from across institutions. Out of many applicants, 30 XR enthusiasts were shortlisted to participate and showcase innovative ideas in extended reality (XR).
I had the honor of being invited as a speaker, where I shared my thoughts on how AI is fostering artificial sense in the XR world. Grateful to be a part of such an impactful event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Patent Granted: Streaming of Composite Alpha Blended AR/MR Video</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/patent-granted-xr-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/patent-granted-xr-3/</guid>
            <description>💡 Innovation Often Begins with Solving Everyday Problems
In our daily work, we regularly develop methods, processes, features, or approaches to address specific challenges. While these may initially seem like routine solutions, some of them quietly evolve into true innovations—often without us realizing it at the time.
🏅 I’m excited to share that one such innovation has now been recognized with a U.S. Patent!
Patent No : US 12,323,679 B2 This patent, titled _&amp;ldquo;Streaming of Composite Alpha Blended AR/MR Video&amp;rdquo; granted to Lenovo, introduces a novel method for web-based AR and MR streaming—allowing mixed reality experiences from a headset to be cast directly to a web browser, along with the phone screen.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit and AWE Nite | XR with AI, Gaming, AVGC</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xr-summit-2024/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to announce that I’ll be part of the XR Summit 2024 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the AI-powered Metaverse is Our Next Reality</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/exploring-ai-powered-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>📖 My Takeaways from Our Next Reality by Alvin Wang Graylin and Louis Rosenberg
☞ Buy - Exploring the Metaverse ☞ Buy - Our Next Reality 
Our Next Reality topped my reading list for months, and travel always helps me catch up on books! After meeting Alvin at AWE Asia 2024, I was eager to dive in and finally complete it. Following recent trips to Singapore and now the US, here’s what I found worth sharing from the book.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>India&#39;s Metaverse Journey - XROM Podcast</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-exploring-the-metaverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/xrom-podcast-exploring-the-metaverse/</guid>
            <description>Exciting conversation on the future of tech with Eddie Avil, where we dive into my journey of writing Exploring the Metaverse, discuss the opportunities and challenges of the digital age, and even touch on mind-bending concepts like Programmable Dreams and Time Travel. Are we ready for what’s coming?
XROM Podcast 🎙️ XROM PODCast, hosted by serial entrepreneur and visionary Eddie Avil, is an incredible YouTube channel showcasing conversations with industry leaders in emerging tech.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/aweasia-2024/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ai-powered-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ai-powered-xr/</guid>
            <description>In a world where AI is ubiquitous, technologies like AR, VR, and XR often raise eyebrows, despite their vast potential. AI is not only propelling these technologies forward but also preparing them for the next stages of development. There are tremendous opportunities to leverage their potential for business transformation. I am honored to be invited by Express Computers - India Leading IT Magazine, to speak on this topic and dispel common myths.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Azure AI Fostering Sense within XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/azure-ai-fostering-sense-within-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>Season of AI, a virtual event series of the Microsoft Azure Developer Community by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a session, where I had the opportunity to guide the community and share insights from my experience in XR and AI development.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, and special thanks to Rohit Sardana and Azkar Khan for extending the invitation.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generative XR – Space aware AI bringing new era of immersion</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</guid>
            <description>Artificial Intelligence has made significant strides with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs) or Generative AI, which are trained to understand and respond to human language naturally. Tools like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google’s Gemini, and Microsoft’s Co-pilot have become the go-to resources for &amp;ldquo;Ask me anything&amp;rdquo; queries. These innovations have been touted as potential Google Search Killer, disrupting the way we search for information, communicate with machines, and receive machine responses.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Making the XR content usable with AI!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</guid>
            <description>Generative AI is revolutionizing content generation across various mediums, disrupting traditional methods in text, images, art, movies, and music creation. XR (Extended Reality) is also undergoing this transformation. In a previous article, Raju Kandaswamy and I discussed how AI aids in generating content for XR, meeting the dynamic needs of XR and the metaverse.
We highlighted content management as a key challenge in XR and metaverse adoption. While generative AI methods offer some solutions, the significant hurdle of content optimization remains.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Run a 2D App in XR Container</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/run-a-2d-app-in-xr-container/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/run-a-2d-app-in-xr-container/</guid>
            <description>There are a number of Enterprise XR use cases where we have a need to open the existing 2D apps in the XR devices in a wrapper app, and this article covers a concept, have a look!
After trying the OS level customization on an XR device, you may like to run your XR apps as a system app. Here is a simple article by Raju K
 Android System Apps development - Android Emulator Setup and guidelines to develop system applications</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>