<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>best practices on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/best-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in best practices on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Speaker at Meta-Meity XR Startup Hub, IITD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
      <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Building Spatial Solutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/xr-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/xr-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 is forcing us into a ‘new normal’, A new normal that makes most of us work from home, and that leads to spending long hours on Zoom, or other video conferencing platforms. Meetings, inceptions, discovery workshops, conferences, and webinars are happening in the same monotonous ways. We are stuck with a screen in almost the same pose and posture. Some might use their mobile phone or tablet but that limits us to a small screen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
