<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>change on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in change on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 — The year of Change</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/2020-year-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/2020-year-of-change/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, early we accept, early we get ready for the future. 2020 is a year of change, accept it, and change our lifestyle and get ready for the future.
I have been writing about the change in the past, right from accepting the change to change for good to have a purposeful and balanced life and uncover human potential in this Covid19 time.
Today, June 20, is my younger son Lovyansh’s 3rd Birthday, and June month is really time to rejuvenate and celebrate for the kids when they are free from school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the human potential</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/uncovering-the-human-potential/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 has challenged the way work, I have penned down my earlier article to cover my workday and our shift toward new ways of working. Covid19 has impacted not just the way we work, but also our lives. All-day, we keep hearing how it is hitting hard on humanity and it has brought so much negativity around us.
Enough of negativity, let’s uncover human potential to cop with it. In this article, I will cover how the ways of our regular life are shifting, and uncovering new human potentials to try out new things and performing our chores own our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embibe purpose and balance in life</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/embibe_purpose_and_balance_in_life/</guid>
      <description>I just finished a book &amp;ldquo;Life&amp;rsquo;s Amazing Secrets&amp;rdquo; by Gaur Gopal Das. It covers the topic of balance and purpose in life nicely. Few of the concepts from the book I can very well relate to my current organization&amp;rsquo;s focus on cultivation and collaboration culture.
It&amp;rsquo;s now more than 6 months of my journey with Thoughtworks, an organization which started as a social experiment more than 25 years ago, and believes in balancing 3 pillars in life ; sustainability, excellence and purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept the change!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/accept_the_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/accept_the_change/</guid>
      <description>The change is inevitable and constant; it is a part of our life. Sooner or later, we have to accept the change. 13 years ago, I joined a small IT organisation of around 100 people, as a developer. I have grown with the organisation; a 40 times growth journey. I really thank the organisation for giving me opportunity, and transforming me, what I am today. Now, the time has come to accept a change, and start a new journey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>