<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>books on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/books/</link>
        <description>Recent content in books on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>My thoughtworkings from five thoughtful years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/five-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/five-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks is celebrating its 30th year in industry, and I have completed five years here, and to celebrate this, I have compiled thoughts from thoughtworkers, and published them as an ebook. I am grateful for the wealth of knowledge and experiences shared by my colleagues. These thoughts have resonated with me and shaped my journey within the organization and life.
I am excited to launch the ebook with this post. I believe this compilation of thoughts will not only serve as a personal reflection but also as a valuable resource for others on their own professional journeys.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Books</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</guid>
            <description>My thoughtworkings The guiding thoughts that work for me In celebration of Thoughtworks&amp;rsquo; 30th anniversary, I am excited to launch this eBook featuring guiding thoughts from a diverse set of 30 thoughtworkers. These thoughts have resonated with me and shaped my journey within the organization and life.
This ebook is launched on my fifth anniversary at Thoughtworks. I believe this compilation of thoughts will not only serve as a personal reflection but also as a valuable resource for others on their own professional journeys.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>