<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>books on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/books/</link>
        <description>Recent content in books on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>📕Jagjeevan launch@Thoughtworks</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-at-thoutghtworks/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks, Thoughtworkers, and books share a deep and enduring connection. Over the years, hundreds of books have been authored by Thoughtworkers, reflecting a culture rooted in thought leadership, learning, and knowledge sharing.
As part of this vibrant thought-sharing community, I recently had the privilege of launching my book 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger than Life at the Thoughtworks office and signing copies for colleagues. The moment was special—not just because it was a book launch, but because it was about sharing timeless life lessons and inspirations drawn from the life of my great-grandfather, lessons that feel especially relevant in today’s fast-paced world.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker | Gatherverse Book Summit 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-booksummit-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gatherverse-booksummit-2025/</guid>
            <description>📢 Gatherverse Book Summit 2025: Exploring Books, Language and Meaning in the Age of New Technology.
 In the intersection of emerging technologies and humanity, this GatherVerse event aims to deep dive into the current and future state of books in an age defined by artificial intelligence. This is a space for authors, researchers, engineers, ethicists, educators, publishers, technologists and readers. We explore what it means to write, publish, and trust books in a time where machine-generated language is flooding the landscape</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Available Now! Jagjeevan : Living Larger than Life</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-avaiable-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-avaiable-now/</guid>
            <description>📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life is a heartfelt tribute to the extraordinary life and timeless wisdom of Shri Jagguram—an enlightened soul whose values shaped generations. Blending personal memories with profound life lessons, it captures the essence of a man who lived with humility, discipline, compassion, and unwavering purpose.
 Through ten insightful chapters, the book explores heritage, resilience, responsibility, inner strength, family unity, conflict resolution, gratitude, and the power of one’s actions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Coming Soon! Jagjeevan : Living Larger than Life</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-coming-soon/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/jagjeevan-coming-soon/</guid>
            <description>Life teaches us lessons every single moment—but only when we pause to reflect do we truly grow. Everyone faces challenges; no life is free from problems. What defines us is not the struggle, but how we rise above it.
 Most challenges we encounter today are the same ones our previous generations faced—whether they relate to daily life, relationships, earning, spending, or navigating responsibilities. So much wisdom already exists around us, in our homes, in our traditions, in the stories of our elders.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Books</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/books/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/about/books/</guid>
            <description>📕 Jagjeevan  Living Larger than Life 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life is a heartfelt tribute to the extraordinary life and timeless wisdom of Shri Jagguram—an enlightened soul whose values shaped generations. Blending personal memories with profound life lessons, it captures the essence of a man who lived with humility, discipline, compassion, and unwavering purpose.
 Through ten insightful chapters, the book explores heritage, resilience, responsibility, inner strength, family unity, conflict resolution, gratitude, and the power of one’s actions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My thoughtworkings from five thoughtful years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/five-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/five-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks is celebrating its 30th year in industry, and I have completed five years here, and to celebrate this, I have compiled thoughts from thoughtworkers, and published them as an ebook. I am grateful for the wealth of knowledge and experiences shared by my colleagues. These thoughts have resonated with me and shaped my journey within the organization and life.
I am excited to launch the ebook with this post. I believe this compilation of thoughts will not only serve as a personal reflection but also as a valuable resource for others on their own professional journeys.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>