<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>evolution on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in evolution on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Agility Today Fest 2023 - Generative AI and XR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/agiletoday_2023_ael/</guid>
      <description>Agility Today is a 2 days annual UnConference, to meet Agility needs of industry, gathered over past few years via meetups, Conferences and Webinar. This UnConference intends to give you best of Agile Psyche (Mindset Culture and Practice) and Geekery (Engineering, Tools and DevOps). This year in Agility Today Fest 2023 there are couple of programs.
I am speaking to at Agile Engineering Lab (Technical Agility &amp;amp; Engineering Excellence), on topic of Scaling content generation for XR using AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Assisted Content Generation Pipeline for XR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-generated-xr-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-generated-xr-content/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I and Raju Kandaswamy talked at Thoughtworks XConf on how AI will play its role in content generation. We are already seeing ChatGPT, as the next revolution in textual content generation space. Let&amp;rsquo;s understand what is the need of such content generation revolution of XR space.
With games like Second Life and the impending mainstreaming of the Metaverse, more and more individuals are embracing a virtual reality that, in some ways, mirrors our own real world and, in other ways, lets us live in our imagination or apply them on the real word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaverse — a technological evolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days. In most of my sessions people ask what is the technology stack for Metaverse? what should I learn to stay relevant? etc.. I will try to cover it in this article. In my earlier article I tried to define the Metaverse, and my friend Vinodh Arumugam also attempted the same here. It is defined so loosely that every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suits their narrative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Technology and User Interactions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/evolution_of_technology_and_user_interactions/</guid>
      <description>Technology defines our interactions with the ambiance, and the way we want to interact with the ambiance further defines the technology. The evolution of technology and user interactions tightly depends on each other.
 &amp;ldquo;Walls have ears!&amp;rdquo;, is very much true today, and not just that, now the walls can see you, feel your presence and talk to you.
 In this post, we will discuss how the user interactions evolved with time and what is next!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
