<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>policy on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/policy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in policy on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 23:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Getherverse Virtual World Symposium 2024</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-virtual-world-symposium/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-virtual-world-symposium/</guid>
            <description>📢 Virtual World Symposium: Join us as we dive deep into the future of AI-powered virtual worlds.
 What are they? Where are they headed? And why is it crucial to discuss these transformative spaces today?
 This symposium will also unpack spatial intelligence and its role in defining and enhancing immersive environments. As we step into a new era of digital interaction, this event will provide insights into the challenges and opportunities that virtual worlds bring to society.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Gatherverse XREvolve Summit 2024</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/gatherverse-xrevolve-summit/</guid>
            <description>XREvolve Summit serves a comprehensive platform for exploring the latest advancements, applications, applied sciences and progresses within AR, VR, and the broader domains of the metaverse such as spatial computing and mixed reality. It is backed by Gatherverse community, that advocates humanity-first standards in accessibility, education, equality, community development, safety &amp;amp; privacy, wellness, and ethics within the metaverse and emerging technologies.
This year&amp;rsquo;s focus is XR : Interface of AI, that open up the extraordinary and near limitless possibilities for humanity.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MIPS kick off event, XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse India Policy and Standards (MIPS) is a pioneering initiative led by Experiential Technology Innovation Centre (XTIC), serving as India’s premier research and product innovation hub for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics, hosted at IIT Madras.
It&amp;rsquo;s an honor to be the member of MIPS and showcase my book Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age, which aligns closely with the initiative&amp;rsquo;s objectives.
I extend my gratitude to Thriveni Palanivelu for orchestrating a seamless event.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>