<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mentor on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/mentor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mentor on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/mentor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentor - Nasscom COE IOT and AI - MIC 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-iotcoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nasscom-iotcoe/</guid>
      <description>NASSCOM is the premier trade body and chamber of commerce of the Tech industry in India and comprises over 2800 member companies including both Indian and multinational organisations that have a presence in India. Center of Excellence - IoT and AI is an initiative from NASSCOM and collective effort from different state governments in India,
NASSCOM is organizing Manufacturing Innovation Challenge 2020 from 12th Oct to 11th Dec, on theme of redefining enterprises and entrepreneurs engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Learning Equation</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</guid>
      <description>Today, The world is celebrating teacher’s day. I wish Happy Teacher&amp;rsquo;s day to all of us! We all are teachers and learners as every one of us has something to learn from others and something to teach others. I am thinking of an equation of learning that defines my way of learning and hope it would be helpful for you too.  The learning equation — Learning is proportional to Sharing; Learning ∝ Sharing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</guid>
      <description>After a wonderful experience of participating as a judge and mentor at Smart India Hackathon 2019, I am delighted to share that I again got a chance to meet and judge India&amp;rsquo;s young winners and innovators at Grand Finale of Smart India Hackathon 2020, world’s biggest open innovation modal, organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. This time it is no more a hackathon but a hackathon of hackathons — 4 Lacks students, 1500 small hackathons, 40 Nodal centers, around 2000 mentors and 1000 evaluators, 11000 finalists and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2019</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</guid>
      <description>Recently got a chance to judge and mentor india&amp;rsquo;s young innovators at Smart India Hackathon 2019, world&amp;rsquo;s largest hackathon with 11000 shortlisted participants, hosted by 48 centers across India. It was organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. I was invited to Judge the event at Panipat Institute of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology, Panipat. I am delighted to contribute in the journey of India&amp;rsquo;s transformation, and see innovative ideas from the new generation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>