<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>vrara on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/vrara/</link>
        <description>Recent content in vrara on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/vrara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Livestreaming</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/streaming/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/streaming/</guid>
            <description>XR in practice: the engineering challenges of extending reality Thoughtworks Podcast - ☞ More Details     AI Assisted Content Pipeline for XR Thoughtworks XConf 2022 - ☞ More Details      Using XR in building autonomous vehicles Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021 - ☞ More Details   &amp;nbsp;    The Shift from Enterprise XR to Ethical XR Thoughtworks XConf 2021 - ☞ More Details     Navigating the new normal The VRARA - ☞ More Details      eXtended Reality for Enterprise XROM Podcast - ☞ More Details     XR - Nicety to Necessity Techgig Webinars - ☞ More Details      How to get started with AR VR?</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Discussion - Navigating the new normal</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-navigating-new-normal/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-navigating-new-normal/</guid>
            <description>The world is finding the ways to get out of Covid impact, some are on recovery path and some are still bettling it. At ThoughtWorks, we have recently published our insights on navigating the new normal with augmented reality. Members of Communities of Practice of The VRARA come together to discuss the topic and share the opinion on way forward for XR.
I presented thoughtworks insights to other renowned industry leaders and VRARA members like Pradeep Sharma, Swarup Choudhury and Rajiv Madane, and technology exports like Pradeep Naik and Dhruv.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Webinar - Essentials of XR Product Design and Development</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</guid>
            <description>The VRAR Association&amp;rsquo;s Product Design and Development (PDD) Communities of Practice (COP) brings its first webinar on &amp;ldquo;Essentials of XR Product Design and Development&amp;rdquo;.
I will be sharing the stage with industry leader Mr. Pradeep Khanna, VR AR Association, and XR innovator Mr. Raju Kandaswamy, ThoughtWorks.
Spread the words  Registration Only Please register at the below link, and save the date Oct 17, 2020, 4:30 PM IST.
https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/14711/445904
The webinar will be available at https://www.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>