<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>5G on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/5g/</link>
        <description>Recent content in 5G on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/5g/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Generative XR – Space aware AI bringing new era of immersion</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/generative-xr-space-aware-ai-bringing-new-era-of-immersion/</guid>
            <description>Artificial Intelligence has made significant strides with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs) or Generative AI, which are trained to understand and respond to human language naturally. Tools like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google’s Gemini, and Microsoft’s Co-pilot have become the go-to resources for &amp;ldquo;Ask me anything&amp;rdquo; queries. These innovations have been touted as potential Google Search Killer, disrupting the way we search for information, communicate with machines, and receive machine responses.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
            <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse — a technological evolution</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/metaverse-a-technological-evolution/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse is the most talked, understood and misunderstood topic these days. In most of my sessions people ask what is the technology stack for Metaverse? what should I learn to stay relevant? etc.. I will try to cover it in this article. In my earlier article I tried to define the Metaverse, and my friend Vinodh Arumugam also attempted the same here. It is defined so loosely that every other industry today is trying to define it in their own way to suits their narrative.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>eXtended Reality for Enterprise - a PODCast by XROM</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xrom-podcast-enterprise-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xrom-podcast-enterprise-xr/</guid>
            <description>Interesting conversation on eXtended Reality (XR) with Eddie Avil, starting from my background, how I landed up in the XR space and where are we heading…
XROM PODCast XROM PODCast is a youtube channel maintained by serial entrepreneur, dreamer &amp;amp; a believer Mr. Eddie Avil. This channel has number of interesting conversations with industry leaders in the emerging technology space. Eddie Avil, also runs a marketplace for AR VR hardware and service, visit here https://www.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>