<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>habit on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/habit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in habit on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/habit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Greening Up: Key takeaways from Green Software Foundation Meetup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/green-software-foundation-meetup-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/green-software-foundation-meetup-2023/</guid>
      <description>As technology continues to advance, electronics are getting smaller and wires are disappearing. Even electric poles, once a familiar sight on road trips, are being phased out. With the internet now ubiquitous, physical storage devices are disappearing too, and we rely more on cloud-based solutions that seem to happen over the air.
 ‘It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder we look up when we think of clouds ☁️, but should actually look down to the earth in the mines!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit Matters - The change is a side effect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/habitmatters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/habitmatters/</guid>
      <description>“Change is the only constant, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether we like it or not, it takes place”- shared and reflected in my change stories.
 Over the years, I have been following my theory of change Accept-Observe-Absorb. It helped me to traverse through the change year 2020, and understand the role of “Will” and how to cultivate it. I shared how just one change “working from my native home” brought so many other changes in lifestyle and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
