<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate lessons from a Home Makeover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</guid>
      <description>Recently I shared an article on my life lessons from my father’s work life, and mentioned that I dedicated a new home to my father’s work life, also promised that I will share some corporate lessons learned from making-over this new home. I can well relate my takeaways to the corporate experiences such as vendor selection, negotiation, solutioning, estimation, prioritization, agility and being a trusted partner and many more..
 As I keep saying “we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons of Life - Father’s Retirement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</guid>
      <description>I started thinkuldeep.com keeping in mind that we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad. Our learning matures by sharing, we explore more of us by giving it away to others.
 Recently my father turned 60, and has retired from government services. 60 years full of life is a quite big experience, where around 38 years he spent in serving the same Govt of Rajasthan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My impactful change stories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/my-impactful-change-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/my-impactful-change-stories/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have been invited to share my 3 years Thoughtworks Journey, at “Impact Series” by Social Change Group TW, India.
 &amp;ldquo;Striving for positive social change is at the heart of our purpose, culture and work&amp;rdquo; — /thoughtworks
 I believe an impactful change is the change that changes you, and any social change start from within, our own journey. I shared my change journey, and received number of comments, and feedbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Thoughtful Years!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/two-thoughtful-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/two-thoughtful-years/</guid>
      <description>It’s now two years since I accepted a challenging change to leave the previous organization after 13 long years, and join ThoughtWorks. Any change requires sacrifices and dedication before it becomes a positive change, but the journey becomes easy when we believe in the change and accept it. A change introduces us to a new environment and enables new thoughts, and new energy. The two years journey at ThoughtWorks is no different.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
