<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>reflection on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/reflection/</link>
        <description>Recent content in reflection on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Testing the Ground: Reflections on 2024 and the Road Ahead for 2025</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2024-reflections-2025-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we bid farewell to 2024 and welcome 2025, it&amp;rsquo;s a time to reflect on the lessons learned, both good and challenging, and prepare for the opportunities ahead. Not everything went as planned, but each experience has been a stepping stone toward growth. Intelligence, after all, evolves through adaptation, and 2024 was undeniably a year where Artificial Intelligence (AI) took center stage.
Looking ahead, 2025 promises to bring more focused implementation, balancing AI advancements with broader digital modernization efforts.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture: AI and Metaverse reshaping the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</guid>
            <description>AI is pervasive, whether we sense it or not. Staying updated has become essential for survival. We are increasingly immersed in artificially generated worlds, with the internet rapidly evolving into what is known as the metaverse. In my book, &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, I delve into its various forms and interpretations, usecases and challenges, and the way forward.
DesignersX, a company specializing in software development, invited me to speak about my book and discuss how AI and the metaverse will shape the future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Being inclusive, being me</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/being-inclusive-being-me/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/being-inclusive-being-me/</guid>
            <description>🙋‍ ️As International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day is celebrated worldwide, efforts are underway to recognize women&amp;rsquo;s representation across diverse fields. In India, the spirit of &amp;lsquo;Nari Shakti&amp;rsquo; is alive as discussions focus on various schemes and initiatives. Increased enforcement is advocating for equal opportunities in underrepresented sectors. The promising shift towards inclusivity is shaping a future grounded in equity and equality.
👩‍💻 Thoughtworks is synonymous with diversity and inclusion, a leading brand in this space.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Foundational shifts: Reflecting on 2023 and anticipating ahead</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2023-reflections-2024-anticipation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/2023-reflections-2024-anticipation/</guid>
            <description>As we say goodbye to 2023 and welcome 2024, it&amp;rsquo;s a time to think about the good and tough parts of the year. Not everything goes the way we want, but we can learn from both the good and bad experiences. I see 2023 as a year of making things better, like fixing the base of a building. I&amp;rsquo;ve picked my top five observations on foundational changes from this year, and some might continue into 2024.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My thoughtworkings from five thoughtful years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/five-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/five-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks is celebrating its 30th year in industry, and I have completed five years here, and to celebrate this, I have compiled thoughts from thoughtworkers, and published them as an ebook. I am grateful for the wealth of knowledge and experiences shared by my colleagues. These thoughts have resonated with me and shaped my journey within the organization and life.
I am excited to launch the ebook with this post. I believe this compilation of thoughts will not only serve as a personal reflection but also as a valuable resource for others on their own professional journeys.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
            <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Corporate lessons from a Home Makeover</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/corporate-lessons-from-a-home-makeover/</guid>
            <description>Recently I shared an article on my life lessons from my father’s work life, and mentioned that I dedicated a new home to my father’s work life, also promised that I will share some corporate lessons learned from making-over this new home. I can well relate my takeaways to the corporate experiences such as vendor selection, negotiation, solutioning, estimation, prioritization, agility and being a trusted partner and many more..
 As I keep saying “we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad”</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lessons of Life - Father’s Retirement</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/lessons-of-life-father-retirement/</guid>
            <description>I started thinkuldeep.com keeping in mind that we learn every day in all situations of life, good or bad. Our learning matures by sharing, we explore more of us by giving it away to others.
 Recently my father turned 60, and has retired from government services. 60 years full of life is a quite big experience, where around 38 years he spent in serving the same Govt of Rajasthan.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My impactful change stories</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/my-impactful-change-stories/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/my-impactful-change-stories/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I have been invited to share my 3 years Thoughtworks Journey, at “Impact Series” by Social Change Group TW, India.
 &amp;ldquo;Striving for positive social change is at the heart of our purpose, culture and work&amp;rdquo; — /thoughtworks
 I believe an impactful change is the change that changes you, and any social change start from within, our own journey. I shared my change journey, and received number of comments, and feedbacks.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two Thoughtful Years!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/two-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/two-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>It’s now two years since I accepted a challenging change to leave the previous organization after 13 long years, and join ThoughtWorks. Any change requires sacrifices and dedication before it becomes a positive change, but the journey becomes easy when we believe in the change and accept it. A change introduces us to a new environment and enables new thoughts, and new energy. The two years journey at ThoughtWorks is no different.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>