<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>SDK on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/sdk/</link>
        <description>Recent content in SDK on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>nRF Connect SDK Advanced Practices</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk-advanced/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk-advanced/</guid>
            <description>In our previous article, we provided a brief overview of the nRF Connect SDK and demonstrated how to build a simple application. This article explores advanced practices for working with the nRF Connect SDK, focusing on Zephyr OS internals, including timers, schedulers, bootloading, DFU, and FOTA concepts. It builds on our previous introduction to the nRF Connect SDK and provides insights into developing multi-threaded firmware, troubleshooting, and deploying firmware over the air (OTA).</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Implementing a Joiner in nRF Connect SDK</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-joiner-implementation/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-thread-joiner-implementation/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how a Commissioner node provisions a Joiner in a Thread network using OpenThread&amp;rsquo;s default firmware. However, in real-world applications, custom firmware logic is often required, along with programmatic control over the commissioning process. In this article, we will implement a Joiner using the nRF Connect SDK, following these four key steps.
Joiner in Action The Joiner process involves the following steps:
 Enable Thread – Ensure that the Thread network and IPv6 are enabled.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting Started with Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE)</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-ble/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-ble/</guid>
            <description>In a previous article, we explored how to build IoT firmware applications using the nRF Connect SDK. We examined its project structure and learned how to build and flash firmware on the nRF52840 dongle. If you missed it, you can catch up here:
For more hands-on practices, use nRF52840 Development Kit (DK), that offers advanced developer features. You need to connect this board via a high-speed data cable like this one, to get it detected on your PC.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Getting Started with nRF Connect SDK</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-nrf-connect-sdk/</guid>
            <description>In the previous article, we explored setting up a Thread Network and enabling communication within and outside the network via a Border Router using OpenThread and the nRF Connect SDK. While we covered installing and configuring the SDK during the setup, we didn’t dive into the development process for nRF Connect SDK Apps. Let’s address that now!
What We’ll Cover This article introduces the nRF Connect SDK and walks through building applications with it.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>