<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>internet of things on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/internet-of-things/</link>
    <description>Recent content in internet of things on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/internet-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IOT 101: A primer on Internet of Things</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot_simplified/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot_simplified/</guid>
      <description>IOT 101 A Primer on Internet of Things  from Kuldeep Singh  The IoT can be described as “Connecting the Things to internet”.
A comprehensive IoT ecosystem consists of many different parts such as electronic circuitry, sensing and acting capability, embedded systems, edge computing, network protocols, communication networks, cloud computing, big data management and analytics, business rules etcetera. This maze of varied parts can be better classified into 4 broad categories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another IoT Disruption: A Need of Multi-Skilled Devs</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/iot-disruption-multi-skilled-people/</guid>
      <description>Technological evolution causes disruption. It replaces traditional, less optimal, complex, lengthy, and costly technology, people, and processes with economical, innovative, optimal, and simpler alternatives. We have seen disruption by mobile phones, and up next is disruption from IoT, wearables, AR-VR, machine Learning, AI, and other innovations. Software development methodology, tools, and people will also face disruption. I expect that the traditional developer will be replaced by the multi-skilled or full-stack developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Steps of the IoT race</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/5-steps-of-the-iot-race/</guid>
      <description>The ‘Internet of Things’ (IoT) presents tremendous opportunity in all the industry verticals and business domains. Specifically, the ‘Industrial Internet of Things’(IIoT) promises to increase the value proposition by making self-optimizing business processes. As discussed in the post “The Driving Forces Behind IoT”, there are several challenges to be addressed to realize the full IoT potentials, but following steps will help organization to systemically make their products participate in the IoT journey and stay in the IoT race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Driving Forces Behind IoT</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/the-driving-forces-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/the-driving-forces-iot/</guid>
      <description>Everybody in the software industry is talking about IoT in terms of billions of devices, their growth in coming years, changing business models, and adaptation of the IoT in the market. Connecting the things has become so prevalent nowadays, that every software company wants to expand in IoT by building IoT-centric products and services.
There are many industrial applications which connect to sensors and actuators, and can be controlled remotely. They have been around for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>