<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mr on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/mr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mr on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/mr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-2/</guid>
      <description>In Part I of the article, we summarized our observations of eXtended reality’s foundational blocks - AR, VR and MR. We also discussed the popular and most relevant tools and implementations of the new technology. In Part II of the article, we will be looking at a few accessible and novel implementations of the tech.
At ThoughtWorks, we have delivered both XR solutions and components of XR SDK (Software Development Kit) on the back of which XR solutions are built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eXtending reality with AR and VR - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/extending_reality_with_ar_and_vr-1/</guid>
      <description>The way we interact with technology today is not too far from what was predicted by futuristic, sci-fi pop culture. We are living in a world where sophisticated touch and gesture based interactions are collaborating with state of the art wearables, sensors, Augmented Reality (AR), Virtual Reality (VR) and Mixed Reality (MR). And, this is eXtending user experiences to be extremely immersive.
Add to this, Gartner’s expectation that 5G and AR/VR implementation will transform not only customer engagement but brands’ entire product management cycles as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>