<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hackathon on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/hackathon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hackathon on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge -  Smart India Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih-2020/</guid>
      <description>After a wonderful experience of participating as a judge and mentor at Smart India Hackathon 2019, I am delighted to share that I again got chance to meet and judge india&amp;rsquo;s young innovators at Smart India Hackathon 2020, world&amp;rsquo;s largest virtual hackathon, organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. Happy to contribute in the journey of India&amp;rsquo;s transformation, and see innovative ideas from the new generation.
See you all at #GrandFinale #SIH2020 https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge - HackInIndia - Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/hackinindia-hackathon-2020/</guid>
      <description>I got chance to judge the HackInIndia event, India&amp;rsquo;s National Level hackathon organized by Script Foundation on 2nd July, 2020.
Around 150 teams signed up across multiple tracks (Healthcare, Open Innovation, ARVR, EdTech, RPA and FinTech) supported by couple of talented mentors. I and Raviraj Subramanian got chance to meet only top 20 teams in Jury round, and I was amazed to see their innovative ideas, and demonstrations the young blood of nation bring on the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge and Mentor -  Smart India Hackathon 2019</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/sih_2019_an_experience/</guid>
      <description>Recently got a chance to judge and mentor india&amp;rsquo;s young innovators at Smart India Hackathon 2019, world&amp;rsquo;s largest hackathon with 11000 shortlisted participants, hosted by 48 centers across India. It was organized by AICTE and MHRD, Govt of India. I was invited to Judge the event at Panipat Institute of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology, Panipat. I am delighted to contribute in the journey of India&amp;rsquo;s transformation, and see innovative ideas from the new generation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>