<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>future on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/future/</link>
        <description>Recent content in future on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Thoughtworks&#39; Looking Glass 2024 - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/thougthworks-looking-glass-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/thougthworks-looking-glass-2024/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks unveils its latest tech trends report, &amp;lsquo;Looking Glass&amp;rsquo;, a comprehensive analysis of emerging technologies designed to empower organizations and leaders in making informed decisions. The 2024 edition of report, covering over 100 trends, is segmented through five lenses, each offering insights, signals, and strategic recommendations for adoption, analysis, and anticipation.
Key takeaways: Here are my key takeaways:
 AI&amp;rsquo;s ubiquitous reach - AI is going in every facet of technology, from conversational interfaces to AI-assisted software development and software-defined vehicles.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The future of shopping</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/future-of-shoping/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/future-of-shoping/</guid>
            <description>eXtended Reality (XR) that includes AR and VR technologies have been silently disrupting the gaming industry for more than a decade. In the recent past, the tech has gained some traction in the education and training space.
Today, however, COVID-19 with its mandates of social distancing and less to no physical interactions has accelerated adoption for XR. The tech is virtual, contactless, and delivers outstanding brand experiences - perfect for the new normal that multiple industries like retail will benefit from.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>