<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workshop on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workshop on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leadership - A result of conscious and continuous effort!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/leadership-development-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/leadership-development-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>Sep 2020, a year ago, I was excited for getting nominated for an year long Global Leadership Development Program at Thoughtworks. At the same time was little confused on what we are going to do in this program for that long. I must say it was so well executed, despite the challenges of Covid#19, where we all(participants, speakers, coaches and other enablers) are globally distributed working from their home. Expectations were set, virtual meetings were set with options to attend at per individual comfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching is not what you think!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/coaching-workshop-key-takaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/coaching-workshop-key-takaways/</guid>
      <description>When the word “Coaching” comes into my mind, one name always pops up, the cricket legend Sachin Tendulkar and his coach Mr. Ramakant Achrekar who gave him cricket. This example also helps us break the myths that coaching is needed when there are performance issues or people who are under-performing need the most.
Sachin Tendulkar with his coach — Source
If Sachin Tendulkar needs a coach then we all need a coach in our life to get going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - AT2020 - Agility in Enterprise XR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/at_2020_agilexr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/at_2020_agilexr/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise XR is gaining good traction, and software development’s best practices like Agile principles really matters due to multitude of tooling and tech stacks used for Enterprise XR solutions
Enterprises do face multiple challenges with the XR development lifecycle. One of them is the automation of testing XR applications. In response to this gap, ThoughtWorks has developed Arium – an open-source, lightweight, extensible, platform-agnostic framework that helps write automation tests that are built specifically for XR Applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception Workshop | Key Takeaways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/inception_workshop_key_takaways/</guid>
      <description>Inception exercise is very common in software development, where we gather the business requirements and define the delivery plan for the MVP(Minimum Viable Product) on a shared understanding. There are a set of tools and practices available to define the MVP requirements and its delivery plan. Famous tools are Lean Value Tree, Business Model Canvas, Plane Map, Elevator Pitch, Futurespective, Empathy Maps, Value Proposition Canvas, User Journey Map, Gamestorming, Process Diagram, MoSCoW, Communication Plan, Project Plan etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
