<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>business on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/business/</link>
        <description>Recent content in business on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit 2024, IIT Madras - Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/xr-summit-2024-takeaways/</guid>
            <description>I recently had the privilege of attending XR Summit 2024 at the eXperiential Technology Innovation Center (XTIC), IIT Madras. My heartfelt thanks to Prof. Mani and his team for the kind invitation and to Thoughtworks for making all the arrangements seamless.
The event was nothing short of extraordinary – a world-class summit showcasing groundbreaking advancements, with an exciting lineup of sessions led by industry pioneers and academics. The topics covered were diverse, thought-provoking, and visionary.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>XR Summit and AWE Nite | XR with AI, Gaming, AVGC</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-summit-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/xr-summit-2024/</guid>
            <description>🚀 Excited to announce that I’ll be part of the XR Summit 2024 hosted by XTIC, IIT Madras, a hub for driving innovation in XR technologies in India! 🌟
IIT Madras, with its state-of-the-art Haptics Lab and the IoE Center for VR and Haptics, supported by the CAVE consortium (via XTIC.org), is at the forefront of advancing experiential technologies. This summit will bring together key stakeholders, industry leaders, and visionaries to shape the future of XR.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Exploring the Metaverse is OUR NEXT REALITY - AWE Asia Day 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day2/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of the Augmented World Expo (AWE), serving as a crucial platform to unite leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to drive the growth of the XR market in Asia.
After an exciting Day 1 at AWE Asia 2024, I’m thrilled to share my key takeaways from Day 2, where both I and my fellow Thoughtworker Arijit had the opportunity to present as speakers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AWE Asia | AI-Powered Real-Time Adaptation in XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/aweasia-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/aweasia-2024/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading AR/VR expo after more than 10 years of dedication, development, and high-quality events. AWE organizes three annual events (USA, Asia, EU) and holds a number of other sessions all over the world. AWE Asia is an opportunity to bring together outstanding XR companies, investors, and other international stakeholders in Asia to promote the development of the local XR market.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI ❤️ XR - AWE Asia Day 1 Takeaways</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/aweasia-2024-day1/</guid>
            <description>AWE Asia is a flagship event of AWE(Augmented World Expo), often dubbed as “XR’s Most Essential Conference” and “The XR Conference for Everyone”. With three major annual events in the USA, Asia, and Europe, along with numerous other sessions worldwide, AWE Asia is a prime opportunity to bring together leading XR companies, investors, and international stakeholders to accelerate the growth of the XR market in Asia.
This year, I had the privilege of attending the event in Singapore in person as a speaker.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Harnessing Business Opportunity with AI Powered XR</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ai-powered-xr/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/ai-powered-xr/</guid>
            <description>In a world where AI is ubiquitous, technologies like AR, VR, and XR often raise eyebrows, despite their vast potential. AI is not only propelling these technologies forward but also preparing them for the next stages of development. There are tremendous opportunities to leverage their potential for business transformation. I am honored to be invited by Express Computers - India Leading IT Magazine, to speak on this topic and dispel common myths.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>