<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>speaker on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/speaker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in speaker on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/speaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Thoughtworks MasterClass-2021</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks-masterclasses-2021/</guid>
      <description>The MasterClass This October, at Thoughtworks India, we’re celebrating our 20th anniversary! That’s 20 years of excellence in technology!
 All through the month we’re hosting 10 tech talks, delivered by some of our best-and-brightest technologists in India. Each of them will be taking you through different topics, ranging from Distributed Delivery and XR, to Security and Navigating Ambiguity.
I am sharing stage with Raju Kandaswamy who is a robotics enthusiast and taking us through &amp;ldquo;Using XR in building autonomous vehicles&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - XConf-2021 - Thoughtworks India</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks-xconf-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks-xconf-2021/</guid>
      <description>The XConf XConf is Thoughtworks annual technology event created by technologists. It is designed for technologists who care deeply about software and its impact on the world.
This year, XConf will be a virtual experience available at two different time slots. October 7th and 8th will feature pre-recorded sessions and October 9th will feature live sessions. During the nine exciting talks spread across three days.
 I am exited to sharing the stage with renowned technologists like Neal Ford, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion - Navigating the new normal</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thevrara-navigating-new-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thevrara-navigating-new-normal/</guid>
      <description>The world is finding the ways to get out of Covid impact, some are on recovery path and some are still bettling it. At ThoughtWorks, we have recently published our insights on navigating the new normal with augmented reality. Members of Communities of Practice of The VRARA come together to discuss the topic and share the opinion on way forward for XR.
I presented thoughtworks insights to other renowned industry leaders and VRARA members like Pradeep Sharma, Swarup Choudhury and Rajiv Madane, and technology exports like Pradeep Naik and Dhruv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - AT2020 - Agility in Enterprise XR</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/at_2020_agilexr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/at_2020_agilexr/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise XR is gaining good traction, and software development’s best practices like Agile principles really matters due to multitude of tooling and tech stacks used for Enterprise XR solutions
Enterprises do face multiple challenges with the XR development lifecycle. One of them is the automation of testing XR applications. In response to this gap, ThoughtWorks has developed Arium – an open-source, lightweight, extensible, platform-agnostic framework that helps write automation tests that are built specifically for XR Applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - GIDS - Extended Machine Learning with XR</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gids_2020_xr4ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 06:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gids_2020_xr4ml/</guid>
      <description>Extended Reality is not only meant for humans, they can very well serve machines by producing Digital twins. Digital twins encapsulate real world elements with all important physics characteristics enabling the researcher to produce large volume of training data needed for reinforment learning and CNN based deep learning algorithms. Extended Reality environments are mature today and are capable of producing photorealistic rendering and physics emulation of real world just by using digital twins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar - Essentials of XR Product Design and Development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thevrara-ppd-cop-webinar/</guid>
      <description>The VRAR Association&amp;rsquo;s Product Design and Development (PDD) Communities of Practice (COP) brings its first webinar on &amp;ldquo;Essentials of XR Product Design and Development&amp;rdquo;.
I will be sharing the stage with industry leader Mr. Pradeep Khanna, VR AR Association, and XR innovator Mr. Raju Kandaswamy, ThoughtWorks.
Spread the words  Registration Only Please register at the below link, and save the date Oct 17, 2020, 4:30 PM IST.
https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/14711/445904
The webinar will be available at https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geeknight - XR - eXtending the Reality</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_geeknight_sep_2020_xr/</guid>
      <description>Geek Night is a regular event to promote the sharing of technical knowledge and increase collaboration among the geeks. It is organized by a passionate group of programmers and sponsored by ThoughtWorks.
Sep month&amp;rsquo;s geek night has covered Extended Reality - An umbrella term covering various technologies like AR,VR and MR. I will be discussing what is XR, its usage and significance today, that is stretching beyond gaming.
Embracing an Agile approach is essential to any successful XR implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webinar - XR - Nicety to Necessity</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/techgigs-xr-webinar-1/</guid>
      <description>Techgig is the largest community of developers, also organizes webinars on emerging technologies.
I have spoken at a webinar on Extended Reality (XR) - Moving from Nicety to Necessity on coming Aug 13, at 3PM IST.
Join @thinkuldeep, Head- ARVR Practice, #ThoughtWorksIndia, for a webinar on &amp;quot;why XR is moving from nicety to necessity in the new normal?&amp;quot;
Registrations are now open: https://t.co/IHcOpLgLXZ@techgigdotcom #ExtendedReality #ThoughtWorks pic.twitter.com/MCf7EcWSjV
&amp;mdash; ThoughtWorks India (@thoughtworksIN) August 11, 2020  Highlights COVID-19 has impacted economies, businesses and human behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here LinkedIn
Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Spatial Web - Life beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/gids_2020_blr_spatialweb/</guid>
      <description>New Date is still to be announced.
Get ready: Great International Developer Summit is re-scheduled and now virtual summit will be organized.
Come and talk about the life beyond keyboard and screens, spatial web is taking over get ready&amp;hellip;
The talk is about Spatial Web is an umbrella term for the next generation web technologies that will transform every aspect of our life. It will connect the human and machines seamlessly such that the difference between physical and virtual will disappear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - XR Day - ThoughtWorks India</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_xrday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_xrday/</guid>
      <description>The XR Day Organized XR Days at ThoughtWorks, India in different cities and conducted awareness sessions and ideation workshop and more..
The talks are about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen xr day 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Event Summary It was well recevied the participats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - AwayDay 2019 - SLAM Aware Applications</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/thougthworks_awayday_2019_slam_aware_apps/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Thoutworks&amp;rsquo;s Awayday 2019, where the entire ThoughtWorks India travelled to celebrate togetherness.
I and my colleague Raju Kandaswamy presented this talk in the breakout sessions in category Seismic Shifts Around 2000 Thoghtworkers get together, and enjoyed fusion of technology showcases, cultural event and more. Glimpse here
 The talk is about  What is SLAM (Simultaneous Localization And Mapping)? The use cases of SLAM? How does it work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - Google Devfest 2019 - Think Beyond Keyboard and Screen</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/google_devfest_2019_think_beyond_keyboard_and_screen/</guid>
      <description>Presented At : Google DevFest 2019, by Google Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group, GDG Cloud Delhi .
The talks is about  How the User interactions evolved with time? Why is it important to think beyond the tradition keyboard and screen? Where is the industry heading? How will it impact us?  Intro here LinkedIn
We have built office-explorer #DevFest2019 pic.twitter.com/0yRz7Euo8J
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@thinkuldeep) September 10, 2019  Detailed Slides   Think beyond keyboard and screen - dev fest 2019  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback It was well recevied the participats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
      <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panelist &amp; Organizer - Nagarro LSD - Industry 4.0</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nagarro-lsd-industory-4-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/nagarro-lsd-industory-4-0/</guid>
      <description>Organized Nagarro LSD event, on Industry 4.0, demonstrated usecases on connected services concept, and was a panelist for a discussion on
 Smarter Services - Predictive, Always Connected, Personalized Global experts will debate ways to create smarter services based around predictive maintenance, always connected devices and personalized solutions.
 Whether we call Industry 4.0 an evolution or a revolution, there is little doubt that it will have a disruptive impact on the manufacturing industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>