<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>paper on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/paper/</link>
        <description>Recent content in paper on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Patents and Papers</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/patents/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/patents/</guid>
            <description>This listing includes patent applications that are pending as well as patents that have already been granted by the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO). It also includes the papers published in various conferences and journals.
 ITU-T Technical Report - Potential requirements of IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System ITU-T Study Group 20 accepted my recommendation as a Technical Report. It defines key layers for IoT-based retail monitoring systems — including Sensing, Communication, Integration, Application &amp;amp; Analytics, and Management &amp;amp; Maintenance layers.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>ITU-T Technical Report - IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/itu-t-sg20-2025/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/itu-t-sg20-2025/</guid>
            <description>Recently, I had the privilege of representing 🇮🇳 India at the International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) Study Group 20 (SG20) meeting in Geneva.
I’m pleased to share that my recommendations for standardizing requirements for an IoT-based Perishable Goods Monitoring System has been accepted as an official Technical Report. Here’s a brief overview of the experience and its significance.
About ITU-T Study Group 20 The ITU-T is a global body that develops standards for telecommunications and ICT, bringing together governments, industry leaders, and academia.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>