<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>introduction on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/introduction/</link>
        <description>Recent content in introduction on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Lean2Lead tech track - Twisted realities</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lean2lead_xr_2023/</guid>
            <description>Lean2Lead is a network of women at work, with will to lead and succeed in their respective areas of work. They are 400+ women from different industries together in this group for exchange of ideas, connecting and coaching, building network with industry leaders and inspiring each other for building strategies for success in leadership and executive roles.
I am speaking at their tech session series, on 15 July 2023, 3-4 PM.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker - Google DSC - How to get started with AR VR?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/google_dsk_skct_xr_introduction/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a live session at Google Developer Students Club of Sri Krishna College of Technology, Coimbatore, TN, India
Intro here LinkedIn
Live session, recording.  The talks is about  What is AR VR? Why to start with AR VR? How to start with AR VR?  Detailed Slides   How to get started with arvr - DSC 2020  from Kuldeep Singh  Feedback  This session was really awesome and I have got lot of new knowledge about ar/vr and it&amp;rsquo;s importance in solving real life problems - Kannan Subramanian</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker &amp; Organizer - IOTNCR - Ideation to Production Workshop</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/iotncr-ideation-to-production/</guid>
            <description>Conducted a workshop on IoT with IOTNCR. I have spoken on IoT technology landscape, and many of other speaker given enlightening talks.
Intro here Nagarro invites IOT enthusiasts to Ideation to Production:An Entrepreneurship Workshop,Apr 29 #IOTNCR #Nagarroiotncr https://t.co/kvQi1CARjG pic.twitter.com/QbY94UId6c
&amp;mdash; Kuldeep Singh (@kuldeepwilldo) April 27, 2017  The talks is about  IOT fundamentals and building blocks  IOT Nodes IOT Gateway IOT Platforms Visualization (AR &amp;amp; VR) Integrations    Detailed Slides   IOT Landscape  from Kuldeep Singh  Social connect Nice to meet you all @Nagarro #iotncr #Nagarroiotncr @kanchanray @mfuloria pic.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>IOT 101: A primer on Internet of Things</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_simplified/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot_simplified/</guid>
            <description>IOT 101 A Primer on Internet of Things  from Kuldeep Singh  The IoT can be described as “Connecting the Things to internet”.
A comprehensive IoT ecosystem consists of many different parts such as electronic circuitry, sensing and acting capability, embedded systems, edge computing, network protocols, communication networks, cloud computing, big data management and analytics, business rules etcetera. This maze of varied parts can be better classified into 4 broad categories:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>SIGFOX - An Introduction</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/sigfox-an-introduction/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/sigfox-an-introduction/</guid>
            <description>SIGFOX is providing a communication solution dedicated to the Internet of Things
Dedicated to the IOT means:
 Simplicity: No configuration, no pairing, no signaling Autonomy: Very low energy consumption, allowing years of autonomy on battery without maintenance Small messages: No large assets or multimedia, only small messages  It is a LPWA (Low-Power Wide-Area) network, currently operating in 20 countries in Europe, Americas and Asia/Pacific. Communications over the SIGFOX network are bi-directional: uplink from device &amp;amp; downlink to the device.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introduction to Java Lambda Expression</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-lambda-expression/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-lambda-expression/</guid>
            <description>After Java 8, developers can apply functional programming constructs in a pure Object-Oriented programming language through lambda expressions. Using lambda expression sequential and parallel execution can be achieved by passing behavior into methods. In Java world lambdas can be thought of as an anonymous method with a more compact syntax. Here compact means it is not mandatory to specify access modifiers, return type and parameter types while defining the expression.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introduction to Java Stream API</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-stream-api/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/java8-stream-api/</guid>
            <description>Prior to JDK 8, collections can only be managed through iterators with the use of for, foreach or while loops. It means that we instruct a computer to execute the algorithm steps.
int sum(List&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt; list) {  Iterator&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt; intIterator = list.iterator();  int sum = 0;  while (intIterator.hasNext()) {  int number = intIterator.next();  if (number &amp;gt; 5) {  sum += number;  }  }  return sum; } The above approach has the following tailbacks:</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Groovy - Getting Started</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/groovy-getting-started/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/groovy-getting-started/</guid>
            <description>This article help you start with Groovy, with step by step guide and series of examples. It starts with an overview and then covers in detail examples.
Groovy Overview Groovy is an Object Oriented Scripting Language which provides Dynamic, Easy-to-use and Integration capabilities to the Java Virtual Machine. It absorbs most of the syntax from Java and it is much powerful in terms of functionalities which is manifested in the form Closures, Dynamic Typing, Builders etc.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Scala - Getting Started - Part 2</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part2/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part2/</guid>
            <description>In previous article we learned basics of Scala, in this articles we will learn how to setup build scripts for scala and build applications using scala.
We will also learn few web development frameworks for Scala and compare them with similar framework in Java.
Building Scala Applications Below program demonstrates the use of Scala script with Maven, Ant, and logging library – LogBack.
Integration with Ant Below example shows how Scala project can be built by the ant build.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Scala - Getting Started - Part 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/scala-getting-started-part1/</guid>
            <description>This article help you to start with Scala, with step by step guide and series of examples. It starts with an overview and then covers in detail examples. In later articles, I will write about feature comparison with other languages. It article is helpful for people coming from Java background, how it is not the prerequisites.
Scala Overview Scala is a general purpose programming language designed to express common programming patterns in a concise, elegant, and type-safe way.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Rule Engine - Getting Started with Drools</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/rule-engine-getting-started/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/rule-engine-getting-started/</guid>
            <description>This article let you start with Rule Engine Drools, with step by step guide and series of examples. It starts with an overview and then covers in detail examples.
Rule Engine Overview The underlying idea of a rule engine is to externalize the business or application logic. A rule engine can be viewed as a sophisticated interpreter of if-then statements. The if-then statements are the rules. A rule is composed of two parts, a condition and an action: When the condition is met, the action is executed.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>