<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>success on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in success on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.github.io/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Change to become more successful!</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/change_to_become_more_successful_/</guid>
      <description>Change is the only constant, it requires continuous effort from humankind to understand the change that leads to success, and make us even more successful. In my earlier article, I talked about the success mantra, and also wrote about accepting the change when required. Sometimes the way we perceive our success becomes a blocker for becoming more successful. We accumulate some habits knowingly or unknowingly along the path of being successful, and mostly we never realize that those habits start blocking our way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success Mantra</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/success_mantra_amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.github.io/post/success_mantra_amazon/</guid>
      <description>Everyone in India is talking about Jeff Bezos, the richest of the world, who was on India&amp;rsquo;s visit recently. People are talking about the investments he is making in India, talking about his prediction about India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;21st Century is going to be the Indian century&amp;rdquo;, and discussing the impact on small businesses. We have seen disruptions lead by Amazon in multiple sectors, now people have a fear that whatever Amazon touch, it becomes Amazon&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>