<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>collaboration on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/collaboration/</link>
        <description>Recent content in collaboration on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>DJXHack 2025 | Fostering Artificial Sense in the XR World</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/djxhack-fostering-artificial-sense-in-xr-world/</guid>
            <description>DJXHack 2025 was an inspiring hackathon organized by DJX Labs, attracting students and professionals from across institutions. Out of many applicants, 30 XR enthusiasts were shortlisted to participate and showcase innovative ideas in extended reality (XR).
I had the honor of being invited as a speaker, where I shared my thoughts on how AI is fostering artificial sense in the XR world. Grateful to be a part of such an impactful event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Why collaboration is essential for building a successful XR future?</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/why-collaboration-is-essential-for-building-a-successful-xr-future/</guid>
            <description>The era of isolated development and secret-keeping innovation is fading. In the past, companies, individuals could thrive by becoming subject matter experts within their own walls. However, the rise of generative AI, fueled by shared knowledge, has changed the game. AI can now imagine and generate solutions faster than ever. The future belongs to those who embrace openness, collaboration, and shared learning.
 Expertise alone isn’t enough. Today, success hinges on building strong networks, fostering partnerships, and collaborating within communities.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🤝 Making the XR content usable with AI!</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/making-the-xr-content-usable-with-ai/</guid>
            <description>Generative AI is revolutionizing content generation across various mediums, disrupting traditional methods in text, images, art, movies, and music creation. XR (Extended Reality) is also undergoing this transformation. In a previous article, Raju Kandaswamy and I discussed how AI aids in generating content for XR, meeting the dynamic needs of XR and the metaverse.
We highlighted content management as a key challenge in XR and metaverse adoption. While generative AI methods offer some solutions, the significant hurdle of content optimization remains.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>