<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Journey on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/journey/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Journey on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>TW Spotlight: Going with the Flow – My Journey</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/tw-spotlight-2024/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/tw-spotlight-2024/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks has always amazed me—whether it&amp;rsquo;s the pioneering work we do in the industry or the contributions we make to software engineering practices. What truly inspires me is our people-centered approach. Recently, I was honored by our market leadership, who put me in the spotlight to share my journey with fellow Thoughtworkers. While I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a great deal from my colleagues, I took this opportunity to share my own experiences in the hope of inspiring others.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My thoughtworkings from five thoughtful years</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/five-thoughtful-years/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/five-thoughtful-years/</guid>
            <description>Thoughtworks is celebrating its 30th year in industry, and I have completed five years here, and to celebrate this, I have compiled thoughts from thoughtworkers, and published them as an ebook. I am grateful for the wealth of knowledge and experiences shared by my colleagues. These thoughts have resonated with me and shaped my journey within the organization and life.
I am excited to launch the ebook with this post. I believe this compilation of thoughts will not only serve as a personal reflection but also as a valuable resource for others on their own professional journeys.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>