<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>concept on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/concept/</link>
        <description>Recent content in concept on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>IoT based insect monitoring concept</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-insect-monitoring/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/iot-insect-monitoring/</guid>
            <description>Insects are the most diverse species of animals found on earth. While every species is required to maintain the balance of nature, excessive accumulation of any one type can have devastating effects on humans and environment.
Insect management relies on the early detection and accuracy of insect population monitoring techniquessensors-12-15801. Integrated data gathering about insect population together with the ecological factors like temperature, humidity, light etc., makes it possible to execute appropriate pest control at the right time in the right place.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Smart bottle IOT concept</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-bottle-concept/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-bottle-concept/</guid>
            <description>The rapid growth of Internet of Things (IoT) and miniature wearable biosensors have generated new opportunities for personalized eHealth and mHealth services. We present a case study of an intelligent cap that can measure the amount of water in the bottle, monitor activity of opening or closing of bottle cap. This paper presents a Proof of Concept implementation for such a connected smart bottle that sends measurements to the IoT Platform.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Building a smart meeting room concept</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/building-smart-meeting-room-concept/</guid>
            <description>On a usual day at office, if an employee wishes to book a meeting room, he or she first has to open their outlook account, check the calendar for its availability and then send a booking invitation. If they directly go to a meeting room, they have no way of knowing whether it is booked or not without checking the calendar.
Smart Meeting Room is a step forward in automating the availability and booking procedure of a meeting room.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>