<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>meity on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/meity/</link>
        <description>Recent content in meity on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/meity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>XR - the Enabler | XROS Fellowship Report</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/extending-reality-the-enabler-xros/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, a transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtended Reality (XR) at its core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution is the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. My book, Exploring the Metaverse, available globally, outlines this kind of collaboration as a call to action for all of us.
FICCI XROS Fellowship Program Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce &amp;amp; Industry (FICCI), is the voice of india&amp;rsquo;s business and industry for policy change.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>MIPS kick off event, XTIC, IIT Madras</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 23:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/metaverse-india-policy-and-standards/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse India Policy and Standards (MIPS) is a pioneering initiative led by Experiential Technology Innovation Centre (XTIC), serving as India’s premier research and product innovation hub for Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Mixed Reality, and Haptics, hosted at IIT Madras.
It&amp;rsquo;s an honor to be the member of MIPS and showcase my book Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age, which aligns closely with the initiative&amp;rsquo;s objectives.
I extend my gratitude to Thriveni Palanivelu for orchestrating a seamless event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Panelist at FICCI XROS Fellowship Summit</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/ficci-xros-fellowship-summit/</guid>
            <description>Welcome to Internet 3.0, the transformative era where reality takes on new dimensions, driven by eXtending Reality (XR) at it&amp;rsquo;s core, along with AI, Cloud, IoT, and more. This evolution would be the product of collaborative efforts involving academia, government, industry, and individuals. I recently had the privilege of participating as a panelist at an event hosted by the pioneers shaping the future of the internet. In this article, I share my insights and a summary of this remarkable event.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Progress Review - Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/msh-progress-review-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/msh-progress-review-1/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality (XR) is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and user believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited to join the Progress Review Committee as a Judge for Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program. It is great talking to top XR startups of India.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
            <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>