<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>async-first on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/async-first/</link>
        <description>Recent content in async-first on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/async-first/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Books</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/books/</guid>
            <description>📕 Jagjeevan  Living Larger than Life 📕 Jagjeevan: Living Larger Than Life is a heartfelt tribute to the extraordinary life and timeless wisdom of Shri Jagguram—an enlightened soul whose values shaped generations. Blending personal memories with profound life lessons, it captures the essence of a man who lived with humility, discipline, compassion, and unwavering purpose.
 Through ten insightful chapters, the book explores heritage, resilience, responsibility, inner strength, family unity, conflict resolution, gratitude, and the power of one’s actions.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
            <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>