<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>lecture on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/lecture/</link>
        <description>Recent content in lecture on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture: AI and Metaverse reshaping the future</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest-lecture-ai-and-metaverse-reshape-the-future/</guid>
            <description>AI is pervasive, whether we sense it or not. Staying updated has become essential for survival. We are increasingly immersed in artificially generated worlds, with the internet rapidly evolving into what is known as the metaverse. In my book, &amp;ldquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, I delve into its various forms and interpretations, usecases and challenges, and the way forward.
DesignersX, a company specializing in software development, invited me to speak about my book and discuss how AI and the metaverse will shape the future.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An Adventure to Remember: Making it to CareerMaker Meetup</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/careermaker-meetup-azure-developer-community/</guid>
            <description>The CareerMaker meetup, hosted by the Microsoft Azure Developer Community and managed by Reskill, stands as a flagship event in empowering aspiring professionals. Recently, I had the privilege of delivering a special keynote address at Microsoft Gurugram, where I had the opportunity to guide students from various institutes and share insights from my experience in product management.
It was an honor to accept this invitation, as engaging with the young, fresh minds of our nation is not only an opportunity to learn from them but also a responsibility to impart valuable knowledge.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Forward Looking Reflection&#39; at DesignersX</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/forward-looking-reflection/</guid>
            <description>Every end is a beginning, if there is no end, then there is no beginning, just like the year 2023 can only start after the end of year 2022. So this is the right time to reflect and plan for a better beginning. A “Forward Looking Reflection” was my topic of a guest lecture at DesignersX at their year end event. We discussed challenges of software development, and how the industry is trying to solve them.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;SpatialWeb and Web3.0&#39; at NIT Calicut</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest_lecture_nit_calicut/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/guest_lecture_nit_calicut/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Calicut is organizing Tathva, Asia&amp;rsquo;s largest student-run Tech Startup Expo. Tathva is a techno-management fest of NIT Calicut is one of south India&amp;rsquo;s biggest scholastic endeavours. Since its inception in 2000, this annual symposium has known only growth and has flourished into one of the few promising enterprises the nation has witnessed. Pushing the barriers year after year, Tathva aims at providing a plethora of platforms to the intrigued technical heads that arrive at this fiesta with an array of events and workshops, to sharpen their skills and widen their knowledge quotient.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Metaverse Workshop - VIT-AP University</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/metaverse-workshop-vit-ap-university/</guid>
            <description>School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCOPE) of VIT-AP University is organizing a 1-day National Workshop on “Exploring the Blockchain in Metaverse” on June 11, 2022, from 11 am to 5 pm.
 The program is intended for students, faculty of technical institutes, professionals from Industry, R&amp;amp;D organizations, and research scholars.
I will be speaking at the workshop on &amp;ldquo;Gearing up for Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, Will touch upon metaverse step by step.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Indian Achievers&#39; Award 2022</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/indian-achievers-awards-2022/</guid>
            <description>Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Awards is India’s Most Coveted Award For Outstanding Achievements, organized by Indian Achievers&amp;rsquo; Forum. It draws attention on the theme “how the successful Achievers can help the social development in and around the country.” It provides examples of social entrepreneurs, successful models of the society and business community partnership. It promotes achievements that inspire businesses and communities, and recognizes the outstanding professional achievers&amp;rsquo; and their contribution in nation building.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture at VIT Vellore</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/the_parallax_view_1_vit/</guid>
            <description>Metaverse has become the newest macro-goal for tech industries to invest in and to see the world in a new perspective with the help of AR and VR technologies.🌟
A student club at VIT Vellore named Mozilla Firefox Club invited me for a guest lecture in The Parallax View Episode 1 :Bring the world to wherever you are
 🔮✨Join us on 22nd April, 6PM to clarify all your doubts regarding AR and VR and opportunities it offers you !</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Recognitions</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/recognitions/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//about/recognitions/</guid>
            <description>Awards Indian Achiever&amp;rsquo;s Awards 2022 ☞ More Details
Recognitions Judge at Smart India Hackathon ☞ More Details ☞ More events like this
Guest Lecture at NIT Calicut ☞ More Details ☞ More events like this
Guest Lecture at DesignersX ☞ More Details ☞ More events like this
Coverage  </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Guest Lecture on &#39;Metaverse&#39; at NIT Hamirpur</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//event/getting_into_metaverse_guest_lecture_nit_hamirpur/</guid>
            <description>National Institute of Technology Hamirpur is organizing Tech-Nexus, an online technical carnival, as an initiative of the Institute Innovation Council, MHRD. The essence of Tech-Nexus is to unite all the technological talents across the nation and give them a platform to express their skills and ideas. This flagship event will help people to showcase their unique projects and trends in the technological field as well as the challenges encountered, and solutions adopted while developing the projects.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>