<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>launch on Kuldeep Singh</title>
        <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//tags/launch/</link>
        <description>Recent content in launch on Kuldeep Singh</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/launch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>🙏 Exploring the Metaverse | Testimonial 1</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-testimonial-1/</guid>
            <description>My book &amp;lsquo;Exploring the Metaverse&amp;rsquo;, is now available in stores, including Amazon and BPB Online. It features forewords and testimonials from a diverse group of industry leaders.
One such testimonial comes from Vishal Shah, General Manager of XR and Metaverse at Lenovo. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of hearing Vishal speak at events like CES and AWE, where he shared invaluable insights on the metaverse and XR technology. Meeting him in person at Lenovo Tech World 2023 was a highlight, where we discussed this book, and he graciously agreed to contribute to its exploration of the metaverse.</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>📕 Exploring the Metaverse | Available Now</title>
            <link>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
            <author>thinkuldeep@gmail.com (Kuldeep Singh)</author>
            <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com//post/exploring-the-metaverse-available-now/</guid>
            <description>Is the metaverse hype or reality? My new book explores what lies ahead The concept of the Metaverse keeps evolving, leaving many confused. 📖 In my book, Exploring the Metaverse: Redefining Reality in the Digital Age I leverage my years of experience to:
 Unravel the Metaverse: Demystify the term and explore its true potential. Separate Myth from Reality: Address misconceptions surrounding the metaverse. Prepare for the Future: Equip you with insights to navigate the evolving digital landscape.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>