<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sustainability on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sustainability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sustainability on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sustainability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Takeaways from Lenovo Techworld India Edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/lenovo-techworld-india-2023/</guid>
      <description>Lenovo, the global technology leader, hosted the India edition of its flagship event, Tech World , on March 16th, 2023. Industry leaders come together and peep into the future of smarter technology, that is empowering a changing world through innovative products, solutions, and witness technological solutions.
I get a chance to join the event, and meet and listen to the industry leaders, experience lenovo’s innovative product line, and see breakthroughs in india shaping up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge at MOZOHACK 4.0 by the Mozilla Students Club</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/judge-mozohack4-srmkzilla-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/judge-mozohack4-srmkzilla-2023/</guid>
      <description>MOZOHACK is a 24-hour hackathon organized by SRMKZILLA. SRMKZILLA is a Mozilla campus club of SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai(India). It is inspired by the Mozilla Learning Network, provides students an open platform to analyze and enhance their technical and non-technical skills, such as working on open-source projects, developing websites, technical fests, and workshops. The club is conducting the seventh edition of its annual flagship event – MOZOFEST&#39;23 – where they celebrate student community through technical and non-technical events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker at Meta-MeitY XR Startup Hub, IIT Delhi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/meta-meity-xr-startsup-hub-2022/</guid>
      <description>Extending Reality is providing experience to user where the boundaries of real and fake blur, and use believe in the new reality presented to them. In the recent years, the tech has evolved to enable extending the reality by XR (AR/VR) faster, and much more evolution still to happen. I was invited at Meta and Meity&amp;rsquo;s Startup Hub program as an industry expert. Here I reflect on the day I spend with the few of the top startup of india, who want to solve some of the key challenges using XR and related technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge - Ashoka University Hackathon 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/ashoka-university-hackathon-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/ashoka-university-hackathon-2022/</guid>
      <description>RedBrick Hacks is flagship summer hackathon of Ashoka University, open to students from Delhi NCR. You will have the opportunity to learn, collaborate, and build meaningful projects alongside mentors from various disciplines. For 24 hours on the weekend of June 18, you will have access to free workshops, plenary lectures, prizes worth over ₹8L, games, and more!
The theme of the event was &amp;ldquo;Tech for Social Good&amp;rdquo; with three main tracks: Health &amp;amp; Wellness, Sustainable Growth, and Security &amp;amp; Privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker - XR and Sustainability - GSF Global Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/green-software-foundation-global-summit-2022/</guid>
      <description>Green Software Foundation Green Software Foundation (GSF) is building a trusted ecosystem of people, standards, tooling and best practices for Green Software. GSF works with vision to change the culture of building software across the tech industry, so sustainability becomes a core priority to software teams, just as important as performance, security, cost and accessibility. Read more here.
GSF Global Summit 2022 The Green Software Foundation Global Summit 2022 is a series of free events organized by Green Software Foundation members all around the globe that are passionate about sustainable software development, maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
