<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learnings on Kuldeep Singh</title>
    <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/learnings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learnings on Kuldeep Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thinkuldeep.com/tags/learnings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Building Spatial Solutions</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/xr-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 is forcing us into a ‘new normal’, A new normal that makes most of us work from home, and that leads to spending long hours on Zoom, or other video conferencing platforms. Meetings, inceptions, discovery workshops, conferences, and webinars are happening in the same monotonous ways. We are stuck with a screen in almost the same pose and posture. Some might use their mobile phone or tablet but that limits us to a small screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Learning Equation</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/the-learning-equation/</guid>
      <description>Today, The world is celebrating teacher’s day. I wish Happy Teacher&amp;rsquo;s day to all of us! We all are teachers and learners as every one of us has something to learn from others and something to teach others. I am thinking of an equation of learning that defines my way of learning and hope it would be helpful for you too.  The learning equation — Learning is proportional to Sharing; Learning ∝ Sharing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned From Blockchain-Based Development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/learnings-from-blockchain-based-development/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain or DLT (Distributed Ledger Technology) is getting good traction in the IT world these days. Earlier, this technology was being mostly explored by banks and other finance-related institutions, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum. Now, it is getting explored for other use cases for building distributed applications. Blockchain technology comes with a decentralized and immutable data structure that maintains a connected block of information. Each block is connected using a hash of the previous block, and every new block on the chain is validated (mined) before adding and replicating it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Hard Lessons From Microservices Development</title>
      <link>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thinkuldeep.com/post/lessons_from_microservices_development/</guid>
      <description>Microservices-based development is happening all around the industry; more than 70% are trying development of microservice-based software. Microservices simplify integration of the businesses, processes, technology, and people by breaking down the big-bang monolith problem to a smaller set that can be handled independently. However, it also comes with the problem of managing relations between these smaller sets. We used to manage fewer independent units, so there was less operation and planning effort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>